<topics>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-hypnotism</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064205/1887-06-29/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=hypnosis+HYPNOTIC+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>One of the most notable features of the
scientific tendencies of the present day is
the extraordinary interest taken in the in
vestigation ofthosejeculiar physical and
psychical conditions now known collec
tively under the name of hypnotism
varying from lethargy catalepsy etc to
somnambulism Until quite recently
these investigations have been frowned
upon and taboed in scientific circles and
the fact that any man of scientific inclina
tions was known to feel an interest in
matters associated with mesmerism or
animal magnetism was sullicient to
make him an object of suspicion and in
jure his good standing among his fellow
scientists The result of these socalled
investigations instituted by the French
academy pronouncing in effect the whole
subject a humbug and delusion has lain
like an interdict upon further re
searches and the whole matter was left
over for the most parr to charlatans or
to persons hardly capable of forming
sound judgment or proceeding according
to the accurate methods demanded by
modern science Science however in
the remarkable progress made of late
23 advanced so far upon certain lines
vt It has been hardly possible to pro
od further in those directions without
leering upon the forbidden fied There
re the old signboards against trespass
is have bten taken down For
mesmerism that verbal scarecrow has
been substituted hypnotism which
word has had a wonderfully legitimizing
effect while animal magnetism that
once llouted idea has been proven to be
sn existing fact by methods as accurate
as those adopted by Faraday or
Edison to verily their observations
EFFORTS OK SCIENTISTS
Many of the most eminent scientists of
Europe are now devoting themselves
assiduously to these researches Periodi
cals making a specialty of the subject are
now published in France Germany and
England A catalogue of the recent
literature of hypnotism and related phe
nomena compiled by Max Dessoir was
printed in the number of the German
magazine called the Sphinx for February
of this year and this catalogue occupied
nine pages The list is limited to those
words written on the lines laid under the
methods of the modern school all books
being excluded whose authors hold to
mesmeric theories or who are even
professional magnetizers The catalogue
is therefore as strictly scientific as pos
sible and being classified with German
thoroughness under the different branches
of the subject such as hysterohypnot
ism suggestion fascination etc
it will prove a valuable assistance to the
udent
In this country the interest of scient
1s has not yet been aroused to an ex
mt comparable to that of European in
jstigators Old prejudices have not
5tirely lost their potency One of the
most eminent professors of s leading
university is said to have been subjected
to ridicule from his colleagues because of
a marked interest shown in the subject
and a Boston physician of high standing
within a few months confided to the
writer that he had made use of hypnotic
methods with gratifying success in the
case of a patient where ordinary reme
dies hd proved unavailing but he did
not venture to make the result public
since his fellowdoctors might be inclined
to condemn his action as irregular
A work embracing the whole subject
has lately appeared in Paris and as it is
to form a volume of the valuable Inter
national Scientific series published in
English French German and Italian it
can hardly fail to diffuse a correct popu
lar understanding of the results thus far
attained The book is called Le Mag
netism Animal Animal Magnetism
and its authors are Messrs Alfred Binet
and Charles Fere of the medical staff of
the Saltpetrier Hospital for Nervous Dis
orders in Paris It gives a history of the
patient researches conducted at that in
stitution by the medical staff under the
celebrated Professor Charcote during the
past nine years These experiments have
been prosecuted according to the most
exact scientific methods and with the
most extreme caution The endeavor
has been to obtain first of all the
most elementary psychic phenomenon
and to test every step in the
investigations by separate experiments
specially devised to prove the good faith
of the subject and the reality of his hal
lucination to eliminate the possibility of
unconscious suggestion to establish re
lations with similar phenomena of disease
or health in tne domain of physiology
and to note the modifications which can
be brought about by altering the condi
tions of the experiments The authors
possess the great scientific virtue of
never dogmatizing In the entire book
not a single law is laid down not a
single hypothesis is advanced which is
not reached by the most improved in
ductive processes A great service of
the book lies in its enunciation of new
and trustworthy methods for studying
the physiology of the brain in health and
disease while It brings into the realm of
physical experiment vexed questions ot
psychology heretofore given over to met
aphysical methods exclusively
THE HYPNOTIC SLEEP
is described as a different form of natu
ral sleep and all the causes which bring
on fatigue are capable of bringing on
hypnotism on suitable subjects Two
of the leading hypnotic states are lethar
gy and catalepsy the former being anala
gous to deep sleep and the latter to a
light slumber In lethargy the respirato
ry movements are slow and deep cat
alepsy slight shallow very slow and
separated by a long interval In lethargy
the application of a magnet over the re
gion of the stomach causes profound mod
ifications in the breathing and circulation
while there is eo such effect in catalepsy
This shows the connection of hypnotism
with magnetism and various other ex
periments with magnets have produced
some wonderful results Here it may be
added that Dr Geesmam a Vienna
scientist who has made a specialty of
hypnotic 8titdies has Invented and suc
cessfully applied an Instrument called a
hypnoscope consisting of an arrangement
of magnets for the purpose of ascertain
ing whether any persons is a good hyp
notic subject
The experiments demonstrate that
sensation In the hypnotic states varies
Detween the two opposite poles of
hypetcc3thesia and antesthesia in other
words the senses may be extraordinarily
excited as in somnambulism or as in
lethargy they may be extinct except
sometimes hearing In somnambulism
the field of vision and acutebess of sight
are about double hearing is made very
acute and smell is so intensely develop
ed that a subject can find by scent the
fragments of a card previously given to
him to feeJ and torn up and hidden The
memory of somnambulism is similarly
exalted When awakened the subject
does not as a rule remember anything
that occurred when he was entranced
but when again hypnotized his memory
includes all the facts of his sleep his life
when awake and his former sleeps
ltichet attests how somnambules recall
with a luxury of detail scenes in which
they have taken part and places they
have visited long ago M one of
his somiambules sings the air of the
second act of the opera LAfricaine when
she is asleep but cnnot remember a
note of it when awake
There is a theory that no experience
wlmtever of a person is lost to the mem
ory it is only the power to recall it that
is defective The authors of this work say
that while the exaltation of the memory
during somnambulism does not give ab
solute proof to the theory that nothing is
lost it proves at any rate that the mem
ory of preservation is much greater than
is generally imagined in comparison with I tauce of
ing recollection more
or less vivid per
sists for a lew seconds then becomes ef
faced This forgetfulness is even more
marked in the case of hypnosis On re
turning to natural consciousness the sub
ject cannot recompose o single one of the
scenes in which he has played his part as
a witness or actor The loss howeveri3
not complete for often a word or two is
sufficient to bring back a whole scene
though this word or two coming from
operator to subject partakes more or less
of the nature ot a suzgestion
SUGGESTION
Suggestion by which is meant the
production of thoughts and actions on the
part of the subject through some indica
tion or bint given by the operator is
found to be analagous to dreaming Say
the authors All suggestion consists
essentially in acting on a person by an
idea every effect suggested is the re
sultant of a phenomenon of ideation but
we must add that the idea is but an
outward sign taken alone it is only in
dicative of some physiological process
which Is alone capable of producing a
material effect Persons vary in their
susceptibility to suggestion For sug
gesiion to succeed the subject must have
naturally fallen or been artifically
thrown into the state of morbid re
ceptivity but it is difficult to deter
mine accurately the conditions of susges
tionability However we may mention
two The first is the mental inertia or
the subject the consciousness
is completely empty an idea is suggest
ed and reigns supreme over the slumber
ing consciousness The second
is psychic hyperexcitability the cause of
the aptitude for suggestion From the
standpoint of psychology the explanation
of the effects of suggestion is to be found
in the association of ideas Suggestion
in its positive aspect is nothing eise than
the throwing Into action of a mental as
sociation preexisting in the spirit
of the hypnotic For example we
say to a patient Look you have a
bird in your apron and no sooner arc
these simple words pronounced than she
sees the bird feels it with herfingersand
sometimes even hears it sing All these
ideas are associated in the mind by habit
and consequently they are called into
action Again in place of speech we
engage the attention of the patient and
when her gaze has become settled and
obediently follows all our movements we
imitate with the hand the motion of an
object which dies Soon the patient
cries Oh what a pretty bird How
has a simple gesture produced so singu
lar an effect Again by the association
of ideas But this case differs from the
preceding in being only an association of
resemblance
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1921-01-11/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnot+HYPNOTIZED&amp;r=0.045,0.251,0.834,0.468,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1919-02-23/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotist&amp;r=-0.154,0.282,1.03,0.579,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1894-12-16/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Hypnosis+hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotically+Hypnotism+hypnotism+hypnotize+Hypnotized+hypnotized+hypnotizing&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.218,-0.032,1.436,1.436,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>But the greatest of these new beliefs
      is hypnotism. Its growth bids tair to
      divide the nation. From recent events
      it would seem that some Democrats
      have already disappeared, and soon
      there will be no Republicans. The
      "iniquitous doctrines" of the Hypnotiz
      ers will be assailed ore long la the na
      tioual platform of the Hypnotized.
      Everywhere intrudes the hypnotic
      "suggestion." We may think we paid
      a delicate compliment to the rector, but
      tii c wife of our bosom put it into our
      head. Little Reginald was "thinkin' of
      them Christmas presents rigbtalong."
      But to th« criminal, the condemned of
      man, comes the new doctrine as a
      heavenly aid. The glories of iisanity
      are past. It is not now conceded that
      Mr. Brown, of i'psilanti, who killed his
      neighbor Rogers, should be at once dis
      charged because th« town records of
      Boston recall the incarceration of an
      ancestral Brown "forasmuch as lie was
      distraught of his intellects."
      The new method is much simpler,
      much easier. The cashier robs a great
      bank systematically for years. He was
      perfectly honest himself, but was under
      the control of another man, who got
      most of the money. A scoundrel slays
      an innocent woman through a hired as
      sassin. The actual murderer had the
      best intentions, but he cou'd not help
      adopting the elaborate plan proposed by
      the hypnotizing villain. The plan was
      known to intelligent men, but they were
      "hypnotized," and could no.t warn the
      victim. Various girls elope with mar
      ried men, but they are "model young
      ladies" under hypnotic influence.
      If all these things are true, anarchy is
      already upon us. bins Sins and J oliet
      are our proper universities. Matters,
      however, might be exaggerated—by the
      other newspapers. A late inquiry among
      prominent local representatives of tho
      medical and legal professions has been
      most reassuring. The following com
      munications exhibit the true nature of
      hypnotism and its possible relations to
      crime. The articles set forth the most
      recent and approved views upon a dif
      ficult and complicated subject, and ex
      emplify the heights to which have risen
      the sciences of Galen and Triboniau,
      PROF. W. XAVIER SUDDUTH.
      University of Minnesota.
      In answer to your letter of inquiry re
      garding the relation of hypnosis to
      crime, would say that 1 no not consider
      that there is any relation, and in proof
      i&gt;t my position cite the fact that hypno
      tism is as old as man and has been
      known as far back as Biblical record
      goes- The Egyptians also were familiar
      with it, and so have been all modern
      nations; but in all this time, so far a3
      my knowledge extends, there has not
      been a single well-authenticated case
      on the criminal records of any country
      where hypnosis has been used to coiu
      del any one to commit any crime, not a
      single case where a pre viously virtuous
      woman hns been led from the path of
      virtue, nor any individual swindled out
      of money by means of hypnotic sugges
      tion, nor do I believe there ever will be.
      Hypnosis is not a condition like ether
      or chloroform narcosis, but a mental
      state into which the individual volun
      tarily enters. No one can be hypno
      tised against his will, nor be kept in the
      hypnotic state any longer than he is
      willing to be. The Idea that many per
      sons have that only weak-minded people
      can be hypnotized is entirely false. The
      best subjects I have ever had have been
      this best educated and possessed of the
      strongest wills. All that is necessary
      for such people to do In order to become
      subjects is to desire to &lt;\\i&gt;erience the
      sensation and put themselves in a stale
      of absolute passivity.
      Idiots, insane people and skeptics can
      not be hypnotized. In order to be a
      good subject a person must first be will
      ing—he must have will power sufficient
      to will to do as he is told, and last, but
      not least, be must possess faith in the
      operator.
      Mo one can bo hypnotized who do.-s
      not know that he is going to be.
      The process is purely one of suggestion.
      There is no mysterious fluid that passes
      from one individual to the other.
      Neither is it a condition of paralysis,
      in which the individual is unable
      to resist the will of the operator.
      The suggestion of acts to a person in the
      hypnotic state that are contrary to his
      ideas of right and wrong will always
      meet with failure, and if the sugges
      tion is persisted in will cause the indi
      vidual to awaken. Constant repetition
      may, as iv the waking state, educate
      him iv the premises, but a person iv
      the hypnotic state is less susceptible to
      criminal suggestion than ho wuuhl be
      in the waking condition, for th» reason
      that in the hypnotic state nil sense of
      material relations is set aside for tho'
      time being. The personality of the in
      dividual la not, however, materially al
      tered, only Modified, partially domi
      nated hy the will ol another for the time
      being, but only in so far as his own
      ideas of rieht and wrong are not seri
      ously crossed. Any strong countor
      cturent of ideas will break the relation
      ship nnd arouse him from the. hypnotic
      state.
      Furthermore, there must be a condi
      tion of absolute sympathy and confi
      dence presented in order to secure' the
      best results. Faith in the ability and'
      good intentions of the operator is an 'es- 1
      Mattel element in hypnotism. No sane
      person would go to sleep with a burglar
      under his bed if he knew it, neither
      would he permit a rascal to hypnotize
      him. The sensational stories that go the
      rounds of cheap literature regarding
      theft, arson and murder committed in
      the hypnotic state, by reason of that
      state, are the creations of diseased
      minds. Unless a person is a thief or
      murderer at heart, he can no more be
      made one in the hypnotic than he can in
      the waking state, in considering this
      subject, however, it must b» remem
      bered that there are people in the world
      who are negatively virtuous and gener
      ally well behaved—people who are good
      simply because they have never been
      tempted to be bad. Such persons,
      tempted either in the waking or hyp
      notic state, might or would fall
      simply because they have no In
      dwelling force of character. Such
      people are only safe in a cloister or be
      liir.a prison bars, and there, in my esti
      mation, is where a considerable portion
      of the inhabitants of a village in a
      neighboring state should be placed. If
      wo can believe the accounts in the
      papers, an innocent man is being perse
      cuted at the Instigation of two hysterical
      girls who have the power of throwing
      themselves into the trance state. The
      days of Salem witchcraft are being en
      acted over again. 1 have never seen
      anything yet in my fifteen years' study
      of the subject that has led me to believe
      in telepathy, and I fully concur in the
      opinion of Judge Bailey as to the ad
      mission of •'hypnotically" secured testi
      mony in court.
      The basis of hypnotism is suggestion,
      and this may be given in the waking as
      well as the hypnotic state, and need not
      be by word alone. Anything that stands
      for an idea to the mind of the indi
      vidual is sufficient to produce the
      effect. Suggestions in the waking
      state sometimes produce epidem
      ics, as in the middle ages, when
      men, women and children were carried
      away by the miliion with the idea of
      of rescuing the Holy city. Epidemics
      of crime seem to spring up as the result
      of some dastardly deed as the incentive.
      "Lynching bees" follow each other in
      rapid succession. Train robberies go
      in groups, although widely separated
      geographically. To sucii an extent do
      these things occur that sometimes .it
      seems as if people were ere atures «f im
      pulse and suggestion rather than rea
      soning beings.
      The danger in hypnosis lies in its
      abuse, and not in its use. Every power
      has its good and its bad aspect, and so
      has this one; but hypnosis offers its own
      remedy. If, when abused,* hypnosis
      may weaken the will,even as morphine,
      ether, chloral and all other narcotics, rt
      may also be used to strengthen the will
      again, whereas'the other analgesics can
      not. No one has ever diod from hyp
      nosis used as an aosesthetic, while
      hundreds have died under chloroform.
      My prediction is that, when the atmos
      phere has been cleared of supersti
      tion, bigotry and professional jealousy,
      hypnosis will come into general use as
      an analgesic and anaesthetic To inhibit
      or even limit the use of this potent
      remedy for the relief of pain would be
      an outrage upon the community. Far
      better educate the people up to its right
      use and point out the danger of its
      abuse.
      If it is to be controlled by legislation,
      where will the line be drawn? Let me
      cite a few places where it is now used.
      A little child is playing with Its blocks
      or dollies, aud the nurse enters to put
      the little one into its crib for its regular
      afternoon nap. The child does not feel
      sleepy, but insists on being allowed to
      finish the house he is building, but the
      nurse persists, and by blandishment*
      and promises ot sugar plums finally
      succeeds in tretting the child into its
      crib or into her lap, and then begins the
      monotonous motion of rocking it to
      sleep, meanwhile emphasizing the
      suggestion by the low droning of the
      lullaby song accompanied by the com
      maud: "Go to sleep, darling—go to
      sieep sleep sleep"—and the child
      "iocs" to sleep—hypnotized.
      Again, a child at its play In
      some way hurts its finger, and
      runs to mamma, crying: the moth
      er soothes away the pain by ca
      resses and diversion of the attention,
      and in all probability, if injury is con
      siderable, ending by rocking and sing
      intr it to sleep while the tears yet glis
      ten between its closed lids.
      In yonder darkened chamber lies a
      person suffering from that terribly
      painful affliction —"a sick head
      ache"—the slightest jar giving ex
      cruciating agony, such as is to be
      appreciated only by one who has
      had it. A friend, hearing of the case,
      comes in, and by gently stroking the
      fevered brow soon quiets the throbbing
      pulse and puts the sufferer to aleep, to
      awake entirely free from pain.
      A person suffuringifrom an acute neu
      ralgia, caused an by exposed pulp in a de
      cayed tooth, calls upon me at my house in
      the evening. I apply some simple house
      hold remedy, and, by a tew gentle but
      firm passes over the face in the painful
      region, suggest freedom from pain, and
      send the sufferer home to pass a com
      fortable night in sleep, instead of walk
      ing the floor, as many a person has done.
      A prominent man, whose voice, no
      doubt, will be heard in the halls ot our
      legislature the coming winter on this
      subject, if it comes up, recently went
      to a "painless joint" and had twoachiiur
      teeth removed with odontuader, or
      something of a like nature, and after
      wards suffered intense neuralgia. He
      Bought me at my home just at dinner
      time. 1 applied topical remedies, but
      failed to relieve him. I finally suggested
      hypnosis, and, placing him upon a
      lounge in my study, soon had him
      asleep, and left him to rest until 1 could
      tret my dinner. On returning I found
      him awake, the pain having oeen
      stronger than my au^estiou to sleep
      I again hypnotized him, and remained
      with him, finally securing immunity
      from the neuralgia, and sent him home
      to a quiet night's rest, a firm believer
      hi the efficacy of hypnosis as an anal*
      gesic.
      A lady came to the late clinic at
      the university with a tumor of long
      standing, the removal of which had
      been a constant dread, undermining
      her health and inducing morbid nerv
      ous symptom*. The tumor was
      successfully removed under hyp
      nosis, and the patient subsequently
      treated for her nervousness.with marked
      improvement and promise of final cure
      A woman stiffenmk from a known
      heart lesion, who had permitted her
      teeth to decay to the jjum line tHjcauso
      an anesthetic had been inteudicted by
      hei family physician, presented for
      treatment. She proved a Kd subject,
      and had a lance number of badly dis~
      eased teeth and roots removed under
      hypnosis, waking up vvitli a smile on
      her face, having been perfectly obliv
      ious to auy paiu, and remained free
      from any subsequent bad effects of neu
      ralgia or shock.
      A man suffering from hysterio-er&gt;i
      lepsy of several years' standing
      presented for treatment. {Suppur
      ation of the antrum and frontal
      sinuses was diagnosed, and, as these
      cases coutraindicate the ordinary an
      aesthetics, hypnosis wan used in the
      presence of several physicians with
      absolute success and tubes placed in the
      several sinuses. The operation was
      followed np by the use of suggestion in
      the treatment of the epileptic attacks,
      and, although the case is still under
      treatment, every indication points to a
      cuie. The epileptic seizures are
      under full control, and all internal
      Medication has been dropped these
      many days.
      A woman in the fifth month of a
      "vomiting pregnancy," with other
      serious complications, wasted to a
      shadow, and only existing on three
      quarters ot a grain of morphine
      daily, administered hypodermatically,
      was put under hypnotic control, and
      the morphine stopped at the second
      sitting. At the third site was taught to
      hypnotize herself. The vomiting was
      treated L*y suggestion, as well as some
      other annoying complications, and the
      patient remains to this day, nearly one
      month since the first treatment, free
      from the use of morphine, a"iid doing as
      well as .could be expected of one iv her
      condition.
      A large number of stammerers have
      also come under my treatment, with
      varying decrees of success; none,
      however, witnout improvement, and
      several have been dismissed as
      cured. In the licht ot tlie above expe
      rience, of which the cases cited are only
      examples, is it strange that I should be
      a firm believer in hypnosis as an anal
      tesie and an aim-schetic in the treat
      ment of neuralgia? The following
      clippiug from the New York Evening
      Post very clearly sets forth the present
      status of hypnosis in its relation to med
      icine:
      The extent to which therapeutic experi
      ments in hypnotic suggestion are exciting
      the attention of physicians and awakening
      the interest of the general public may be in
      ferred from the fact that during: the past
      year more than 100 books and brochures,
      especially devoted to the discussion of this
      subject, have been published. One of the
      most valuable of these is the small volume
      just issued by Bong, in Berlin, entitled "Die
      Bedeutuug der Uynotischen Suggestion als
      Ileilmittel." The author. Dr. J. Grossman,
      editor of the Zeitschrift fur Hypotismus,
      prints communications from thirty of the
      most eminent professors and physicians ot
      Europe, firing the results of their experi
      ence in the application of hypnotic sugges
      tions to the healing of disease. Thus Van
      .'edeu and Van Reuterghem. of Amsterdam,
      report that from May 5,1557, to June 30, 1893,
      in the institution under their charge, 1.098
      patients were subjected to the treatment;
      of those £8.28 percent were entirely cured.
      2&amp;6!) per cent permanently improved, 21.02
      per cent slightly bettered, 17.81 per cent
      unaffected, and in U.lB per cent of the
      cases the results were unknown. Dr.
      Wetterstrand, of Stockholm, has used this
      method of medical treatment in 7,000, and
      Dr. Bornneim, of Nancy, in 12,000 cases, and
      both express themselves strongly in favor of
      it. Indeed, Dr. Bernheim does not hesitate
      to declare that the study of Hypnotic sugges
      tion should be made obligatory in all medical
      school?, and that nowadays a physician who
      ignores the psychical element in disease, and
      has no knowledge of the part it plays in
      palhogeny and therapeutics, is no better
      than a horse doctor, and should confine him
      self to veterinary practice. Another impor
      tant point brought out by Dr. Kraltt-Ebing,
      of Vienna, is the influence of "a utosugges
      tion" in the production of disease. The
      number of ailments and morbid conditions
      of this) kind, that have their origin in the
      nervous system, and are indicated by pains,
      paralysis and other symptoms of hysterical,
      hypochondriac and neurasthenic affections,
      is astonishing. Although not merely i mag
      inary complaints, they cease with the re
      moval of the "autosuargestive cause," which
      may be effected by any change of scene ban
      ishing it from the thoughts, or by heterosug
      gestion (fremd-suggestlon) on the part of a
      physician, who may impart it verbally or in
      the disguise of a dose of medicine. In obsti
      nate cases, in which the autosuggestion is
      firmly entrenched in mental imbecility, su
      perstituiion, morbid appetites and passions,
      inveterate habits, or abnormities of charac
      ter, recourse must be had to hypnotism. That
      the great majority of mankind are capable of
      being hypnotized is shown by the experi
      ments of Dr. Freihorr yon Schrank Noizing,
      of Munich, on 5.705 persons of different na
      tionalities, of whom only per cent proved
      to be entirely unsusceptible."
      The following paragraph is taken
      from a letter of mine published in the
      Minneapolis Journal:
      "I have observed from a perusal of the
      literature on the- sub ject that nearly al! the
      work done so far has been in the direction
      of investigating its value as a therapeutic
      agent, rather than as au an a-sthetie. Tiie
      special line of work that I have been and am
      still engaged upon is its application to sur
      gery, upon which little or nothing has been
      written. The value of hypnosis as an anal
      gesic in neuralgia has long been known.
      That I entered uuon the work with consid
      erable trepidation is shown by the fact that,
      although I have been a close student of the
      subject formauy years past, aud have uieJ it
      in my private practice, yet I bad never given
      a public demonstration until last year. I
      cannot do belter in closing this letter than to
      quote the opening paragraph of the first
      paper I ever wrote upon the subject: "The
      liae of detnarkaiiou between the sublime aud
      the ridiculous, between the mysterious ana
      the miraculous, Between belief and iucredu
      l.ty, between respect and diversion in this life,
      is so narrow that to espouse auy causa that
      is not woll understood, or in at verges on tne
      occult, is really dangerous to oue's reputa
      tion; and la treating of hypnosis I should be
      vain Indeed did did I expect to escape the
      lot of others who have iv the past essayed
      the role of interpreters of ibis ruueh-abused,
      but Httle understood, science.' 1 The clinic
      at the -U." while ruuulng. daily demon
      strated its value as au amesthetic. It was
      fitting that a dental clinic stiould bo the first
      10 take the lead in the maUor, us dentistry
      has always b'en in the front rank iv ex peri
      meiu with aiuesthetics, and with excellent
      results.' 1
      I As to who can use hypnosis there is
      no limit. All are more or less suscepti
      ble to its influence. All that the hyp
      notizer can do is to direct the course to
      be pursued,and the result depends upon
      the Individual. I have taught a great
      many persons to hypnotize themselves,
      to their great benefit. When it is fully
      understood that it is a mental state and
      not a physical condition, ana that no
      one can bo hypnotized against his will,
      then tho dread that some good pcoDle
      have of it will cease, and hypnotic sug
      gestion will come to occupy th place it
      deservedly should among household
      remedies.
      _
      Call and see what George Refer, Ml
      Wubasha street, has to offer in Pure
      Wines for the holidays.
      HON. C. D. O'BRIEN.
      As to whether the law recognizes an
      alleged hypnotic influence, under which
      a crime was committed, as being a de
      fense fur the party charged with the
      commission of such crime, 1 will say
      that, so far as the existence of the con
      dition called hypnotism is concerned, or
      whether it exists as a condition or as a
      fact. lam unable to state. From what
      is said about it ami written about it, it
      aDpears that some people have the fac
      ulty of producing on others an influ
      ence called hysterical or hypnotic, un
      der which the subject apparently ap
      pears to have abandoned all self-power
      and self-consciousness, and to be en
      tirely under the domination of the op
      erator.
      But so far the law has nol, recognized
      the existence of any such condition;
      that is, it has not been satisfactorily
      proven ift any court of justice, to my
      knowledge, that either tbe operator
      possesses the alleged power, or that the
      subject can be entirely subordinated to
      the will of the operator to the extent
      that it is claimed that he can—that is, so
      as to produce an abnormal condition in
      which the individuality of the subject is
      completely wiped out, and he or she be
      comes the more instrument of the de
      sires or wishes of the operator.
      Now, I say the law does not recognize
      the existence of that condition; there
      fore, up to this time, there is, so far as 1
      know, no adjudicated case which holds
      that a defense based upon a theory that
      a criminal act was committed by one
      because of and while under the power
      of hypnotic influence can be sustained.
      I very much doubt whether such a de
      fense ever will b« sustained, because I
      do not tluiik the law will ever recogniz
      a hypnotic condition as a defense to a
      criminal act committed by one who
      claims to be in that state when so
      committing the crime. Neither would
      the law recognize, without a direct
      statutory enactment in that behalf, a
      criminal act committed by the operator
      in the hypnotic suggestion. In other
      words, to make it plain, if it should be
      claimed that the operator hypnotized
      the subject, and then, while the subject
      was under the influence, suggested to
      the subject the commission of a crime,
      which such person so under the influence
      should then proceed to commit, the legal
      consequences would be, very likely, that
      both of them would be indicted for the
      crime and both Dunislied as principal
      and accessory both before and after the
      fact.
      You now ask me whether the hypno
      tizing of a person against his will,
      winch results in the mental or physical
      injury of the person so hypnotized,
      would be considered in law a crime.
      Under the penal code of this state there
      is no provision that will reach such a
      e.ise that lam aware of. As this state
      has abolished common law jurisdiction
      for crimes, and nothing is a crime unless
      so specifically designated iv the statutes
      (and we have no statute upon the sub
      ject of hypnotism or occult Influence),
      there could be no charge predicated upon
      the hypnotizing of an individual, pro
      vided the subject consented to the ex
      periment; but if it should be proved iv
      court that such a thing as hypnotic in
      fluence existed, and that a person was
      hypnotized against his will, thereby
      producing a physical injury to him, 1
      should think that certainly, under the
      common law jurisdiction, and, perhaps,
      under our penal code, a prosecution for
      assault might be maintained, for it has
      been held that the administration of
      anesthetics to a patient against his will
      do's constitute an assault.
      Speaking generally of the subject, the
      most remarkable thing connected with
      the so-called hypnotic manifestations is
      the resemblance which they bear to the
      old theories of witchcraft, both in Eu
      rope and iv this country.
      The alleged case of hypnotism re
      cently occurring in Eau Claire, and the
      manifestations of the hypnotic subjects,
      as reported in the Globs on last Sun
      day, are remarkably similar to the man
      ifestations of witchcraft delusion as we
      read them, both in the histories of Eu
      rope and of New England. The state
      ments of the two girls in Eau Claire
      concerning the Influence of J)r. Pickin,
      and the hysterical or cataleptic con
      dition which they ascribe to his in
      fluence, are almost precisely the same
      as the manifestations of witchcraft aud
      the charges made against those unfor
      tunate people that are alleged to have
      practiced the art In New England dur
      ii.sr the early history of the country.
      When you add to this the sympathetic
      symptoms between the two s-irls, you
      have, if you choose to call it so, a case of
      witchcraft or possession produced by
      witchcraft, or absolutely similar symp
      toms; and it is a very remarkable thing
      that in tiie year 18U4, at what we consider
      the acme of our development in civili
      zation, progress and culture, we should
      find ourselves confronted with a condi
      tion, or popular delusion, which has
      heretofore been entirely ascribed to the
      ignorance and superstition of former
      ages.
      You ask me if a confession or testi
      mony obtained under hypnotic Influence
      could be used in a court of law, or would
      the procuring of a confession under surh
      circumstances be a violation of personal
      right. The entire value of a confession
      rests upon the eireumstamces under
      which it is obtained. It must be volun
      tary, and not induced by undue influence
      of any kind. The mind of the party
      confessing must not be overcome Liy any
      influence such as threats, or hope of re
      ward or of escaping punishment. It
      therefore follows that a confession
      obtained from a person who, it
      is conceded, was at the time unable to
      contiol his own faculties, would be
      worthless, nor would a person under
      what is called hypnotic influence be
      permitted to testify in a court of com
      mon law while in that condition, if such
      condition were known to the court. 11 a
      person BeSerinf under temporary or
      permanent aberration of mind is dis
      qualified as a witness, so would a per
      son be who waa under the influence
      either of narcotics or intoxicants to such
      an extent as to atlect his judgment. If
      you once assume that a person can be
      placed under hypnotic influence and the
      law should recognize it, it would cer
      tainly disqualify that person from testi
      fying while in that condition.
      HON. CHARLES E. FLANDRAU.
      On the subject of hypnotism 1 know
      nothing, and do not suppose any one
      knows any more than I do, therefore 1
      will say nothing about it.
      As to whether the plea of having been
      under hypnotic influence at tho time of
      the commission of a crime would be re
      ceived by a court as a defense, all I can
      say is to Quote a very familiar principle
      in criminal law, winch is that intention
      is Mm gist of oil crime. No ohm can be
      guilty of a crime unless lie perpetrated
      it knowingly. Responsibility for ciime
      depends wholly upon intention.
      A familiar instance of this principle i
      is the. plea of insanity, if the party is
      insane when the act is committed, he is
      not himself, is not impelled b\ his own i
      reason, but by some delusion thai clouds
      bn mind and destroys his will. .So he j
      is not held responsible for his act.
      If any one person possesses the power
      of absolutely controlling the actions of
      another (which [seriously doubt, unless
      such other is so mentally diseased as to
      be generally irresponsible), and should
      by such influence and power impel such
      person to commit a crime. tii«?n, of
      course, the one exerting the influence
      would be the criminal, and not the party
      performing the involuntary act. This
      is on the principle that he acted without
      intention on hi* part, but by an irre
      sistible impulse exerted by another.
      Whether courts will accept any ex
      pert evidence on a matter of this kind.
      1, of course, am unable to say; but. in
      the light of experience, science and
      common sense, I think they should be
      very careful In listening to anything of
      the kind.
      Charles E. Flasdkau.
      DR. W. E. HALLOWELL.
      A great deal of nonsense has been
      printed in the daily press lately about
      hypnotism, «nd people generally seem
      willing to set hardly any limit to the
      powers of the dreadful individuals who
      "influence," in accordance with their
      own sweet will, any and everybody with
      whom they come into contact, and be
      fore whom neither virtue, life nor prop
      erty is supposed to be safe. If one may
      judge by the tone of the press in the
      :.ews and editorial eolutnus,an epidemic
      of hypnotic crime is threatening the inteerity of society. It is even pro
      posed to appeal to legislation to
      protect a helpless community against
      these dangerous persons, and, strange
      to say, by a law forbidding the class of
      men least likely to misuse their power
      -namely, physicians aim dentists- to
      induce th« hypnotic state, leaving the
      man with the "evil eye" loose among
      the people.
      As a matter of fact, there Is nothing
      j more mysterious about hypnotism thai:
      there is about any scientific subject, ol
      j which our knowledge is incomplete.
      Indeed, the vital point in the subject
      I is not the hypnotic sleep at all, but" th«
      j "sufgeattoa;" and by suggestion wear*
      all influenced, and constantly. It you
      t«ll any one something, he is inclined tc
      I believe it. or. if he is told to do some
      i thing, he is inclined to do it.
      The intensity or this inclination de«
      pends upon the character of the individ
      ual tiiat receives the "suggestion." and.
      to a smaller extent, upon the manner in
      which it is given. If we see* ther
      mometer registering 30 deg below
      zero, we are likely to begin to feel cold,
      even though we thought it a line morn
      ing a few minutes before. We
      have all been told that there is
      a man in the moon, and prob
      ably most of us have seen him: but
      Were we all to draw what we see,
      how many of the pictures would be the
      same? That it is possible to make a
      well man sick ny repeatedly assuring
      him that he is sick is well known. In
      normal sleep a mind is still more open
      to such an influence; and people half
      asleep will do almost anything the} are
      ordered to do; only, if it be a compiN
      rated action, they usually awake be
      fore fully accomplishing it.
      Ordinary sleep itself is induced large
      ly by an autosuggestion, as when a per
      son that is not at all sleepy goes to bed
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1899-09-24/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=Hypnotic+HYPNOTISM+Hypnotism+Hypnotize+Hypnotized+medicine&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.204,-0.07,1.407,1.407,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>WHAT IS HYPNOTISM swim. Anyone who desires can l arn how to Hyp-
      nottte. Anyone who learns can practise It. The Held
      Is Htpnotltedt What form l exerted that after for Its exercise Is as wide as humanity Itself. As a
      makingRmnn sleeproiidcn him ton false wakeful. study It Is neither deep nor dlfflerilt. The most
      nc s In which he obejr anysuirKettlon loses hit IJon- ordinary capacity and attention are all that arc re
      itltr. jiiMXt ii UfiRuiRf for- quired. The study Is not only easy but delightful
      dun to him feels rontrmtlc- and Inspiring. You must Irurn It. You cannot
      torjrirnnMloni ntmtakesrart afford to neglect n science so full of grand poMlblll-
      In ttrnnec scene ami Ihcnii ties. If you desire to make the most of Ufa you
      suddenly aroused to Imvc no should master Its powers for yourself and nse them
      memory of what hns hap for your own gain advancement and Inflne nee. Why
      pened not.yourself sway the minds of othtrs.control friend
      These questions are airtta. ship and altcctlon. heal the sick and sultorlng gKo
      tins the minds of untold proOtablo entertainment In publto or private and dis
      thousands throughout the cover at your v. 111 the hidden aveimn of success and
      world toitAr. What do you material wealth Others nrodolng lu Whynotyouf
      know about Hypnotism r
      Nothing. Then 1 will tell jou HOW YOU MAY LEARN HYPNOTISM.
      nil about It.
      I will show rou that It Is I am recognized aa the
      the tnout wotiilrrfnl leading Hypnotist InAmer
      tliltiR on rnrth. I will lea. 1 lint e practised and
      taught the Art of Hypnotism
      provo to on that Ilrpnottim
      cures diseasethat ItbanUhc tism for years. Nearly all
      pain that It unravels the mjrt- thechlcf Hypnotists of the
      lory of crimp that It aid Jus- land have been my pupils.
      ttco that It fosters brainpower No other Hypnotist has
      
      power ml tint It can bruucd won greater renown In this
      by all who know It to mnko those dear to them happy field or haa done so much
      nnd auccetif ul to reform the crrlnff and degraded and for the promotion of this
      to confer n thousand blessings on ttio feeble the un wonderful Science. 1 am
      happy the poverty-stricken on the unetlnp of mind the conceded authority on
      nnd body who arc al ays and everywhere a largo ele this subject In this coun
      ment In our surroundings. try. I have given the best of my days to tha study
      and demonstration of thin darling sclcnco. Its wonderful
      1 win ihow jou that every day la revealing new
      wonders deeper mysteries nnd wander possibilities derful powers and mysteries have become a part of
      In thin the Selrnco of the Century and that you my being and fill mo with an enthusiasm that over
      rnn learn to utlllie thin wonderful force In all Iti flows In the longing to Impart them to others. I nm
      form and phases. I will tell you about a wonderful like one who has found gold-mine and cannot keep
      Illumined book on Hypnotism which for the asking the secret of his wealth. All the plaudits I have won
      w HI conio to you postage paid without any charge or In my exhibitions and all the money I hm e made by
      cost whatever. But first you Ik them could not gratify mo half to much as to
      know that others were cherishing the snmo science
      WHAT IS HYPNOTISM and would further the development of Its possibili
      ties for good I want to Interest the whole world la
      Hypnotism Isaniipll or trance-like sleep i that one Hypnotism. I want you to learn It. 1 want you to
      person by certain simple methods east orcr another. understand It because It will give you the mastery of
      while In thlsstatcthasubjectorhypn minds the ability to mould at pleasure the Impe
      oncan bo made to perform the most rial human will. Hypnotism will do n thousand
      urprlstnR and amazing feats bodily times more than this. It Is n healer of disease. It
      nnd mental of which they are totally .Isnwlnncrof human affections. It
      Incapable whtlo In their waking Isn spell of hnp. It Is an agency of
      hours. The mind of the subject Is success position wealth nnd fame.
      entirely under tlio control of the It Is n tutrncle. worker and an Influ
      operator. Ho may be made to see ence In all the ltal concerns
      and bcnr nnd think and feel exactly as the of Individuals families and so1 1
      Hypnotist wishes and just so long and no clety. Not to know such n
      longer 1 science Is to ho Ignorant Indeed
      Not to use. such a weapon 1st
      THE WONDERS OF HYPNOTISM. prcmo folly. It Is a\ntlabl
      to young or old of cither
      In attempting to stale what Hypnotism Is sex and It Is my proud
      I can gl\olntho space hero available but n boast to have made It
      bnro outline of Its tremendous powers. No
      pen could adcquatclydescrlbetheinarvclsihat FREE TO ALL.
      may bo bronght about through Hypnotism.
      You must sco It and learn to use It before I I have publfshed at great
      you can fully renllto how wonderful Is that eixpnnao n MA51-
      Nllout nnil mynterlouH force which en MOTII ir.i.us-
      ables one man to seize on Its very throne the TKATljn TK15AT-
      will of another and'mako him conform to his IHF. or limtriirtor
      Bllgbtest wish In every act and feeling. In llypnotlamwhlcli
      tein ovcrythlnir
      THE USE OF HYPNOTISM. te about this Art. A
      copy of It Is at your
      The possession of Hypnotic power will open _ eervlca If you tnko
      up to you whole regions of good to your fellow mor the trouble to write for It.
      tals and a sure way for yourself to honors and wealth There Is positively no cost nor charge In connection
      no less than to scientific progress and pleasant pas- with this gift. If you wrlto for It oven on a postal
      time. If you are an eager student It will unfold to card 1 will send It promptly nnd free by mall. Kv-
      you a now and fascinating realm of science. If you eryhodv who has read It pronounces It a wonderful
      are a person of means and book. It Is a clear exposition of the Importance
      S leisure Itwlll provide you with methods wonders and uses of Hypnotic Sclcncn
      v endless recreation. If you are down even to the details of entertainments given
      generous and philanthropic for money-making purposes. Never before \\ai
      \Itwlllcnablcyoutuheapblcsi- such a gift made In the Interests of any science.
      lIngs on less fortunate fellow-
      j beings. If you are the head THIS WONDERFUL BOOK IS FREE.
      j will of a make family or household. It It Is the most valuable and Interesting work of the
      nnd you the physician kind ever published. It explains the Mysteries or
      true ot
      comforter those
      lu Hypnotism from A to Z. It tells you Just what Hyp
      your that caro. And finally notism Is and what It will accomplish. It tells you
      suppose ago or fortune how you may control the minds of others perform ns-
      arc frowning upon you or that tonlimng feats and produce amusement by the hour.
      you arestlllyoung.fortuneless It covers the whole ground of Hypnntlo methods In
      and and have
      friendless to
      yet caryo In
      your way
      such that ou can learn rapidly. It tells you
      away
      the world all these various privileges will be In
      your
      all should know about Hypnotism Its phenomena
      and with them you
      grasp along a sure means to position
      na Its mysteries and Its advantages to you personally
      Influence happiness and golden wealth. If
      your
      wealth. Influence
      for the certain attainment of
      ally
      choice Is not already taken or desire to make
      you a
      cannot fiord to bo without
      health and happiness. Ton n
      change can also 11 ml In Hypnotism Itself lu-
      you a
      and honorable out this knowledge. You need not alt In darkncsa
      crtithe. tbat
      permiinant profession while such light Is free. Do sensible send for a copy
      will give you fame and competence during your active
      of this book and Icnrn to Hypnotize.
      with and
      tive years security distinction for the
      evening ot life.
      HYPNOTISM IN DISEASE.
      Hypnotism has Indeed grand and glorious utili
      ties It has gains aa well as enjoyments for all who
      master It. Among these the
      place of honor limy well bo
      1 plven to Us wonderful efficacy
      llu alleviating human gutter-
      ling and curing disease. With-
      lout doubt It la the Krcat
      Ihcnlorof the future. No
      /Anodyne ever known Is equal
      f to It In the relief and allcvl-
      r atton of pain. No medicine
      ever prepared can wrestle so
      effectively with the ravages of
      disease. The delicate and nervous
      vous woman tbo overworked
      man and the sickly and fretful child may all alike be
      benefited by Its application. It Ii a boon and bless
      ing to the entire race.
      AS A MEANS OF AMUSEMENT.
      The fun makln possibilities of Hypnotism are
      Imply unlimited. Ha\o you over been present at
      an exhibition ot Hypnotism given cither to a publto
      or private audience If you have you will readily
      agree that as a means of entertainment of genuine
      hilarity and fun this wonderful power Is beyond all
      rivalry. Not all the comedy ever teen on the mimic
      stage Is so absurd and mirth-provoking or so full of
      laughable and yet harmless surprises.
      The absurd and ridiculous things a Hypnotized
      person will do are almost beyond belief Uo will do
      anything you command or ftuRgcst to him.
      A f uw persons wlillo under the Influence of Hypno
      tism will produce more genuine amusement moro
      astonishment and amazement than a minstrel show
      and comic openi combined. This crand work contains hundreds or tbo most ar
      This fact will at once tistic Illustrations ever produced. Tlio cover Is n
      suggest that If you have no remarkable work of art. Above all clto the subject
      accomplishments Hypno- matter Is ably handled and Is new llcly and fascin
      tlsm would provo of Im ating. Everything Is told In plain lanijunRO Kvcry
      mense value to you. You fact method and phenomenon described can lie un
      would no longer ho kept derstood by anybody who knows how to read. Kvcry
      In the background at a par process that calls for pictorial help will bo found
      ty or publlu gathering for fully Illustrated so that you will bo carried along
      with the abfilty to llyp- pleasantly until you know all the Ins and outs of tlio
      notlze you can produce subject. Everything about the work shows that no
      amusement for hours at a expense was spared In getting It up and when you
      time. With a few subjects consider tbat It
      or even one you can keep _ COSTS ABSOLUTELY NOTHING
      an audience lu a continual roar of laughter.
      you must admit that this Is tha most generous offer
      YOU CAN LEARN IT. uvcr made lu behalf of this marvelous science.
      Let me mail you a copy of tuU book. If you nro
      Reader you can become a Hypnotist. There Is no not surprised auddcllRhted with It If you do no t con-
      reason on earth to the contrary. It is a faculty Inborn elder It tlio most valuable and Interesting Rift ever
      born In every Individual just like the faculty of offered the American public I will Rladly reimburse
      speech. It only requires cultivation In order to bo you for the slight trouble of wrltlnc for It. Hcincm-
      developed and applied. In fact. It Is as easy to learn herltls free as nlr. A postal card will bring It by
      how to Hypnotize aa It Is to learn how to waltz or return mallpostage paid. Bend for It today.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84037890/1888-07-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotizing&amp;r=0.376%2C0.307%2C0.531%2C0.298%2C0&amp;st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Study of the Hypnotic State.
  Dr. A. Dichas has mado n detailed study
  of tho memory In tho hypnotic state, nnd
  summarizes his main conclusions
  as follows: (1) during tlio hypnotic
  sleep tho subject remembers the experiences
  of his wiking Ufo ns well rs of
  previous hypnosis; (2) in hypnotism tlicro
  is often an exalt tion of tho memory, and
  at times n cliang in Its content, leading
  to tho assumpti n of a foreign
  (3) tho mo nory of what has been
  going on during hypnosis is usually lost,
  it can often bo ruvlvcd by n simplo suggestion,
  and at times the memory of a
  suggested hallucination may l!.,jor on.
  and influenco thu waking condition; (4)
  tho operator cau at his wjll havo any of
  tho nets of the liypnotK state remembered
  or forgotten by maMug this a part
  of tho suggestion; (5) sitgjfcstion seems to
  bo largely explicable 'as unconscious
  memory.
  Dr. Cybulski has studied tho power of
  hypnotic subjects to hypnotlzo themselves.
  IIo finds that such subjects
  strongly Imagiuo for a mlnuto or less that
  that tho operator commands them to go
  to sleep, nnd tho desired result ensues.
  Furthermore, If tlio subject, on going to
  sleep, imagines himself controlled by a
  certain person, then, even though another
  sent him to sleep, he will bo subject to
  tlio former, nnd not to tho operator.
  These observations show the Importance
  of tho subjectivo clement in tho process
  of hypnotism, nnd Indicate tho method by
  which tho subject unconsciously takes
  suggestions and acts upon them. Dr.
  Bcrkhan has applied hypnotism to the
  amelioration of the hearing of tho deaf.
  Ho tested tho hearing of nino deaf boys,
  and, after hypnotizing them, spoko to
  them and had varions.noises made before
  them Tho hearing of four of them was
  found to bo Improved, and tho improve
  merit is reported as still persisting after
  eighteen months Science.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042405/1892-12-15/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=hypnosis+Hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotized+hypnotizing&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.281,0.3,1.561,1.561,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>THE ABUSE OF HYPNOTISM.
      Quack* and CliarlntaiM Wlio Mukti I'M OL
      It to iiull the Public.
      Wliilo tho benefits from hypnotism
      thus fur have been few anil small, the
      evils have been many nml great. Its
      Bleeplike btato is not a normal sleep,
      bringing health and Htrength to the
      sliuuberer, but a morbid conditiou bor­
      dering u|iou disease. It irritates the en­
      tire nervous organization and tempora­
      rily if not organically weakens the sys­
      tem. This drawback is serious enough.
      Darker and more terrible effects lie in
      the suppression of the object's will for
      the time being, and the substitution
      therefor of the operator's. In this re­
      gard it opens avenues to crime and crimi­
      nals such us has never been equaled
      heretofore. Already so many discredit­
      able actions, not to use a stronger word,
      have been committed in Europe by
      means of hypnotism that in Italy, Aus
      tro-Hungary, parts of Switzerland, Co­
      penhagen and other municipalities laws
      have been enacted prohibiting its public
      practice by any except physicians. So,
      on the other hand, tip police, without
      any statute on the subject, have treated
      traveling mesmerists as disorderly char­
      acters. Thus Donato was expelled from
      Italy, and Hansen, another hypnotist,
      from Austria, was notified never to re­
      turn under penalty of arrest, fine and
      imprisonment.
      This Donato (whose real name, by the
      way, is Dhont) hypnotized an Italian ar­
      tillery officer, who immediately became
      half crazy. From time to time he would
      go into somnambulism at the sight of a
      bright object. He would follow carriage
      iamps. and unless prevented would walk
      toward locomotive or steamer lights.
      An architectural student was mesmer­
      ized by staring at his compasses, after
      which it was impossible for him to draw
      without going to sleep.
      A young girl of Milan, of beauty and
      character, was hypnotized and impressed
      with the notion that she was married 'o
      a man she had never seen but once, and
      then in the darkness. She went crazy
      and died in a hospital.
      Another voting girl (of Paris, this
      time) was put under a similar spell and
      was ruined. She finally entered the
      Saltpetriere hospital, where, after along
      and painful remedy, what was left of
      her former self was pronounced cured.
      In New York a hypnotized person was
      made to believe that he had taken slow
      poison. He fell sick and wasted away
      to a shadow. Not until the attending
      physician discovered the true nature of
      the hallucination and relivpnotized the
      subject was there any symptom of con­
      valescence.
      In Turin, at a series of hypnotic lec­
      tures and public experiments, a large
      proportion of those who attended were
      taken sick with headache, insomnia and
      other nervous ailments. A few of those
      who were of a hysterical temperament
      remained ill for along time.
      In the foregoing cases the hypnotizing
      was done with no evil intent, but there
      are hundreds of recorded instances where
      it was done with intent of evil.—Phila­
      delphia Times.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063557/1888-03-02/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotization+hypnotized&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.068,-0.053,0.582,0.654,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Tcoplc fiuseeptlblo to JtypnntlMn.
  Pcrsons of n nervous constitution, nnd
  ln particular thoso subject to hysteria,
  nro most npt to fnll Into nrtiflciai Klcop.
  Thcro is thcn produccd in thein n pecu
  liar neurosis, hypnotism, having psjxhl
  cal nnd physical charactcra of its own a
  genuino disease prcscnting n diversity of
  Byinptoms. Hcnco hypnotic phenomena
  ouglit not to be callcd forth rnshly nor
  without the )recaution8 suggestcd by
  inedical scienco. 'VVomcn aro spccially
  Biiscoptiblo to hypnotio manipulation, par
  tictilarly during tho period bctwoen the
  18tlinnd tho 30th ycar, whcn tho ner
  vous system is in full nctivity. Young
  lncn may bo hypnotized, but it is very
  difllcult to produco hypnotic slccp in old
  uion or in ehildren. Pcrsons who in carly
  llfo nro subject to naturnl somnambulism
  or slecp walldng are latcr in life good
  hypnotio subjccts, just as they aro nlo
  likely to Imj victiius of hysteria and othcr
  nervous complaints.
  Jlany aro tlio processes oniploycd for
  prodticing hypnoais. One that is very
  frecjucntly used consists in fixing tiio gazo
  upon soino hriglit object placed a littlo
  abovo tho eycs and in front of tho median
  lino of tho forohcad, so that visunl fntiguo
  uiay cnsuo quickly, tiio eyeballs being
  dircctod upward and iuward. This pro
  cess, or othcrs of a liko kind, may Ihj otn
  ployed in tho caso of pcrsons wlio havo
  novcr bcforc been hypnotized. Dtit after
  awliile, when the subject has, so to speak,
  been eduoated. various nioro exix?ditious
  uiethods may be employed. Thus a jct
  of elcctrio light or a violcnt blow stmck
  on a gong near tlio ear of tho subject will
  quickly induco sleep. Again, in hypno
  tizablo ixji-sons, the surface of tlie body
  often prescnts special points, "hypnogenic
  zoncs, as thoy aro called, analagous to
  tho ''hysterogcuic zones." Simplo pres
  8uro upon theso produces hypnosis.
  Even in tho caso of tho most susceptiblo
  individuals rarely does sleep nppear when
  tliey. for tho flrst time, undergo tho hyp
  notizing manipulations, howcver skilled
  tho ojwrator may be. Tliero is necded a
  completo surrender of ono's will and nb
  senco of all mental preoccupation, and
  on tho part of the company prcsent abso
  lutc silcnce. In most cases exhibitions
  of hypnotization develop, at flrst, only
  vaguo jihcnomena not easily classified,
  foreshadowing, 60 to 6)eak, what will
  follow later. North American Eoview.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1896-08-22/ed-1/?sp=19&amp;q=Hypnosis+HYPNOSIS+hypnosis+hypnot+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized+hypnotizer&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.711,0.247,0.258,0.29,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>HYPNOSIS MACHINES
      Devices to Produce the M umrne
      8tate Mechanicaly.
      "Ill' ERB AD CM lTtm
      Influence of Certain Chemicals
      Upon Sensitive Subjects.
      USES OF THE POWER
      VEN HYPNOSIS
      may now be pro
      duced by machinery.
      We are approaching
      a day when the di
      rect influence of
      Svengalles will not
      be necessary to
      throw Trilbies Into
      subjective at ate a.
      when hypnotists will
      exert their powers
      through machinery
      set to operate at
      given times, the
      presence of the Instruments being un
      known to the subjects. The mechanical
      mesmerizer will then find an essential
      place In the burglar's tool kit, and we will
      have to look under our beds to see If such
      traps have been set by our enemies. The
      mechanical hypnotizer as now made, how
      ever, is strictly a scientific instrument.
      The government's bureau of education re
      cently purchased a collection of such appar
      atus, which are new In this country. They
      will be used by a specialist for studying
      the values of hypnotic suggestion in the
      education of the abnormal classes. Ex
      periments will be made determining their
      effect upon the sensibilities, emotions,
      breathing,. circulation and temperature of
      the body'.
      An Elaborate Apparatus.
      The most elaborate form of hypnotiser
      is a small box, containing clock work, sur
      mounted by two horizontal oblong fans,
      one over the other, revolving rapidly In op
      posite directions. The fans are studded
      on each side with a row of circular mir
      rors, about the size of nickel pieces. The
      rapid rotation produces an odd flashing
      effect which greatly fatigues the eyelid
      muscles of the beholder. This machine is
      found to be very effective when used upon
      sersitives who can be thrown into a hyp
      notic sleep by concentration or sight stimu
      lus.
      A simpler form of mechanical hypnotizer
      is a belt of broad tape to be placed upon
      the forehead and over the temples, being
      tied at the back of the head. From a me
      tallic plate In front protrudes a wire, ex
      terding upward In an S-like curve and
      holding a bright ball of nickel, about the
      size of a marble, at the end. When this is
      placed upon the st'bject the wire Is bent
      until the ball reaches a point above the
      eye, where it may be seen by the wearer
      only by intensely straining the eyelids.
      The same effect, as produced by the former
      rr achine is accomplished by this simpler ap
      paratus. These instruments have been
      Irvented to serve in substitution for the
      gestures, known as passes, commonly ma
      by hypnotists. The scientific hypnotist
      makes movements before and above tho
      eyes of his subject to concentrate his at
      tention and to fatigue the eyelid muscles
      both by causing the eyes to follow the
      movements and by fannirig air against
      them. Fatigue of the muscles of the eye
      lids is found to he one of the direct causes
      of sleep. Persons in no mental need of sleep
      may "read themselves sleepy" under a too
      bright or a too (im light. A severe breeze
      against the eyelids will cause the same
      effect.
      Magnetic Influentea.
      Another form of hypnotizer, in this col
      lection, is a large horshoe magnet with an
      attached armature. It is given to a sensi
      tive who is told to continuously separate
      and fit together the two parts. A similar
      magnetic hypnotizer is a steel ring to fit
      the index finger. The ring is of magnetized
      steel and is broken at one place, the space
      being filled by a small steel armature.
      These two contrivances are used princi
      pally for humoring the more unsophisti
      cated and superstitious sensitives who fos
      ter the belief that hypnotism is supernat
      ural. The magnet in most cases suggests
      mystery to the ignorant and sensitives of
      that class are readily excited by it. The
      ring device, also called a hypnoscope, Is
      used by some hypnotists for determining
      sensitives. Hypnotizable persons are al
      leged to experience certain tinglings in the
      skin and twitchings of the muscles while
      wearing it. A more complicated instru
      ment in this collection, which may be used
      as a hypnoscope, is a bulb-shaped rod, re
      sembling an electrode, which may be
      made to create pressure against the
      palm of the hand by a spring inside. When
      the pressure Is applied the subject is asked
      if he feels an electric shock. If he so con
      fesses he is rated as a hynotic sensitive.
      Sometimes the whole frame will tremble
      as a result of this imaginary electrical
      fluid.
      Crystal Viaions.
      Equally interesting devices of a related
      class, now growing in vogue among certain
      experimental hypnotists, are for applica
      tion to sensitives for the purpose of caus
      ing hallucinations known as crystal visions.
      One instrument of this class is a ball of
      crystal mounted upon a handle. Mirrors
      and other polished or transparent surfaces
      are employed for the same effect. The
      crystal or reflecting medium by producing
      partly obscured or scattered reflections to
      the sensitive mind's eye aid the subje-t
      in perceiving unnatural mental embodi
      ments of various objects. Many abnormal
      persons, habitually haunted by phantasms,
      for which visions they develop appetites,
      so to speak, employ these crystals and re
      flectors for throwing themselves into states
      during which they may experience what Is
      alleged to be the actual or imagined "sixth
      sense" or "second sight." Crystal gazing
      has lately become so popular that many
      psychic experimentalists in Europe are in
      viting tests with the paraphernalia thus
      employed, and agents were some time
      since engaged by the Society for Psychical
      Research to furnish balls for the purpose.
      Prof. Win. Romaine Newbold of the Uni
      versity 'of Pennsylvania recently made an
      extensive Investigation of crystal vision
      and found that twenty-two subjects out of
      eighty-six could perceive illusions by gaz
      ing into mirrors, surfaces of water- and
      objects of glass varying in form. Phan
      tasms appeared to the sensitives usually
      within five minutes, being prec~ed direct
      ly by cloudiness, hazes of color or illumin
      ations before the eyes. The phantasms
      varied from dim outlines to brilliant col
      ored pictures. Like dreams some of these
      forms were based upon recent experiences
      of the subjects, while others were purely
      fantastic.
      An Experiment.
      A simple experiment in thi\ line may be
      tried at home by any one who *11 sit before
      an open window, at twilight, keeping his
      gaze fixed preferably upon some landscape,
      distant row of houses or collection of con
      spicuous clouds. If the temptation to wink
      the eyelids can be resisted until the eyes
      become greatly fatigued, so as to remain
      open only at a great strain, the natural
      images will gradually grow more and more
      indistinct, and will apparently arrange
      themselves into fantastic groups or fade in
      to rapidly changing forms. The abnormal
      imagination of a person subject to Uight
      hallucinations would readily discern weird
      phantoms in such a picture.
      Drugs, such as urethane, suiphonal, peaa
      dehyde, etc., are now used successfully to
      produce a sleep which to all appearances is
      hypnotic. Some foreign hypnotists use
      ether and chloroform to induce hypnosis.
      Recent experiments indicate that there is
      a great similarity between hypnosis and theI
      action of hasheesh,as well as the newly test
      ed mescal, which is used by certain of our
      western Indians to produce trances. Phe
      nomena very similar to hypnosis is now
      noticed also during the ordinary sleep pro
      duced by simple anaesthetics, and the ques
      tion is being asked, Do anaesthetics produce
      hypnosis? A member of the Royal Chemi
      cal Society of London recently demonstrated
      that man possesses two distinct conscious
      nesses. He says that persons under the in
      fluence of anaesthetics. while not conscious
      of what is happening at the time of the
      operation, are sometimes able, several days
      after, to describe in detail what was hap
      pnnto e them. Wrhat he.n call t.."o
      aday consciousnE as" was absent at the time.
but the "subliminal consciousness." he says.
was present during the operation. Hence
anaesthetics destroy the former and only
postpone the enregistering of the sensation
conductors controlling the latter conscious
ness. It may be that this "subliminal con
sciousness" is the one affected by hypnot
ists.
Senlttve to Drmss.
Recent laboratory experiments have also
been made to ascertain the effects of drugs
upon persons in a hypnotic state. Some
subjects are found to be so sensitive to
drugs while in this condition that they con
tort themselves in various ways when the
substances are not applied directly, but
merely held in proximity to their skin, not
even touching it. Some chemical substanc+-s,
even when sealed in tubes, will cause sen
sitives to alter their bodily appearances and
physical conditions, producing violent con
vulsions, hallucinations, alterations of the
pupils, changes In the pulse-beats, symp
toms of joy, grief or anger and other emo
tional conditions.
The influence of color upon hypnotized
persons has also been tested in the labo
ratcry by subjecting sensitives to rays of
light passing through various screens of
different colored glass. Blue light is found
to produce sadness, red light joy, yellow
light strong sffection and violet or green
light variable conditions. Charcot used a
sudden ray of Intense light as one means
or throwing sensitives into the hypnotic
state.
Just as these instruments for producing
hypnosis are applied to the sense of sight,
other physical methods are applied, in its
induction, to the senses of hearing and
touch. The condition does not seem to be
induced by stimulations of either taste smell. Charcot threw some of his subjects
into hypnotic states by the sharp and
sudden sounding of a large gong. The
ticking of a watch has been used with
the same success by others, the sensitive
being required to concentrate his mind
upon the sound. just as he does upon the
seeing of the revolving fans or nickel ball.
The monotonous chants sung by semi
civilized nations are found to produce the
same effect.
Strokes and Passes.
For creating hypnosis through the sense
of touch, strokings or pressure upon the
skin are resorted to by some hypnotists,
while others apply warm plates of metal
to different parts of the body. Physicians
realize that warmth induces natural sleep,
while coldness tends to prevent it. Some
foreign hypnotists maintain that the crown
of the head, roof of the nose, the thumb
or elbow are most sensitive to hypnotic
stimulation by touch. Some merely
s'ratch the skin of the neck or touch the
forehead. The electric battery has been
resorted to by a few experimenters, who
claim that it is successful. as an inducing
agent. It is said to cause the same imag
inary effect as the magnet.
It is now an easy matter for certain hyp
niotists to transform natural sleep into
hypnotic sleep without the subject's knowl
edge. Thus one .who gces to sleep in a
public place may never remember what
foolish actions he has been made to do
Ouring that period. Hypnotic suggestion is
the latest phase of this whole subject which
is now interesting experimenters. A sensi
tive, under hypnotic influence, receives a
command fram the hypnotist which he
will obey on awakening, altough he is un
(onsciou of ever having received such a
(ommand. This power is used by a physi
cian in Massachusetts, who is said to be
able to stop the most severe pain by sug
gestion. Several people report to the Soci
ety for Psychical Research that he has
given thcm suggestions before they have
gone to the dentist, %ith the result that
their dentstry has invariably been painless,
kxperiments are now being made as to the
valu. of hypnotic suggestion in education.
Its medical value has already neen proven
in France. where such conditions as ner
vous insomnia, sonambulism, kleptomania,
ilziness and varicus forms of moral degen
eracy have been cured by its means.
Ues of Hypnosis.
The power of suggestic n as an agent in
crime is now being talked about in this
country. Men are believed to have been
banged for committing murder while acting
under hypnotic Influence from another.
Some celebrated medico-legalists have pro
posed that laws should be passed defining
the responsible murderers in such cases.
In such an event hypnotism will be as both
ersome a plea of defense as insanity is to
day. The dangers threatened by the vicious
or careless hypnotist have become legally
realized In France and Russia. In the
former hypnotism is forbidden for purposes
of public amusement, and in the latter no
persons except, licensed physicians can
practice It It is said that tilt per cent of
ithe people In thne world are hypnotizable.
The hypnotists, on the other hand, are dis
covering and improving their powers faster
and faster each day. Will they at some
future century become the governing class
If a door is hung
to swnmy one way,
I there s no use
trying to push it
the other w ay.
.1 There is a right
and a wrong way
to do things.
Many thousands
of women in
and would like to
be well. T he y
aremaking efforts
to get well, hut
they are making them in the wrong way.
They are taking medicines prepared by in
competent nurses, or inexperienced physi
cians. They ar alubmitting to exam
inations and local treatment, for which thesem
Is generally no necessity. They are grow
ngsteadily worse instead of steadily better.
Tere is no reason why almost every wo
man should not be well and strong. Over
thirty years ago, Dr. R. V. Pierce, of Buf
falo, an eminent and successful specialist in
the treatment of the diseases of women,
discovered a wonderful specific for woman's
diseases las since become world
mous as .r Pirce's Favorite Prescription,
It cures all forms of female weakness ad
disease, Its effect is immediately ecpi
ble in the better feeling of the palnit
forces ont impuiy soothes e infianema
tion that is always present in disorders of
this kind, promotes regularity, and stops
debilitating drains on the system. It cures
nevuness, ritailty 19epe.mesa*, lac
CREAT FiEDICAL. BOOK FREE.
Every' womaan should have a coyof Dusder
Pierce's Comamou Sense Medical Adviser. R ts
a handosey illustrated wolusa
of womnen. It is writtn a
thre hnrd illsttissu
colored plates. Untif recently,
it was aoid at a dollar and a
hafa ,and at tis price,
of sia hundred and eighty thu
sand copies. Rt Is now oareed,
mlerba~d. bssistey fwa to any woman who
to cove the o mail o Westd'
dhbnding if ihdn is, a each
thty ai in aleLm
!orld's
perient Water.
cess in U. S.
.A Over the Worm.
without the signature
firm
axlehner,
Label.
es of the earth, and will the great host of
sensitives become their slaves? Perhaps
that is somewhat the case now. Trust
worthy authorities relate hypnotism with
the same power by which the teacher Im
Presses his students, the preacher converts
his congregation, the pleader convinces the
jury, the cross-examiner "rattles" the wit
new. or by which the orator holds his audi
ence with bated breath. receiving cheers at
every nod. although heard and understood
by few. According to this. Mr. Bryan is a
hypnottst. and doubtless Mr. McKinley is
one.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-09-06/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=hypnotic+Hypnotic+HYPNOTISM+Hypnotism+hypnotism+science&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.246,-0.223,1.492,1.492,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>HYPNOTISM IN A VERY PAINFUL DENTAL OPERATION
  Bvj a J4ere WaVe of tke jiarxd Ir\ter\se
  Suffering Was pVeVerxted
  In the rooms of the Stomatological Club,
  at Post and Stockton streets, on Tuesday
  afternoon last, a clinic was held in the
  presence of nearly all the members, in i
  which hypnotism was introduced as a sub
  stitute for anesthesia.
  It was an experiment and the experi
  ment was successful in the highest degree,
  insomuch that it is safe to say that it
  fixes the date of a subsidence of old and
  the beginning of entirely new methods in
  the operating-rooms of San Francisco
  dentists.
  Hypnotism is not a new thing in dentis
  try any more than it is in therapeutics. It
  has just landed in San Francisco, how
  ever preceded, to be sure, by tales of
  great successes in Paris, Berlin, London
  and New York. That San Francisco
  dentists are fully alive to the progress that
  has been making in their science and
  eager to keep the best pace that is being
  made in the world was made evident by
  the number in attendance and the inter
  est manifested in the clinic
  The demonstration was arranged by Dr.
  M. W. Levkowicz. His subject was a boy
  of 17, Alfred Boulton, a native of Victoria,
  B. C, but who has returned but a few
  weeks from a residence of some years in
  Honolulu. He was an admirable subject
  for a test of the possibilities of applied
  hypnotism, in that he was a bright-eyed,
  intelligent lad of nervous temperament,
  and in that he had a couple of very sore
  teeth.
  J. B. Earley, a teacher of hypnotism,
  was present to make the magic passes and
  show the congregated doctors how easily
  it might be done. The clinic began
  shortly after 4 o'clock, the subject or pa
  tient being placed in the red-plush chair,
  so full of terrors to the tooth-aching con
  tingent, and all of which tenors were to
  be driven away by the wave of a hand.
  But tne thing was an experiment, and
  the terrors have been long intrenched in
  tnat red-plush chair. Tney laughed at
  this mild attempt to dislodge them— at
  first they did.
  The chair was placed in a wide bay-win
  dow that extends out from an upper floor
  immediately at the corner— the southeast
  corner of Post and Stockton streets. There
  was plenty of light and platform steps sur
  rounded the chair, and on these the mem
  bers of tie society were gathered, full of
  interest. The boy took his place and Pro
  fe^-sor Earley told him to close his ejea.
  He did so. ''You cannot open them,"
  said the professor, and he could not.
  "Open them," said the professor, and be
  did "Piace your hand! together— there;
  you cannot take them apart," and he
  could not.
  "Now when I count ten you will be
  sound asleep and your sense ol feeling
  will have entirely left you, bo that you
  wili feel no »aia."
  The professor counted ten slowly and
  deliberately. The boy waited a moment
  and then opened bis eyes, quite es wide
  awake as before. The professor smiled re
  assuringly and placing his hands upon
  the boy's head, with his thumbs at the
  bridge of the nose, repeated his statement
  in quiet confidence. Still the boy looked
  up with wide-awake eyes. The terror of
  the red cliair was upon him.
  Two or three times the charm was tried
  again, but it would not work. The doctors
  watched and waited patiently enough, but
  their comments and discussions, however
  quiet, were distracting. The professor
  saw his influence slipping away. He took
  the boy out of the red chair and led him
  to a rocter in the corner, as unlike the red
  cbair as possible.
  Still the boy's eyes H
  would open. It be-
  gan to look like a ,fl
  I hopeless case. The J
  I doctors broke up in jl
  j knots and talked of
  I other things.
  Finally it was SU2- I
  gested that the pro- I
  fessor lake the sub- I
  ject into a room I
  I apart and to them- I
  selves. He did so and I
  the doctors waited I
  waited quite a little I
  j while. Then the sep- I
  arating door opened I
  and the doctor en- I
  tered, leading the I
  boy, his eyes fast H
  shut, impossible for I
  him to open them, I
  but still not asleep. I
  He was led to the I
  chair, and the profes- I
  sor told the doctors I
  to go ahead.
  "This boy is not I
  asleep," said the pro- I
  fessor. 'He is in a I
  semi-conscious state, I
  but he has nofeelin.-. I
  You can work witli I
  him with perfect free- I
  dom." He spoke to I
  the boy. "Now. my I
  boy, you will feel no I
  pain whatever. Do I
  not think of the den- I
  tist; think of me; no I
  harm will come to I
  I you; you need have I
  Ino fear; lie there I
  quietly and dream I
  pleasant dreams."
  Dr. Levkowicz be- I
  gan to work with no I
  more ado. The boy I
  responded to his in- I
  structions, opening I
  his mouth wide and I
  holding it as desired. I
  He had what the den- I
  tists call a "fungoid I
  growm 01 me pulp
  of a back molar. rffi^^s^^^^^^he
  "nerve," as it is popularly called, was ex
  posed and had filled up the large cavity of
  a decayed tooth.
  As explained afterward by the doctor
  "This is a most sensitive and painful con
  dition. To touch such a tooth under or
  dinary conditions will cause great pain,
  and dentists do not attempt to work with
  such a tooth until after two or three days,
  and then with iodine and arsenic The
  THE SAN FRANCISCO CALL, SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 6, 1896.
  THE LAST BOAT
  pulp bleeds prof us°ly upon tne slightest
  touch. Now, I wished to demonstrate
  that with the patient under the influence
  of hypnotism this painful and distressing
  growth could be removed quickly and
  without pain."
  The doctor began digging into the sensi
  tive tooth with his cold steel instruments
  with speedy and certain touch. In fifteen
  minutes the growth had been wholly re-
  Scene at the Clinic in the Rooms of the. Stomatological Club When the Hypnotic Experiment Was Made
  moved and the cavity made clean for a
  fiiling. And during those fifteen minuted
  the boy lay in the chair apparently as
  comfortable as though he were enjoying
  a siesta in a hammock. The professor
  had said at the beginning that there
  j would be a minimum of blood flow from
  i the operation. The doctor took up what
  little there was in the customary way with
  I small pellets of absorbent cotton in the
  I tooth. One of the doctors remarked that
  there seemed to be a good deal of saliva
  in the mouth. "I will stop it," said the
  professor, and he did so by merely speak
  in^ the word.
  When it was finished and the doctors
  had examined and approved and mar
  veled at the demonstration, the boy said,
  "I would like to open my eyes."
  "Oh, certainly," said the professor, "you
  may open your eyes, but you will still re
  main without pain without being sus
  ceptible to pain."
  The boy opened his eyes— as clear and
  as intelligent as when he had closed them.
  Then Doctor Frank 8. Pague stepped up
  with a pair of forceps and from the other
  side of the afflicted mouth he pulled a
  tooth. It was well planted and resisted
  at first and broke off. The doctor took
  another hold, pushed the forceps down
  hard upon the fragment remaining,
  twisted it in tbe fetching way that dentists
  have, until it yielded and came out. It
  was then discovered to have an ulcerated
  root.
  "That should hurt you, boy."
  "Should it?" he answered.
  "Didn't you feel it?"
  "Oh, yes; I felt you were pulling my
  tooth, but it did not hurt."
  "Such a tooth ordinarily is very painful
  in being drawn," explained the doctor.
  J\ Remarkable Derr\or\stratior\ of tke
  JMystericxis Sciervce
  "For fifteen minutes, and sometimes an
  hour, alter pulling an ulcerated tooth the
  patient usually suffers greatly. It is cer
  tainly a convincing demonstration of the
  great beneficence of hypnotism in den
  tistry that this patient did not. Further
  more, I felt his pulse when he took a seat
  in the chair under the hypnotic influence
  and it was beating wildly. During the
  progress of this ordinarily painful opera-
  tion it quieted down until it became en
  tirely normaL"
  But this was not the end of the demon
  stration. The operation for the day being
  finished, the boy said, "1 would like
  to be released now; I want my sense of
  feeling."
  "Certainly," said the professor, "I will
  give you that again." But to show the
  doctors that the subject's entire body was
  without feeling he ran a needle through
  the flesh of the arm and drew it away
  without any blood following.
  "Now," he said, "you have your sense
  of feeling all except in your teeth ttat
  have been operated upon. Tney will re
  main painless until the operation is over
  and they have healed up. You are to go
  up to Dr. Levkowicz' office to-morrow
  morning at 10 o'clock and this tooth will
  be filled. It will give you no pain what-
  ever remember
  I that. Now you have
  sense of feeling
  Hagain except as 1
  Hhave said."
  The clinic being at
  Han end a general dis-
  Heussion of the mys-
  Htery of hypnotism
  Hran on for some time.
  I"I will show you,"
  Hsaid Professor Earley,
  H"the difference in the
  Hamenability of the
  I patient to the influ-
  Hence, now that the
  Hfear of the dental op-
  Herat ion is removed.
  HaII the surroundings
  I were beiore alarming
  H and distracting.
  H&gt;'ow, my boy," said
  I the professor, ad-
  H dressing young 80l-
  Hton, "take that chair
  I over there in the cor-
  I ncr as far from me
  las you can get. Sit
  Hdown. That's right.
  Bw'hen I count ten
  Hyou will be sound
  I asleep." The profes-
  I sor coanted ten and
  I the boy was I asleep. He was put
  Ito convincing tests
  I that it was so.
  B "Now," said the
  Hproiessor, "when you
  Ha wake and have
  Hialked with these gen-
  Htienien in your nor-
  Hmal condition you
  Hwill fall asleep again
  Himmediately upon
  Hseein? me draw my
  H watch from my pock-
  Het. "Then the pro-
  Hfessor snapped his
  H ringers and told him
  Htowakeup. He came
  Hto instantly, lie was
  H questioned as to how
  Ihe lelt and the con-
  Hversation became
  Hg ener al. Professor
  Earley casually drew his watch while
  the boy was looking his way, and
  the latter instantly dropped over asleep.
  The doctors present, as stated, made them
  selves certain that the demonstration was
  in all particulars just what it seemed.
  On Wednesday rooming young Boulton
  went to the office of Dr. Levkowicz
  and bad that sensitive tooth filled without
  feeling any pain, the "post hypnotic sug
  gestion," as they call it, holding good.
  All the dentists present at the clinic and
  aware of the circumstances are agreed
  that the results are nothing less than
  wonderful and that they mean a revolu
  tion in the science of dentistry.
  "It means that by a wave of the hand a
  patient having a painful operation to go
  through may be set at ease. It means
  much for both the dentist and the suffer
  ing public," said one of them.
  The Stomatological Club is a rather ex
  clusive organization and its members were
  at first blush greatly opposed to having the
  fact made public that it had lent itself to
  a countenancing of hypnotism. Dr.
  Levkowicz explained this feeling:
  "We know, as scientific men, the trend
  of the times and the necessity of keeping
  pace with them if we are to keep in the
  race at all. Dr. Bernheim's work in the
  hospitals of France is familiar to all well
  informed practitionera his success, the
  wonderful results he has attained. We
  know also the charlatanism that obtains in
  this mystic art, and we know that the pub
  lic at large, generally less well informed in
  scientific matters than the practitioner, is
  inclined to be wary of men whopraciice it.
  While we feel it our duty to investigate it
  we do not wish the impression to go
  abroad that the members of the Stomato
  logical Club are rushing into hypnotism
  as a fad. We approach the subject with
  the conservative care of a scientific propo
  sition. We feel that it would be a great
  beneficence to a patient if the pain of the
  dentist's chair might be done away with
  by a word. But, while we have had a
  number of experiments of the kind at the
  clubrooms, I am free to say that this of
  Professor Earley is the only one that has
  proved entirely convincing as to the util
  ity of hypnotism in the science of den
  tistry. All persons may not be hypno
  tized, however. Dr. Bumheim himself, I
  believe, brings under the influence only
  about 80 per cent of those he attempts.
  And, at all events, the consent of the
  patient must be obtained. As I say, with
  the Stomatological Club it is a scientific
  experiment."
  Following were the members of the club
  who were present at the clinic; Clinician,
  M. W. Levkowicz; William J. Younger,
  president of the club; Russell H. Cool,
  vice-president; S. E. Knowles, secretary;
  Thomas Morffew, treasurer; Luther A.
  Teague, A. J. Merriman Jr., J. A. W.
  Lundborg, Walter F. Lewis, Clyde S.
  Payne, W. Z. King, H. R. Morton Sr., F.
  M. Hackett, J. S. Knowlton. F. L. Platt,
  S. L. Btrickland, M. A. Greenlaw, J. J.
  Giusti, E. A. Younger, George W. Cool, J.
  E. Cummings, A. H. Millberry. Cecil
  Corwin, Arthur H. Wallace, Frank C.
  Pague, J. L. Asay, Max Sichel, Alfred
  Cane, H. D. Boyes, F. K. Ledyard.
  As for Professor J. B. Parley, who
  worked the strange influence, he is a new
  comer to the City. He is a man of slight
  figure and quiet manner, wearing the ap
  pearance of the student. His voice is low
  and kindly rather than stern and com
  manding. His eyes and the expression of
  his face are calm and reassuring. He said
  "I cannot attempt to explain the mystery of
  hypnotism any more than Edison will try
  to tell you what electricity is," he said.
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090528/1901-02-21/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=hypnotic&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.323,-0.082,1.647,1.647,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Cure Hypnotism
  To cheek the spread of crime through
  hypnotic suggestion a means has been
  discovered by Jules Liegeols. a French
  psychologist, of the well-known "Nancy
  school." who declares that In counter
  suggestion" the moat perfect protection
  Is found.
  Liegeols has carried on experiments for
  many years In company with other scien
  tists at the clinic, where are treated all
  forms of nervous disesse. He discovered
  in the course of his Investigations that
  even the best sort of hypnotic subject
  could not be prevented from taking crim
  inal suggestions by forbidding It while
  the person was In a hypnotic stale.
  In spite of every effort, persons ordin
  arily hy pnotized with the srreat -st ete
  I could not be hypnotised at all while un
  der the flrst Influence, and nothlnsr could
  be done with them until they had keen
  j released front the first hypnotic state by
  the same person who put them Into It.
  This discovery Is of great Importance.
  weak
  Iy af
  and
  fected by the magnetic power of others
  will do whatever they have been told to
  I do while in a hypnotic sleep, even though
  tt was to commit a crime.
  Liegeols refers to several cases of which
  i he knes- personally. On subject, a
  woman, was compelled to poison her hus-
  I band and then commit suicide. Four
  other persons killed themselves and a
  woman was driven into an unhappy mar
  riage by the hypnotic command of wicked
  I Liegeols says that all persons should
  know exactly to what extent they are
  subject to hypnotism, and that If they
  are easily influenced by this dangerous
  power they should without hesitation be
  put In safety by a counter suggestion so
  that nobody can hypnotise them or com
  pel them to obey any hypnotic sarwes-
  der that th effect may not wear ff
  Of course there is danger here that thej
  nerrot s system of the person itTtr- sxf
  this stste of hypnotism might be series
  "rol faineant.
by Hypnotism.
Iy affected by the restraint under 'which
they would be held.
The magnetic nerve force of hypnotism
Is too trem-i.dous to be lightly used even
to prevent the evil oow.r oi the mm
Diseases of the -the
(tower of real
make them easy
scoundrels, and If
strengthened, as L
by hypnotic sugg
Incalculable benefii
(really weakening
e In the afflicted,
is f ail sorts of
l sufferers can be
Is says Is possible.
a disco vet y oi
been made. Crime.
disease, suffering and death in i.
iy the result of defective nerve force and
will power that any light on th treat
ment of nerve weakness is a great bless
ing. Prevention through hypnotic sug
gestion might lead to actual lenrtheniiur
Preven
bly the
rpnotlc suggestion can be put.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1960-07-17/ed-1/?sp=116&amp;q=hypnotic&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.187,-0.069,1.375,1.375,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Hypnosis: the c ure
  that can bo dynamite!
  Hypnosis can be a valuable tool, but, warns one expert, it is full of booby traps.
  These fantastic case bistories sbow you wby By HAROLD ROSEN, m.o. HBaMH
  Chairman, Committee on Hypnosis of The American Medical Association
  No one knows why hypnosis works. It just does.
  It takes only 15 to 30 minutes for most physicians
  to learn how to hypnotize a patient. But it takes
  months of closely supervised instruction for phy
  sicians to learn when not to hypnotize. It is this
  which must be stressed, for hypnotism can be
  exceedingly dangerous.
  One person out of every four is readily hypno
  tizable. He can be hypnotized whether he con
  sciously wishes to be or not. He can be hypnotized
  with his eyes wide open. Even experts may find it
  hard to tell whether or not he is hypnotized. Yet
  under hypnosis criminal, antisocial and even self
  destructive behavior may take place.
  As a medical tool its results are melodramatic.
  With selected patients pain can be partly or com
  pletely abolished. Hypnosis has been used for
  both Caesarean delivery and hysterectomy. It
  has been utilised as a partial anaesthetic during
  a lung operation. It has stop/sed brain-tumor
  headaches. It has put an end to one patient's
  compulsive nail biting; kept another patient
  from grinding his teeth while asleep; and has
  made it possible for a 320-pound woman to lose
  60 pounds within a few months. It has cured
  severe back pain; wryneck; sexual frigidity in
  women and impotence in men, and practically
  every other complaint that human beings can
  develop. But in some cases these cures have
  turned out to be dangerous.
  When hypnotism should no* be used
  No one should be hypnotized unless he first has
  had a competent physical and mental examination.
  If a headache, for instance, is due to a brain
  tumor, whether or not that headache is suggested
  away, g brain operation is still needed. Medical
  treatment is usually directed not to symptom, but
  to cause. Headaches, for example, can be due not
  only to brain tumors but to sinus trouble (and the
  sinusitis needs treatment); to improper glasses (and
  new glasses should be prescribed); to stomach or
  intestinal disease (for which medication or surgery
  is indicated); to worry and tension; to a morning
  after a night before, or to a number of other causes.
  There have been hypnotic symptom cures when
  underlying conditions were not treated, and as a
  result patients have suffered irreparable harm.
  To illustrate:
  A business executive’s wife had a hypnotist
  cure her compulsive nail biting. It worked. She
  broke the habit but instead became a compul
  sive overeater, gained 44) pounds and then asked
  another hypnotist to cure her obesity. Her slim
  figure was restored through hypnotic suggestion
  but she then started drinking more and more.
  Within a few months she was frequently "under the
  8
  I
  Foul Pedersen
  influence.” She now’ wished a hypnotic cure of her
  compulsive martini intake. This was refused. If her
  alcoholism were cured this way, the psychiatrist who
  now saw her believed, she might commit suicide or
  become a drug addict. She should not have been
  hypnotized in the first place.
  2. A taxi driver gnashed his teeth in his sleep.
  His dentist cured this by hypnosis. His wife was
  awakened from a sound sleep two nights later. He
  was trying to strangle her while in a nightmare from
  which he could not at first be aroused. He was re
  hypnotized and again allowed to grind his teeth.
  3. A secretary-stenographer was cured of her
  frigidity by hypnosis. She and her husband were
  both grateful to the hypnotist. But shortly after
  wards she developed "blackout” spells, and had to
  be examined for "heart trouble.” Without con-
  YOUR HEALTH
  AnwnccM Modical Association Aufhon'nd
  sciously realizing it, when she passed men on the
  street she had begun to feel sexually aroused. She
  had developed not heart disease but what the psy
  chiatrist terms a phobic reaction. She had needed
  psychiatric treatment, not hypnosis, for her frigidity.
  4. A school teacher with severe back pain was
  completely cured of this symptom in one hypnotic
  session. But his pain was what the psychiatrist calls
  a depressive equivalent. As long as he could focus
  on the pain, he could keep from feeling depressed.
  With the cure of his symptom, this was no longer
  possible. He committed suicide by jumping out of a
  seventh story window’ a few’ days later.
  Only the cure* are publicized
  With each of these patients there was a melo
  dramatic cure of his symptom. Such cures are
  publicized, but not what happens later on. The
  patient and the public do not even realize that there
  is any connection with subsequent tragedy.
  Hypnosis is a medical technique, but not a medi
  cal specialty. There is no bona fide A.M.A.-recog
  nized hypnosis specialty board although some have
  been deluded into thinking there is.
  Physicians who treat patients on hypnotic levels
  should do so only within the areas of their own
  specialty competence. They should not over-sim
  plify or over-dramatize what they are doing. And
  they should have taken extra work in psychody
  namics (that is, in the motivational bases of hu
  man behavior). This cannot be taught in any of the
  three-day hotel-room courses currently offered phy
  sicians and dentists in most sections of the country.
  Few non-psychiatrists as yet have the necessary
  training to use hypnotism in their practice, for in
  the last analysis it must be considered a psychiatric
  tool. Physicians who hypnotize patients need addi
  tional training, not in hypnosis, but in Basic Psy
  chiatry for the Non-Psychiatrist. This can be taught
  only in medical schools or in teaching hospitals.
  For obvious reasons self-hypnosis can be poten
  tially dangerous. No one should hypnotize himself.
  Neither do we feel that ballplayers or other athletes
  should be hypnotized in an effort to help them to
  win games. This too can be potentially dangerous.
  And the use of hypnosis for entertainment purposes
  is vigorously to be condemned.
  Research projects which would teach us more
  about this fascinating phenomenon are now under
  consideration, and considerable clinical research
  with hypnotic techniques is already in process in a
  number of institutions. As a result of what these
  projects have uncovered it can be stated that irre
  sponsible hypnosis of patients without prior com
  petent physical and mental examination is dan
  gerous. Those who practice it —and those who sub
  mit to it are playing with dynamite. Th» End
  THIS WEEK Magoiln, July 17, 1960</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82000867/1956-09-14/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=illusion&amp;r=-0.555,0.144,1.949,1.019,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89051220/1901-02-14/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=hypnotic&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.015,0.74,0.574,0.6,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>HEW THING IN HYPNGTISM.
  Connter-Sng'Kestloii la Now Offered
  a Preventive of Certain
  Crimen.
  To clieck the spread of crime through
  hypnotic suggestion a means Jias been
  discovered by Jules Liegeois, a French
  psychologist of the wen-known “Nan
  cy school,“who declares that in “coun
  ter suggestion” tne most perfect pro
  tection is found. Liegeois, according
  to report, has carried on experiments
  for many years in company with otli
  er scientists at the clinic, where are
  treated all forms of nervous disease.
  He discovered in the course of his
  investigations that even the best sort
  of a hypnotic subject could be pre
  vented from taking criminal sugges
  tions by forbidding it,while the per
  sdR was in a hypnotic state. In spite
  ofltpvery effort, persons ordinarily
  hypnotized with the greatest ease
  could not be hypnotized at all while
  under the first influence, and nothing
  could be done with them until they
  had been released from the first hyp
  notic state by the same person who
  put them into it.
  This discovery is of great impor
  tance. Many crimes and offenses have
  been traced to hypnotic influences.
  It has been known for years that
  weak and nervous persons who are
  easily affected by the magnetic pow
  er of others will do whatever they
  have been told to do while in a hyp
  notic sleep, even though it was to
  commit a crime. Liegeois refers to
  several corses of which he knew per
  sonally. One subject, a woman, was
  compelled to poison her husband and
  then commit suicide. Four other per
  sons killed themselves and a woman
  was driven into an unhappy marriage
  by the hypnotic command of wicked
  persons. Liegeois says that all per
  sons should know exactly to what ex
  tent they are subject to hypnotises
  and that'if they are easily influenced
  by this dangerous power they should
  without hesitation be put in safety
  by a counter suggestion so that no
  body can hypnotize them or compel
  them to obey any hypnotic sugges
  tions- This treatment should be gone
  through With at leist once or twice a
  year in order that the effect may not
  wear off.
  Of' course there is danger here that
  the nervous system of the person liv
  ing in this state of hypnotism might
  be seriously affected by the restraint
  under which they would be held. The
  magnetic nerve force of hypnotism iis,
  too tremendous to be lightly used,
  even to prevent the evil power of the
  will over weak persons.
  Diseases of the wnl, greatly weak
  ening the power of resistance in the
  afflicted, make them easy victims .of
  all sorts of scoundrels and if these
  sufferers can be strengthened, as
  Liegeois says is possible, by hypnotic
  suggestion, a discovery of incalculable
  benefit has been made. Crime, dis
  ease, suffering and death are so large
  ly »the result of defective nerve force
  and will power that any light on the
  treatment of nerve weakness iB a
  great blessing. Prevention through
  '■’t hypnotic suggestion might lead to
  6 actual lengthening of life and renewal
  °f youth.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90051033/1920-11-05/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=illusion&amp;r=0.064,0.591,0.998,0.522,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-york-city-subway</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1904-10-09/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;q=New+subway+Subway+York&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.235,-0.141,1.47,1.47,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Tlie New York Subway tlie
  Greatest Thing of Its Kind
  Ever Undertaken.
  NO OTHER COMPARES WITH IT
  ?\Vhat lt Is Expectcd to Do in
  Solving tlie Most Difiictilt City
  Transportation Problcm.
  By Bassett Staincs.
  ll?pNEW lollK, Oct. S.?There are grealor
  fiiglnnorliig work's going on In tho world
  to-day, For cxample,, l.lm constructlon
  of the A.isouun dnm and the other lrrlga
  ?'.lldrj w-orks on lho Nilo, whlch, a? thclr
  erentor, iHIr Wllllam Gnt-stln, prottdly
  hiitisir, wlll llve ln tho uso and obser
  vntlon of umiiklnd long nfter ihe an
  cletit inoniiment.i of tho Egyptlans hava
  illsappoared beiieath Ihe Biinds of the
  Nublan deserl. But of Its klnd lho New
  Toik siihwny Is the grentcst thlng yet
  done, and It is o.Iso the greatest en
  ghioerlng entcrprlse of any klnd ln tlie
  1 "1111011 States to-day.
  It wlll be opened Ihroughoul nrnily
  the whole of Its length In the course of
  Ihe preKi-nt ninnth, If slrlkes do not fur?
  ther delay Ihe completlon of tlie work.
  31 Is prnctlf-ally ilnlshed from the resl
  'lgri-at. buslness soctlon Around City Hall,
  foinn work ls stlll going on farther down*
  town townrds the Battery, and nlso nt
  the northern extremlty of Mmiliattiin
  nnd on the Iiiooklyn oxleilslon,
  Will Exceed All Others.
  Time was when the Gothard and Mont
  ?'cnls. tunnelH wero held to bo conslder
  nlile iioles In the earth. They nre merc
  rabblt burrows In comparlson wlth the
  Vitst sliaft whlch has been drlven long
  glttidlnally through the Inland ot Man
  hnttan.
  Or take, Instead, the greatest oxcava
  tlons made by vanlshed civlllznilons.
  ?Great as ure tlie ca%*es of Elephanta and
  llie tomples of ICarnak nnd of Ahooslm
  1'rd on the Nllo bank, the floor space. of
  tlie statlomtof tho New York subway.
  t.-iken togother, ls greater than that of
  any two of them, and when the Jirook
  lyn nnd under-the-r-ver tunnels to be
  made are completed, such ttatlonal areas
  wlll oxcecd in comblncd space nll the
  rock-lu'wn templcs of the anclent world
  Itoown to archaeology."
  Thls Is the statement. of an cngineer
  conhected with the work who happens to
  be glfted wlth a poetlc imaglnatlon. But
  none tho less hc possesses that preclslon
  of dctall whlch properly belongs to hls
  jji-ofcEslon, for he -has computed that
  the carth whlch has been, or wlll be,
  excavatcd In the making of the subway
  iimounts to exactly .1.700.2SS cublc yardsf.
  Tho rock lunneled ainuunts to half a
  sullllon yards; the rock excavalc-d, to
  more than double that quantliy.
  Some Striking Figures.
  Here nre some other figures whlch
  Kpeak for thcmncivea us to the nioighl
  fii'dii of the work:
  Stee! usc-d ln the structurc, 75,000 tons;
  cost iron, a mere trifle ot' 10,000 tons;
  c-oncrete, far over 500.000 cublc yards;
  water proollng, more than 700.000 cublc
  yards; brlck. 20,000 cublc yards; vauit
  ifglit-, over 7,000, each shedding Its
  beams for a radlus of many yards;
  total length of track apprbac-.hes, aiout
  oto.Wi) feet. Theso figures do not ln
  clude the great Brooklyn extcnsi^i by
  way of the Battery tunnel, which ls al
  ready under way: or- other &gt;chemcs for
  ihe exlenslon of the subway sorvlce,
  tlthcrlmooted or ln actlve procoss of ex
  ccutlon.
  The Ptolcmles and tho thlrd Rameses
  bullded monum?nts In their day, but
  they did nothlng so vast as thls.
  "f'n the days of the Caesars," sald u
  New 'York englneer. "Pliny tells us It
  took thlrty thousand men eleven weary
  years to cut a tunnel three and a half
  inlles long. To-day, employlng less than
  twelve thousand men, the New York
  masters of enginecrlng mechanlcs have
  made a tunnel eqiial ln capaclty to one
  of over flfty mllcs ln length llke that
  of Rome, to. say nothlng of some ten
  mllcs of elevated structurc ajid the ex
  cavatlon of extra areas for nndergvound
  s'tatlbns."
  True, there are olher underground roads
  In the. world; but, compared wlth thom,
  thls one ls as "all Lombard-street to a
  Chlna' oran'ge." Tho famous "twoperiny
  tube" In Lopdon, for oxumple, about
  oovers the dlstanco from the Battery to
  Forty-sccond street, where the real
  journey to tho end of the. llno is hnrdly
  bcglnning.
  Its Appalling Dimensions.
  lt has been carefully est'imnted by en
  plneers that lf the subway were a Blngle
  tunnel slx feet hlgh ahd threo feet wide,
  lt would reach from New York to Chl?
  cago. The part exeavated through tho
  tiolld rock would reach from the metropo
  lis to Cleveland. "Three mllllon-cublc
  yards of hole"?that is how one man
  conneoted wlth the work summed lt up.
  Wlille the excavatlons aro going on.
  mllllons of ftet oflumbcr are, belng used
  to prop up the streets so'that tue ordl
  nary trafllc-can go on. All the englneers
  engaged ln the. cnLerprlse are impressed
  bv Its magnltude. and cannot help stop
  ping now and then to Indulge in the
  welroV.st klnd One of them' says that this tlmber ?n
  ployed in the "falso work" would bulld
  no fower than ten thousand two-story
  framo houscs: whlle another asserts that
  the rock talten out by the tunnel would
  niako a respc-ctablc imltatlon ot the
  Great Wall of Chlna, naniely, a struc
  ture threo feet thick, slx feet hlgh, and
  about flve hundred mlles long.
  There -ls no. doubt a.bout lt?the New
  York subway ls the greatest thlng of
  Its kind 'that manklnd has yet done.
  Was a Big Job.
  Tho city of New York declded to have
  tho subway constructed by contract and
  leased to the contractdr for-flfty yearn
  for nn annual rental of rather more than
  the interest payable by tho city on the
  bonds Issued to provide means for tho
  constructlon. It is -hardly credlble, but
  lt ls the fact that ot all the great con
  tracting englneers ln the world only two
  could be found to put ln blds for suoh a
  vast. work. They were .lohu B. McDon
  ald ahd Andrew Onderdonk.
  McDomald askied for $35,000,000 In a
  round sum. That was about the tigure
  e-tlmated by tf&gt;o cnglneer of tho Rapid
  Transit Commisslon, "Wllliam Barclay
  Paraona. Onderdpnk wanted JS9.300.W1
  and certaln concesslons. lloDonald got
  the job. and has carried lt outln a
  manner that has met wlth the' enthu
  slostic approval .of' many dlstingulshed
  englncers who have Inspected hls w,ork.
  "Rapld transit"?the elusivc dream Of
  Xew Yorkers for so many years?wiil
  be something more than a mere phrase
  when tho subway ls runnlng full-blast.
  It Is provlded by contract that local
  tralns must run at an average-speed ot
  not less than fourteen mlles ,an hour.
  Including statlon stops;. whlle. expresses
  must make thlrty mlles an hour. This
  will easlly brlng people from Klngs
  bridgc. at the northern polnt of Mnn
  hnttan. down to the Clty Hali.In ..flfteen
  minutes. Vlsltors from "out of town'-'
  will no longer bc able to say. as; they
  n.lways .do say howadays, "Come to
  our clty and wc'll teach you how to
  travel."
  Close to the Surface.
  IJnllko most underground roads, the
  New York subway runs close to thesur
  fnce. Throughout most 'of-tho length
  fi-om the Battery to Harlem, lt ls only
  four or flve feet below the street levelj
  This makes tho excavation about twenty
  feet ln depth. and the 'platforms of the
  statlons are wlthin slxteen and elghteen
  f.-et of the surface. The steps down from
  the street to' the statlon are thus fewer
  in number, as a rule, than those. up to
  the present elevated statlons. Tho
  problem of ventllatlon?always a- dltH
  cult ono Jn underground Tallroads?ls
  mucli slmptlfled by this nearncss to the
  street, and- the fotil. atmosphere that
  chokes the1 passongers.ln.JJohd'on's "two
  penhy tub*-" need not be.feoreid.
  The largesfstatioii on .the subway ls
  the' Brooklyn -33ridge statlon. whlch. ls,
  really the down town tcrminal. Its net-!
  work of tracks rlvale the avera'ge ter?
  minal In a falrly large city, iund a few
  fest above lt rolls Interminably the
  -hcavlest street tr'allic bf tho-!clty. in?
  cludlng.many ele'ctric tar lines.. Stcal
  beams, flve feet thlck, ho.ld. up tho lri
  mense'weight of thls traflic.
  From thls .fitation. at the .Brooklyn
  Brldge' clear up to Thlrty^thlrd street
  the hub of the linlverse-t'o. many New
  Yorkers?.the subway oonsists of a four
  track llne runnlng ln..- a slrigle tunriel.
  Two tracks aro for expresses. and two
  for' locals. It ls arranged that exprejs
  tralns wlll run.-on expre'ss. tracks only,
  and Iocal tralns on local tracks?an ex
  celleht system; whlch dqes not now pre
  vair on tho elevated rallways of Now
  York city.
  Have Double Tracks.
  The road conslsts of. two doublo-track
  tunn.els above Thirty-fourth streot, whlch
  pass.on elther slde ot the.exlstlng,Park
  avenue street rallway tunnel, but at a
  tower.level. ManHattan,1s, lndeed.be
  comlng honeycombed- ln' all' dlrectlons,
  and the end of the tunn'elllng ls not yet
  ln slght. New .Yorkers- ara llvlng ln
  thlrty storles and; travolllng in three?
  In tunhels, street /cars,' and elevated
  tralns.
  The subway follows Broadwny lo' One
  Hundred and Fourth' street and there
  dlvides into two llnes?ono on the East i
  Slde and the: other on ;the West Slde.
  At' two polnts before reaohlng One Hun?
  dred and Fourth street .tho tunnel has
  to'pass.urider tlie elevated rallway... and
  the task'of holdlng'up the great-welght
  of that gtructurc.;.whlle the tunnelllng
  was golng on r was one. of the most'dirti
  cult that-: the'-. ongineers had to face.
  Downtown. they.dlved under"a Park.row
  newspaper, offlce with such- a small jnnr
  gln to sparo'that th'o erids of the presses
  actually.projected over the tunnel, and
  yet Were abl.e to keep.-runnlng 'wlthout
  aiv hbu'r'a ioss of'-tlme. Another. tlck
  llnh problem 'was to runMinderrieathi the
  vaults of th'o New York postofflcc wlth
  ?Dut disturblng tho work golng on thero.
  But lt' is not only tho underground
  work of whlch tlio siibwoy englneers
  have good' reason to be' proud. From
  Ono Hundred andFoiirth'to One Hun?
  dred and Sfxtee'nth. s't'roets ttiey havo
  carried the llno on a- slngle "solld -con
  crete arch ln an open cut, wlth a span
  of forty-'two'. feet. This Is. technlcally
  regarded as orie of th'o best pleces of
  work of its charactcr everdone. At tho
  end of this out comes the long, deep
  dip known as-Manhattan Valjey; whlch
  ls crossed'on an Imrnense elevated-steel
  vladuct In -order to m'alntain the,' giVdo
  of the llrie. From-Ono'Hundred and
  Flfty-flfth street to Ono Hundrfcd and
  Nlnetletli street tho' tunnel had to be
  bored entirely through solld rock, and
  this part of tho'work alono ls sald to be
  the longest double-track railroad tunnel
  ln tho' Unlted States.
  Thousands at Work,
  On an average the nrmy of subway
  laborers has conslstod of about ten thous?
  and inen durlng the. past four years,. and
  the cost of cxcavatlng .toolc lip about
  ono-thlrd of the entlre contract prlce of
  $iS,Cup the gi-en.t part of the tlme. If it had
  beeii drllled by band, the engfueers doubt
  whether liio work could liavo boen dono
  In a rtuartor of a centnry. Thero has
  beon no such dlfflculty' In any prevtous
  work of the kind. Tho Hiibways of J./011
  doii and Pnrls Were cui. through clay.
  and that of Boston through earth.
  Many unexpected dtttleu+fles were met
  with ln'the cptirso of tlie work. Ouc was
  the Intorferejice, wlth' the dralnagc of
  the clty?ninnlng suddenly up agnlnirt a
  network ot sowers whlch scemed to el-;
  Tectu'ally bl'ock the path. These wer*
  problonis sufflcleiit to turn nn englneer's
  hair gray. In one place, merely;as a
  llttle alde lssuo of their business, tbe
  makers' of the subway hud to change
  tho system of drainago of a largo dis?
  trlct, maklng tho sew.ers dral'n Into tho
  East rlver Inctead of tho Harlem rlvor.
  At another place they had to tear up
  a network of street. car tr.u-ks and relay
  them.
  Tho subway will not bo a dark', mis
  erablo. stuffy place, llke the London
  Underground Railwny. It Is clenh and
  whlto (throu_4hout, nnd wo -Ihorouglily
  llghted by clcctriolty that It Is os .brlght
  as' day everywherc. Tho statlons aro,
  ln many cases, real works of art, and
  all of'them aro con'vonlenl and coiiifort
  able.
  Tho glgnnllo. pow'er-liouso on Flfty
  elghth and Flfty-nlnth streets, whlch
  Plans Already Underway to Ex
  tcnd tllc Underground Transit
  in Manhattan and Brooklyn.
  PROBLEM FOR ENGINEERS
  Many of These Had to bc Dcalt
  With in the Grcat Work?-The
  Tracks and Stations.
  vltall-/.ei tlie thlrd rall, ls a slnictur.
  ot whlch tho tno.kcrs of the subway afo
  Justlv protifk It has a frontoge of 300
  feot' on Blfiventlt avenue and extends
  wstward for nearly *0J feet, whlle tho
  helght Is 12.1 feet. lt Is thifs one of tho
  largcst buildlngs In Now York, und. ono
  of tho Inrgest' power hous^s ln tho
  world. The welght of the steel frame
  work alono ls about. .12.000 tons. Tho to?
  tal genernllng capaclty of the plant l?
  about 130,000 horsc power. The thlrd
  rh.ll system of elcctrlcal propulsion i 1*
  to bo usod throughout.
  Now Practically Complete.
  The su'oway Is now practically eom
  pieted throughout the entlre length of
  Mnnhnttan.. It ls a great wOrk grcatl.v
  done, .but It mu.it not be supposed that
  lt has solved the vexed nuestlon of
  trnnsportatlon ln the motropolls. En?
  glneers and trairte. mann.gers fnmillnr
  wlth enndltlons ln New York ibelleve that
  it wlll bo at best merel.v a temporary and
  partial relief to th* present unbcarablo
  congcstlon of traflle. Thero wlll stlll, lu
  all probablllty, ibe a jvast army ot
  "strnp-hangr.rs"?on the subway Itseir,
  as well as on tho elevated' and sur
  fnce llnes. Other subways wlll havo to
  .be bullt, nnd plans for them arn already
  belng tcntatlvely prepared and consid
  ered.
  The Brooklyn .'oxtenslon iruns under
  the East rtver' to Joralemon street,
  Brooklyn. The Rapid Transit Commls
  sion has already authorlzed an exten
  skm of thls 'Brooklyn road to Prospecu
  Park, and South Brooklyn has also be
  gun to clamor for a branch and ls
  ilkely to get It.
  Tn many parts of Gr-eater New York
  the publlc ls agltatlng for an extcn
  slon of the orijrinal scheme of tho sub?
  way). ;Tho iRrooklyn gxiterinlon i^ider
  the Eant rlver. was not a part of that
  origlnol scheme. wlilch ,\va8 doslgned
  only to rellevo tho congestlon ot traflle
  in Manhattan and the Brohx.
  Other Work Under Ground.
  The rallroad companios, especially ,the
  Pennsylvania, nre also doing much tun
  nelling lu Now York at the present tlmo,
  and aro connccting. thoir systems with
  tho subway. The Rapld Transit Board
  has grautcd to lho Pennsylvania* ...ew;
  Jersey and New York Rallroad Com?
  pany and to tho Pennsylvania, New York
  and Long lsland iRailroad Company.
  jointly, frunchlses for a tunnel system;'
  passing from VVeehawken, N. .T., acrbss
  tho North rlver, rlght iinder Manhattan
  lsland (along Thlrty-second and Thlrty
  tlilrd streets),-aud thenco Into tho Bor
  ough of'Queehs. There ls to be. a doublo
  tunnel under the North rlver. Thls Penn?
  sylvania extenslon will cost anout $?0,
  000,000, and wlll be provldcd wlth what
  has been descrlbed nt. "the most mas
  sive rallroad depot yet concelved of."'
  Four ftill-slzed city blocks have been
  torn down to make way for it, and from
  thls statlon threo tunnels wlll extend
  under tho .East rlver Into ...e Horough
  of Queens. Tho Pennsylvania wil. h??s.
  havo direct communicatlon, .wlthout the
  rilct of flodls, not only with Manhal-.
  tun, but wlth the cxtromlties of Long
  lsland. Tho, big statlon in the center
  of Manhattan ls tb bo connccted wl/.h
  the subway and the Grand Contval sta?
  tlon.
  Needs Not Yet Met.
  They aro dolng great things ln New
  York city to-day to brli'ig Father ICniri&gt;
  erbocker's chlldren down to work wlth?
  out packhig thom llke herrlngs ln /a
  barrel. .But, though tho dollars aro be
  irig pourod out by the mlltlon every
  month for the lmprovement of trahspor
  tation' fa'cllltles, tho provlslon ls stlll
  inadequate. to the need, and ls Ilkely to
  remaln so for. many years to come.
  Jt .ls Imposslblo to glve any exact fig?
  ures on thls polnt of the relation of tha
  provlslon to tho need. Even the dally
  carrylng capaclty of the subway cannot
  bc detormlned by ostlmate. Th? offlclnls
  ln charge of tho enterprlse wlll each
  glve you a dlfforent guess, all of whlch
  aro away up Into the mllllons. Tho
  vaflatlon ln these estlmatos ls explatn
  ed by' the fact that some of them' are
  based on tho seatlng capaclty of tho
  cars whlch wlll be run, whlle others
  aro foimdod on the demonstrated carry?
  lng capaclty of tho elevated aud surraco
  cars, with half their passeogers hanglns
  on to straps in tho "rush hours."
      </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1910-10-05/ed-1/?dl=page&amp;q=subway&amp;sp=5&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.222,-0.072,1.445,1.445,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1913-12-28/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=Subway&amp;r=-0.075,0.122,0.848,0.444,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>he
      Real Estate Market Conditions
      As Seen by Leading Experts
      Finance, Gardens, Poultry, Kennels
      THIRD SECTION
      TWELVE PAGES
      UVL
      NEW YORK, SUNDAY, DECEMBER 28, 1913 Copyright, 1913, fcj the .'nu Printing PuMlsalim Aatoclntu.
      NEW YORK CITY TO GO FORWARD ONCE MORE
      STIMULATED BY GREAT NEW TRANSIT SYSTEM
      Fortunes Greater Than Those Created
      by the Present Subway Expected to
      Result From the Demand for Prop
      erty Along the 324 Miles of New Lines
      11 r imw.win k. mocam..
      halrataa of the Public Scrxlce
      Commlmlon.
      As Tar n 1 can judge the real entitle
      outlook for tho year 101 1 if more promising
      than It hag lieon fur ninny yearn. This
      I say In vtaw of the tremendous trniif It
      improvements which the city of New
      Vork is now making ami Ihe efiect of
      which bhould ho felt during the year 101 1
      I ho construction of sulrwuys and ele
      vated railroads invariably bus liroiiKht
      about, a large increase, in the value of
      ie.il property. esieciully In territory
      previously deficient in transportation
      lacilities The dual system or rapid
      transit wo expect to see in complete
      operation hy January 1. 101" The Inter
      vening three years, therofote, should
      bring about the development of muny
      hitherto neglected sections of tho city,
      as well uh increased values in sections
      iilivudy built up. If we could bee to-day
      tho figures wliich will npvear on Ihe as
      sessment books four years hence I urn
      sure they would startle even the moitt
      optimistic of real estate oierutor's.
      We know what a stimulus Ihe existing
      subway proved to valuations in Man
      hattan and The Bronx, uud we have every
      reason to believe thut history will rewat
      itsslf when tho new lines now under
      construction are completed and placed
      in oieratioii, Tho existing subway all
      told has only ubmit t-evenly-live miles
      of (.ingle track The new com miction
      alone of the dual system will add XM
      miles of single track to the existing lines,
      lint system will embrace the existing
      -ithway, the existing elevated lines in
      Manhattan and The Bronx and the ex
      isting elevated railroads in Brooklyn,
      with a total or '.'Wl miles of single tniek.
      With the 3:l miles of new construction the
      whole system will have a trackage of
      miles, which will lie divided fr operation
      between the luterborottgh Rapid Transit
      lompany and the New Yoik Municipal
      K-iilway CorHjration
      llefote this -Vslein can be placed in
      operation the city of New York and the
      two operating companies wilt have ox
      Iwiided moie than tMn.mw.uni) for con
      struction nnd equipment Even in Ihe
      linancial capital of the riche-t nation or
      ihe world, where transactions involving
      millions are of coiiimou occurrence, this
      i a stupendous total for disbursement
      within four short years, ll i- more than
      one-third of the national debt, and it is
      about tho cost of the Panama Canal
      Suoh an amount of money invested in a
      publin improvement anywhere in the
      world must be followed by great benefit
      t the surrounding prorty
      When the existing subway was built
      its two branches in 'Ihe lirnux, viz., the
      Broadway division und the Iamiox avenue
      division, projected largely into unde
      veloped territory A study of the real
      estate vulues of vacant lots in this terri
      tory for the year louo, four years prior
      to the opening of the subway, shows the
      increase in valuations brnuuht about by
      t lie opera; ion of the subwuy Comparison
      of these values with Ihe assessed valua
      tions in 1907, a little more than two years
      alter the subway begun operation, shows
      Mil astounding increase In the territory
      opened up bv the Broadway brunch
      valuations between Kt.'tli street and
      spuyten Duyvil from iwmto Itw; increased 1
      about MtCluo.tiOo. 'I lie normal increase of i
      he previous seven years was estimated
      .it lhO.000, which, subtrai ted I rum ihe
      IW7 valuations, shows the increase due'
      to the building of the Midway to have
      been about JUV.'ou.imni. 'Ibis was an in-1
      i tease of KM er cent in seven years,,
      l roerty ueveIo'd ly Hie i.enox avenue
      blanch made a similar showing. The
      aggregate increase for the seven yeurs in
      the district lrom tho llurlem Kiver to
      brum I'ark (.vacant lots) woa about
      Jlt.soo.ono, As the normal increase for
      the previous seven years was estimated
      at JlU.WO.OOO, this showed an increase of
      XII.SW.ooo apparently duo to Ihe building
      of the subwuy. 1 nee no reason why a
      similar increase in values should not
      billow the opening up of the dual system
      in undeveloHid or partially developed
      sections.
      1 am glad to be able to state that con
      struction work on the dual system is pro
      gressing rapidly. There is now under con
      t met ion newly $eo,0oo,ouo worth of work
      nail before the new year is two months
      old this total will be increased to more
      than HOO.OUO.OOO. This means that more
      than half of the work which the City of
      Vw York is to puy for in I lie new system
      is already under contract. This work is
      being done by eighteen different con
      tractors who employ all told a daily force
      ol about 7,000 men. For tho year 101S up
      'o tho 15th of December the City of New
      nrk had paid these contractors a total of
      nearly $15,000,000, so that the new work
      i- already putting into circulation more
      i ha u $!,noo,00n of new money every month
      I he average expenditure for 1014 will be
      e en larger, so thut the construction of
      this groat work is already proving on im
      portant factor in tho employment of labor
      and tho promotion of the general pros
      perity. While the dual system will extend rapid
      transit facilities lo many undeveloped
      sections, it will also relieve present con
      '.Mioii in most of Ihe developed portions
      of the city. Even streets in the old city
      ol Vow York, away down in the financial
      district or Manhuttan, will be tunnelled
      to miiliu space for the tracks which will
      i.njiat.i under rivers and over miles of
      and to tho remotest districts of Brooklyn.
      Queens and The Hronx. The system will
      have two grand divisions, one to be oper
      ated by the Jnterboroush lUpid Transit
      i ompany and the other by the New York
      Municipal Hallway Corporal ion. Iu tho
      Interborough territory important uddi
      "e will bo made lu ihe subway and ele
      v.ited lines it now operate. I'ho nib
      y runs lrom 1 lall iish and Atlantic
      venues in Brooklyn under the East Hirer
      to Manhattan and up tho Kut Side of
      .Manhattan Island to Forty-second street
      at the Grand Central Station, where It
      turns westward and runs through Forty
      seoond 'street to Broudway ut 'limes
      Square, and thenco continues up Broad
      way to Ninety-sixth, where it divides into
      two branches, the westorly branch con
      tinuing up Broadway and across the Har
      lam River to Von Cortlandt I'ark or
      342d street and the easterly branch run
      ning out Lenox avenue and other afreets
      to Bronx Park or 180th atreet. The line
      from Brooklyn Bridge to Nluety-slxth
      street la a four track road upon which
      both express and local trains are operated,
      Ihe dual system plans call for the exten
      sion of this subwuy from Forty -second
      street at the Grand Central Stutlon, up
      Lexington avenue, un Mast Side thorough-
      faro, to tho Harlem Hiver as a four truck
      road, Hero the line, will diride Into two I
      branches, ihe westerly branch running
      through Moll, JUver and It tome avenues
      to Wood lawn road and the easterly brunch
      through Southern Boulevard und West
      Chester uvenue lo l'elham Bay I'ark Each
      of these branches will be u three track
      road.
      On the West Side, beginning nl Tunes
      Square, there will be an extension down
      Seventh uvenue, Vuriek slieef. West
      Broudwav and Greenwich stieet to the
      Battery. This also will lie a four track
      lino from Tunes Square to I'.irlc pl.ic".
      where two tracks will divcige to lliooklyu
      und the other two continue on to the
      Battery uud u junction wllji tho existing
      subwuy loop under Battery I'ark. The
      two truoks diverging ut I'ark place will
      oontinue through I'ark place under the
      Post Oflloe building to Beekiuun street,
      through Beekman street to William street
      and down William st reet to Old Slip, where
      they will enter tho tunnol lo bo built
      under the Eust Iliver to Clark street,
      Brooklyn, and a connection with tho ex
      isting subway near Borougii Hull, Brook
      lyn, The subway which now ends at
      Flatbush and Atluntio avenues will also
      be extended out Flatbush avenue to
      Eastern Parkway uud through Eastern
      Parkway to Buffalo uvenue. This will bo
      a four track road. 1'rom Buffalo fcvenUe
      au extension will be built thiough Kasi
      Ninety-eighth street to blvonia avenue
      and out blvonia avenue to New Lots road.
      This extension will be a three track line.
      Front this brief sketch of the routes it
      will be seen that the additions lo t ,ie exist
      ing subway will more than double lt
      pie-ent facilities, By the building of the
      Lexington avenue line north or Forty
      second street and joining It to the e: isting
      subway south or thut street the 'liter
      borough will have for operation n com
      plete, four track lino up and down the
      The Spirit of New York
      East Side from Brooklyn Bridge to the
      Ifnrlem Hiver. Similarly by building the
      Seventh uvenue subway south of Forty
      second street und attaching it to the
      existing subwuy in Broudway north of
      that street the company will have a com
      plete West Side lino from I'ark place to
      Ninety-sixth street. Instead of having
      four trucks bet weed Brooklyn Bridge
      and Ninety-sixth street, us ut present,
      the now system, therefore, will have eight
      truoks between those points, practically
      a duplication of tho existing subwuy.
      In 'I'he Bronx ihe existing brunches of
      the subway have only two trucks each,
      although in places there are three tracks,
      but for operating purposes ihey may be
      considered two truck lines As Ih.i now
      line up Jerome avenue and the new lino
      out .Southern Boulevard und Westchester
      avenue will have three tracks each, It is
      apMirent that these two branches of the
      Lexington uvenue subway alone will nunc
      than double Ihe present subway facilities
      lu The Bronx, lu uddition, however, Ihe
      dual system plans ,i for the extension
      or tiie Lenox avenue branch of the exist
      ing subway from isuih stieet out White
      Plums, raid lo 2 list street, very near the
      northerly city line. As tills ulso will be n
      three track road the three new subway
      hues iu I'he Bronx will provide s total or
      nine trucks, us ugaiiisi I our on i he existing
      subway. The subway facilities ulon
      therelore, iu tliat borough will be more
      than trebled,
      Extensions to the elevuted railroads
      operulod by the luterliorough Company
      will further amplify the facilities of those
      important agencies of transportation. At
      present I hero urn two elevated lines on the
      West Side und two on the East Side of
      Munhuttun The West Side lines ure tho
      Ninth nnd Sixth uvenue systems. Whilo
      both art operated from the Buttery to the
      Harlem Hlvou at l.Vith street, they are
      cm te lines only south of Fifty-third
      street Norlhofthal point Ihereureonly
      three tracks u-cit iu common by trains
      from both lines, The Ninth avenue lino
      now bus a third truck for express service
      Public Service Commission Pushing Work
      on Entire $360,000,000 Improvement
      About Which Centre Hopes of All
      Realty Owners in Greater City
      extending from Christopher stieet on the
      south to IIHtli street on the 1101 th Under
      the dual system plans this third track will
      he extended lo Bulleiy place on the south
      uud lo iMlh street on the north, mi that
      through express service will lie possible
      for the entire length of the present line,
      In addition the Ninth avenue linn will bo
      connected at 15Mb street with tho pio
      poscd elevuted branch of tho Lexington
      avenue subway in .lerome uvenue, which
      will be used jointly by elevated uud bub
      wuy trains. When this is done travellers
      on tho West Side elevated roads will bo
      enabled lo go from downtown .Mauliatlun
      to Woodlawn roud without chanvnof cars.
      Of the East Side elevated roads the
      Second uvenue line ha- no third Hack
      whatever The Third uvenue line has u
      third track from Forty second stieet In,
      (he llurlem Iliver at With street The
      I necessity for switching express trains lo
      the local tracks south of Forty-second is
      one of the grout defects of present opera
      tion. Under the dual system this wilt be
      remedied by the extension of the third
      track from Forty-second street down to
      City Hall There will also be a third track
      added to the Second avenue line for its
      entire length below the Harlem River
      The Third avenue line will be third tracked
      also ucross the Harlem and as far as Pel-
      lia 111 avenue An extension of this lino will
      also be built from the present terminus
      north through Webster uvcnuo to Gun Hill
      1 road and through Ouu Hill road to White
      I'liiin- road, where a junction will be made
      witli the extension of tho Lenox avenue
      I subway to 311st street. This extension,
      like -loroiiip avenue, will lie used jointly by
      subway ami elevated truins. so that when
      I I lie system is completed it will bo possible
      for a piiKfecugor to travel on tho elevated
      line or the subway from tho City Hall lo
      :isi street without chunge or cum and
      lor n single raie.
      i The InterlKiioiigh lines will also l
      extended into the Borough of Queens,
      which up to the present time lids never
      enjoyed rapid transit except such as is
      possible through the Pennsylvania tun-
      i uels. The city is now building for opera
      tion by the Intcrborough, witlt trackage
      rights also to the New York Municipal
      Hallway Coiporation, two important lines
      in Queens borough Both begin ut Queens-
      Isiro Bridge, and ono runs north
      i through Second avenue to Oil mars ave
      ntle, Astoria, and the other through
      Koo-evelt uvenue to Corona und Flush
      i lie. and each will be a three track ele-
      v.i led ruilroud. 'Ihe Ititerborough com
      pany will extend the Second avenue ele
      vated line to uud over the Queensboro
      Bridge lo connect with these new lines,
      over which it will oKrate elevated trains
      I l rom the Second avenue system. The
      city alo is building an extension to the
      I Steinwuy tunnel from its piesent terminus
      in Long Islund City to the Queensboro
      Bridge plaza. This extension also will
      join the new Queens lines so that tho ln
      iterborough will be enabled to run trains
      from the .Steinway tunnel to Astoria
      nnd to Flushing. The Steinwuy tunnel
      al-o will be extended lai the .Manhattan
      ide through Forty-second street to
      Times Sqiiaie and u junction with the
      existing subway, so that eventually it will
      be possible for train- starling ut un
      Cortlandt Park to pass through the Stein
      way tunnel and over tne new lines lo
      A-toiia and Flushing
      Tne mere statement of Ihe extent to
      which the luterliorough lines are to be
      eviandeil i-. siifticienl lo convince any
      me that the dual system will work n
      i evolution in transportation facilities iu
      i lie field now covered by that system.
      No one can now predict the full ex
      lent of the benefits which will follow.
      Il will icm.iin for uctual operation to
      -bow the degree of benefit which this
      i great improvement will confer.
      In the Brooklyn field no less of a traffic
      revolution will follow the completion of
      the dual system This territory is now
      served mainly Wy the lines of the Brooklyn
      liupid Tiaiisil Coinpanv This company,
      under the name of the New York Municipal
      Itiiilw iv Coiporation, has madeii contract
      with the City of New ,urk to connect it
      existing lines witli new lines lo ls buill by
      the city and to operate them as one sys
      tem At present the Brooklyn elevated
      railroads cover in.", miles of single track.
      I'lnler Ihe dual system the enmpuny will
      have for otorut inn HI Millie of single track.
      The lliooklyu elevated roads now enter
      Williamsburg Budge Cnder the new sys
      tem they will Imve additional entrances
      iliioiub two new tunnel.', under the East
      Kiver nnd ov er the Manhattan Bridge A I
      pieent(.ill such lines tei initiate at Ihe
      two bridge- named, so thai passengers
      mii-t pay another faro to leach uny other
      pal I of Manhattan The dual system will
      provide the lliooklyu company with two
      tiewsudwuys in Manhattan through which
      the entile Unfile ut the Brooklyn elevated
      railioads can ls dirliibuted without the
      payment of an additional tare, One of
      Ihse subways i- the Centre street loop
      and Ihe oilier the Broadway subway, Tho
      Centre street loop is ulready completed
      from the Manhattun end or the Brooklyn
      Biidge north through Centre street to
      IMiincey stieet extension, uud through
      heluncey street extension to the Williams
      burg Undue, with a spur at Canal street
      connecting with the .Mitnliuttuii Bridge,
      I Ins .pur is now lieing connected with t tie
      Brooklyn Bridge and will soon bccxlondrd
      down Nassau slieei to Broad street, and
      a conneclion with the proposed tunnel
      under the East Hiver from Whitehall
      street, Manhuttan, lo Montague street,
      Brooklyn, and u connection with the
      l'ouilli avenue subway in Brooklyn.
      The Broudwuy subway will also lie con
      nected with this tunnel lino und will
      extend up Trinity plate uud Church
      Nlieel lo Veey street, through Vesey
      Mi eel to Bioiidvvay and up Broadway
      to Forty-second stieet ut Times Square
      'and thence up Seventh uvenue to Flfty
      iiiiilh street From Cunui street lo
      I'oi l y. second sheet Ihis subway will be
      a four track road. At Fifty-ninth street
      two tracks will terminate and two tracks
      .will continue eastward through Fifty-
      ninth and Sixtieth streets to nna over tne
      Queensboro Bridge and n connection with
      the new rnpid transit line! in Queens
      llOI'OIIR.I.
      The Centre stieet loop subway is the
      11 1 si part of the dual system to be placed
      iu operation. Since August 4 lust the
      Brooklyn company bus been opcratiiw
      all its elevated trains coining tmiu ui-s
      Williutiiburg Bridge through this sub
      way For this purpose only the two
      westerly tracks In the loop subway I
      being used, und the other two tracks will
      remain idle uiililhe conneclion with the
      Hiool.l.-n Undue is completed 'I he pre,
      cut operation, however, has greatly re
      lieved the ciusli on the Brooklyn Biidge,
      L'OllllMUtll uu
      Hctvnd
      ray:.
      1</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1911-05-25/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=Subway&amp;r=0.049%2C0.734%2C0.708%2C0.37%2C0&amp;st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The Interboroug'h Offer Completes the City-Owned Subway. The Brooklyn Rapid Transit
  Company Asks the City to Build Subways as Terminals for Its Elevated Railroads.
  The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company Proposes More Elevated
  Roads for Brooklyn. The Interborough Builds Subways There.
  WHAT THE INTERBOROUGH PLAN DOES FOR BROOKL YN
  y TERBOROUGH.
  20
  EXISTING SUBWAYS
  PROPOSED SU8WAYS,IM MEDIATE C Off STRUCT ON,
  INTERBOROUGH AND CITY MONEY.
  ocxxxxxxEUWRE EXTENSIONS TO SUBWAY SYSTEM.
  wmmm SUBWAYS under constnuctoy.
  ALL TO BE OPERATED BY iTERBOROUGH
  FOR A SINGLE S CEiT
  If V--. X A
  m m (CV 4 11 S J x U
  The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company Offers to Reduce Fares to Manhattan at the City's
  Expense, But Refuses to Reduce Fares to Coney Island at that Company's Expense.
  This map shows what the Interborough Company has offered to
  the City as a comprehensive subway plan. The lines shown in heay
  broken lines can be immediately constructed and placed in opera
  tion for a single five-cent subway fare in connection with the present
  subway, the bridge Loop, and the Fourth Avenue Subway. The total
  construction cost will be $198,788,650, of which the City pays
  $110,320,150 for construction and the Interborough $88,478,500. The
  Interborough supplies all of the equipment, which makes a total
  contribution by the Interborough of $140, 824, SCO. The City's expen
  diture under this plan is $58,000,000, leas than called for by the
  Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan.
  The Interborough's plan establishes a universal five-cent subway
  fare from Fort Hamilton, Coney Island. Shetpihead Bay, East New
  York. Ridgewood, Wocdside, Coona, Astoria and all parts of the
  Bronx. The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan establishes a
  ten-cent fare within the Greater City ard for a great many of the
  people in Queens, Manhattan and the Bronx a fii teen-cent fare to
  Coney Island. The Brooklyn Company claims that it will make a
  great saving to Brooklyn people by extending its lines into Manhat
  tan, thus avoiding a double fare.
  The Interborough Company, by going to Brooklyn for the
  people with its numerous lines with a single fare, save more then
  the Brooklyn Company claims to save, because on the Interborough
  there will be a single fare to reach from every point in Brooklyn to
  every point in Greater New York.
  If the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company is so interested in re
  ducing the expenditures of the fare-payer, why do they insist in
  A their proposition that for a short ride from Brooklyn to Coney
  '""'md the lare must be ten cents
  The Interborough has adopted the principle that a single five
  cent fare paid on the subway system shall carry a person from one
  end to the other of the Greater City of New York. On the other
  hand, the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan proposes to
  perpetuate a two-and three-fare system.
  The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's proposal is that it will
  spend less than $21,000,000 for construction in improving its eleva
  ted lines in Brooklyn and placing third tracks thereon if the Greater
  City of New York will pay about $168,000,000 of the taxpayers' money
  for subway construction and connect it with the out-of-date eleva
  ted lines in Brooklyn, provided further that all the receipts on the
  Subways built by the taxpayers' money shall be used by the Brooklyn
  Rapid Transit Company in establishing for all time a dividend on
  many of the unprofitable elevated lines in Boooklyn.
  The Interborough's plan proposes to extend the present City
  Subway so that all the people in Brooklyn, including the outlying
  districts, will be given a five-cent subway fare from one end to the
  other ofthe Greater City of New York. If the Interborough's plan is
  adopted by the City it will save $58,000,000 of the taxpayers' money
  that the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan calls for, and this
  $58,0C0,000, will construct the lines shown on this map to Rich
  mend, to Jamaica and to Flushing, and if these lines are construc
  ted there would still be $30,000,000 of the taxpayers' money saved by
  accepting the Interborough's plan.
  The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Co. advertises that it will take only
  $73,500,000 of City money to construct the rapid transit lines which
  it has been showing in heavy black lines on its advertising maps.
  The misleading character of this talk about cost can be seen read
  ily by lookinar at its offer of April 25th. in which it was stated that
  the City's requirement of new capital would be $73,500,000 for the
  lines then proposed.
  Since that date and on May 1st the Brooklyn Company added
  to its so-called original lines:
  1. The Jerome Avenue extension to Jerome Park Reservoir.
  2. The Southern Boulevard extension to the Bronx River.
  3. Lines to Astoria and Corona.
  4. The Nostrand Avenue extension.
  5. The Livonia Avenue extension; and
  6. The Fourteenth Street Tunnel to East New York.
  But not a word has been said about the additional cost of these
  lines. Every day since they were added the Brooklyn Company has
  stuck to its original figure of $73,500,000. More than this, and still
  further showing the deceptiveness of their advertisements, the
  Brooklyn Company are placing upon their advertising maps in black
  lines the following lines which they have riot even yet agreed to put
  in their offer:
  a i The Southern Boulevard line extending as far as Pelham
  Bay Park.
  (b) The Utica Avenue extension; and
  (c) The Tunnel to Staten Island.
  And still they seek to lead the public to believe that all the black
  lines will cost the city only $73,500,000.
  Now the facts are that the cost to the city of the lines first
  mentioned by them will be $118,000,000.
  The cost to the city, with their additions of May 1st, will run
  up to $168,000,000.
  The grand total cost to the city of their layout as advertised
  will run up to $188,500,000.
  rMfcall.
  Uuut. It</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-09-29/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=NEW+New+SUBWAY+subway+York&amp;r=-1.04,-0.021,3.08,1.61,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>SERIOUS SMASH-UP IN NEW
  YORK SUBWAY TUNNEL
  New York, Sept 29. One of the
  most serious accidents in the his
  tory of the New York subway sys
  tem occurred early today when two
  trains collided underneath 142d st,
  the Bronx.
  Three men received injuries which
  are expected to prove fatal. The
  trains took fire and, in fighting the
  flames, 20 firemen were overcome by
  the dense smoke which choked the
  tunnel. 100 passengers on a train
  following those which collided were
  thrown into a panic and fought the
  guards until the doors were opened.
  They then walked seven blocks back
  through the smoke-filled tunnel.
  The injured men are all subway
  employes They were removed to the
  Fordham Hospital There it was stat
  ed that they had a small chance for
  recovery.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-25/ed-1/?sp=31&amp;q=New+York+Subway&amp;r=-1.048,-0.152,3.096,1.618,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>NEW YORK SUBWAY CAVE-IK
      J i i irTMn Ssammnim 1 1 BJ
      i.imuil nil I JJ f
      frrngaww 7y
      This shows the cave-in of the Seventh ave. subway at New York, in
      which seven people were killed arid more than 100 injured. The cave-in1
      cfollowed the premature explosion of a large blast of dynamite. Rescuers,
      are shown in -the bed of -the. subway searching for victims. The construc
      tion work gave way for a block, dropping three crowded care into chasm.
      -o o-</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1922-08-28/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Subway&amp;r=-0.128,0.043,1.082,0.566,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>v ROUTES PROPOSED
  FOR NEW SUBWAYS
  THE EVENING WORLD, MONDAY, AUGUST 28, 192 2.
  UNDER HYLAN PLAN
  Full List of Lines With
  Extensions Announced in
  1 $600,000,000 Scheme.
  Tho following arc tho routes of tho
  gV. ew subways proposed In Mayor Hy-
  lan's plan to expend $600,000,000 In
  y! new construction:
  tS Manhattan and Bronx 1. Construct
  two-track extension from COth Street
  3 nd Seventh Avenue across Central
  Pork to 63d Street nnd Central i'ark
  West: north on Central Park West
  to 72(1 Street; west on 72d Street to
  Amsterdam Avenue; four tracks north
  on Amsterdam Avenue to 162d Street;
  throo tracks on St. Nicholas Avenue
  to 168th Street: on Uroadway to
  Dyckman Street.
  352" Extensions:
  Two tracks on Amsterdam Avenue
  rg,rrom 162d to 190th Streets.
  0 Two tracks from Dyckman Street
  Vv and Broadway north on Scnnian Ave-
  nuo, under Harlem River, through
  Rlverdalo Avenuo to city lino at
  Tonkcrs.
  to MontaKUo Street, Brooklyn, as 1
  roncltidlng part of Contto Strcot loop,
  as provided In dnnl contracts.
  i. Construct four track subway
  from llailem tllver south on Flint
  Avrmio to Tenth Street: two tracks
  West on Tenth Street to Second
  Avonuo, through Htuyvcsnnt Streot
  to Third Avenue, to Bowery; south
  on Uowory and Park How to connect
  with new Dover Street tunnel to Lu
  fayetto Avenuo line. Brooklyn. Two
  tracks east on Tenth Street to Ave
  nue C. throuch Avenue C, Pitt Street
  and East Broadway to Park How, to
  a loop east of Municipal Building.
  EXTENSIONS UNDER THE
  HARLEM RIVER.
  Extension tour tracks north on
  Flint Avenuo under Harlem nivcr,
  thro'igh Alexander Avenuo to Third
  Avenuo to 101st Street, at which
  point three trackB on Third Avenue
  to Boston Road nt 163d, on Boston
  Road to 174th Stroet, on Southern
  Boulevard to Pcllmin Parkway. Three
  trucks from 161st Street und Third
  Avenue to Wohstor Avenue, on Web
  ster Avenue to l'ordham Road, con
  necting with recupturablo "It" on
  Webster Avenue, running to a con
  nectlon with Whtto Plains Road lino
  at Gun III11 Road.
  B. Construct two-track Runway
  from Loxincton Avenuo and 42d
  Street south th rough Lexington Avo
  nuo and Irving Place to Hth Street,
  cast to Third Avenue: south to Stuy
  vesant Street Into new First Avenue
  subway.
  6. Construct two track subway
  through 12Bth Street from Hudson
  River (Fort Leo Ferry) to connect
  with new bridge from Bronx and Har
  lem to Astoria. (This lino permits
  Interchange of passengers from all
  city owned and operated north and
  south subway lines, as well as opera
  tion via Now Trl-Rorough Brldgo to
  Queens and Brooklyn.)
  7. Extend Queensboro subway from
  Wn urvn 1in Mil confirm WCst Of
  Broadway, construct enclosed escala- f Street and Eighth Avenuo to
  tors on station streets from Broad-
  way to Fort Washington Avonue.)
  J! 2. Construct four-track subway
  from Seventy-second Street and Am
  4 f
  11
  aterdam Avenuo south on Amsterdam
  'T 1 ..AMiin iwinnnKtltll.
  two tracks with Fourteenth Street
  line. Other two trncks continuing
  I'l couth on Hudson and Washington
  Btreets to a loop at tho Battery and
  i tunnel to Atlantic Avenue, Brooklyn,
  J! oonncctlne with Red Hook lino at
  Hicks Street. (Concourse ut Cham-
  ji lxrs Street to connect with present
  west side subway station.)
  Jj Construct at Seventy-second Street,
  fj Broadway and Amsterdam Avenuo
  i an underground concourse to enable
  j; transfer of passengers from tho pres-
  ent west sldo subway to tho New
  Jl' Amsterdam Avenuo line.
  if S. Construct two track Nassau-
  J: Broad Street subway from City Hall
  Jf ,to Old Slip, connecting with tunnel
  Tenth Avonue,
  8. Extend 14th Street lino from
  Sixth to Tenth Avenues, to connect
  with Tenth Avcnuo-Amstcrdam Ave
  nuo line.
  Extend west side subway from
  Broadway and 242d Street to Vun
  Cortlandt Station of Putnam Division
  (quarter mile).
  10. (Brooklyn.) Construct two-track
  subway from Hunterspolnt Avenue
  station of tho Queensboro lino to
  Jackson Avenue, Borden Avenue,
  Front Street, under Newtown Creek
  through private property to Manhat
  tan Avenue. Four-track subway
  from this point (two-track loop)
  through Manhattan Avenue to Roeb-
  llng Street, to Taylor Street, to
  Bedford Avenue, to Lafayette Ave
  nue. From this point two tracks con
  tinue to Bedford Avenue, to Fulton
  Street, through Brovoort Placo ana
  Franklin Avenue (with transfer con
  nection at Franklin Avenuo and East
  ern Parkway), to Intersection of
  Franklin and Flatbush Avenues, con
  necting with N'o. 13; other two tracks
  run west from Hf-dford Avenuo mm
  four-track Lafayette Avenuo 8ubwo
  (No. 11).
  FOUR -TRACK SUBWAY FOR
  BROOKLYN.
  U. Construct four-track subway
  from Wai.hmgton Street and Myrtlo
  Avenue, tunning through Myrtlo Ave
  nue to and thiough Fort Crecno Purk,
  und Fort Grerno Place to Lafayette
  Avenue, to Bcdfard Avenuo; contin
  uing thrco tracks on Lafayette Ave
  nuo to Broadway, (two or mcso lour
  tracks from Bedford and Lafayette
  Avenues to Myrtle A.vcnuo nnd Wash
  ington Struct aro Included In No. 10).
  Two tracks from Myrtle Avenuo and
  Washington Street to Tlllary Street;
  under Brooklyn Brldgo property to
  Fulton Street, tunnel to Dover Street,
  Manhattan: under Brooklyn Bridge
  property to Park Row, connecting
  with First Avenuo (Manhattan) sub
  way, (Transfer connection at Wash
  Ington and Concord Streets to Hicks
  Street subway ond nt Washington
  Street nnd Myrtlo Avenuo to Court
  Street and Boruugh Hall stations of
  "recaptured" subways; and at Myrtlo
  Avenue nnd FlatbUBh Avenuo exten
  sion to Myrtle Avenuo station of "re
  captured" subway.)
  Extension: Thrco tracks from
  Broadway and Lafayette Avenue
  through Broadway to Jamaica Avenue
  to a connection with "recapturnblo"
  "It" cast of Crescent Street, which
  runs to lCSth Street In Jamaica.
  12. Construct three-track subway
  through Utlca Avenuo from Eastern
  Parkway subway to Flatlands Avenue.
  (Spur tracks from Eastern Parkway
  already laid.)
  Extension: Through Utlca Avenuo
  to Flatbush Avenue, crossing ut Jum-
  alca Bay.
  13. Construct four-track extension
  from Flatbush nnd Franklin Avenues
  through Flatbush Avenue to Internee
  (Ion of Nostrand venue, through
  Nostrand Avenuo to Emmons Avenuo
  (Shccpshcnd Bay) Into Surf Avenue.
  Coney Island. Two of these four
  tracks will bo an extension from the
  Malbone Street tunnel. Tho other two
  tracks arc described In No, 10, tho
  crosstown subway.
  14. Extend Nostrand Avenuo sub
  way from Nostrand and Flatbush Ave
  nuos throiiRh Flatbush Avenuo to
  Jamaica Buy, (Concourso station at
  Flutbuhh und Nostrund Avenues with
  No. 13.)
  IB. Extond 14th Street-Eastern Dis
  trict subway from Iiushwlck and
  Metropolitan Avenues through Metro
  politan Avenuo to a connection with
  tho Jamaica Avonuo "It."
  16. Construct thrce-traclc eubwny
  from tho Prospect Avenue Htutlon of
  Fourth Avcmin (Brooklyn) cubway
  through Prospect Avenuo under
  Gowanus Cunul to Lorrnlno Street,
  Hicks Street, to Atlantic Avenue, "y
  tunnel to connect with Tenth Avo
  nuo (Manhattan) subway at Buttery,
  with loop through State Street, Clin
  ton, Plneupple und Hicks Streets.
  17. Construct three-track Mibwuy
  fiom 90th Street nnd Tenth Avenuo,
  north on Tenth Avenue to Fort Ham
  ilton 1'urkwuy, through Fort Humil
  mi Parkway to Prospect Avenue
  hrough Prospect Avenuo to connect
  with Hicks Street line. (The "recap
  tured" Culvor lino to operate through
  Ins Hue to .Manhattan instead of pres
  ent operation.)
  EXTENSION OF THE FOURTH
  AVENUE LINE.
  18. Extend Fourth Avenue subway
  from 86th Streot to 90th Street.
  19. Construct two-track subway
  from Fourth Avenuo nnd 80th Street
  cast to connect with new Tenth Avo
  nue subway and with New Utrecht
  Avenue line to Coney Island.
  20 Construct two-track BUbwav
  from Fourth Avenuo nt C7th Street
  to connect with tunnel to Staten
  Islnml.
  21. Extend Livonia Avenue lino
  through New Lots Avenuo to Blake
  Avenue, through 76th Street to "n--nipturablu"
  extension of Libert
  Avenuo lino running to Leffcrts Au--
  nue, Itlciimond Hill.
  !2, Extend present Corona line
  from Alburtls Avenue to Main Street,
  Flushing, crossing Flushing Creek by
  bridge Into subway, the brldgo also to
  accommodate vehicular and pedes
  trian traffic.
  Extension; Two-track subway from
  Main Street to Baysldo by way of
  Jamaica Avenue, Sanford Avenue
  and Broadway to Bell Avenue.
  Extension: Two tracks to College
  Point from Main Street, Flushing,
  through Farrlngton Street, Myrtle
  Avenuo to Collego Point causeway;
  Thirteenth Street to East River, tun
  nel to Clason Point Road nnd sub
  way to 177th Street, Intersecting tho
  Bronx Park subway at west f arms
  and to tho new subway on Boston
  Road and Southern Boulevard.
  :3. Construct subway extension
  from Corona lino through Queens
  Boulevard, from Gosman and ureen
  polnt Avenues to Jamaica Avenue.
  24. Extend Astoria lino inrougn As
  toria Avenue to Steinway.
  Extension: Through Junction and
  Woodhavcn Avenues to Liberty Ave
  nue, meeting the new boulevard
  across Jamaica Bay.
  Tri-Borough Bridge Route 25. Construct brldgo from St. Ann's Ave
  nue, Bronx, and 125th Street, Har
  lem, over Randall's nnd Ward's Islands
  to Potter Avenue, Astoria; Astoria
  trains to operate over brldgo Into sub
  way on St. Ann's Avenue, Dionx, to
  lfilst Street and Third Avenue and
  Into subway on 125th Streot to Fort
  Leo Kerry, Manhattan.
  (This bridge will provide n through
  route from the Bronx, Harlem and
  Washington Heights to vurlous parts
  of Queens and Brooklyn without
  passing through Manhattan.)</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1922-08-28/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.259,0.79,0.453,0.473,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>600 Million
  Cost of Hylan
  Subway Plan
  Mayor's Project Copies
  Many Features of the
  Transit Commission
  Involving 218 Millions
  126 Miles of New
  Lines; Six Tunnels
  Author Says Strikes Will
  Be Unknown; Busses to
  Replace Surf ace Coaches
  Mayor Hylan's long-deferred plan
  for rapid transit was made public at
  the City Hall yesterday in the ab?
  sence of the executive, who is in Sar?
  atoga on a vacation.
  The Mayor seems to ignore the law
  which places responsibility for initiat?
  ing new subway plans with the Transit
  Commission. It was the failure of the
  Hylan administration to lay down any
  feasible plan for new subways that
  prompted the Legislature to create the
  Transit Commission.
  The Mayor's plan provides new tran?
  sit lines costing, with equipment,
  $600,000,000.
  Copying many of the salient routes
  and features of the Transit Commis?
  sion's comprehensive plan, which is to
  cost $218,000,000, the Mayor proposes to
  build 126 miles of new subways, over
  35 new routes, extensions and tunnels.
  Six New Tunnels
  The plan provides for unified city
  operation, as proposed by the Transit
  Commission, and a universal five-cent
  fare.
  It provides for immediate transit re?
  lief in all boroughs by the use of city
  owned busses.
  It provides six new tunnels besides
  the one to Staten Island.
  It provides for the "recapture" of
  ninety-seven miles of existing subways
  in 1625 and 1926 and the termination
  of the city's contracts with the Inter
  borough and the B. R. T.
  It provides direct routes from Wash?
  ington Heights, Hariem and the Bronx
  to Queens, Brooklyn and Staten Island
  without passing through Manhattan
  Island.
  The Mayor said that the city did
  not intend to invest another dollar in
  the acquisition of antiquated elevated
  and surface lines controlled^ by pri?
  vate operators.
  In various parts of his project the
  Mayor lapses into attacks on Cfoair**
  man McAneny of the Transit Commis?
  sion and Governor Miller, and he finds
  in the Transit Commission's compre?
  hensive transit plan for New York
  only a malevolent project to rehabili?
  tate the "interests."
  Cost $600,000,000
  The formal statement setting forth
  the Mayor's plan says that he will pre?
  sent it to the Board of Estimate on
  September 6, and he ventures the sug?
  gestion that it will spread peace and
  plenty throughout the city, provide
  employment and "bring New York to
  the pinnacle of social, civic and com?
  mercial greatness."
  The Mayor calls for an amendment
  to the transit law, so that the Board
  of Estimate may have undivided re?
  sponsibility.
  "The city intends," said the Mayor,
  "to spend about $600,000,000 during
  the next fifteen years to construct and
  equip these new rapid transit lines.
  It intends to begin its first construc?
  tion immediately?as soon as the nec?
  essary detailed plans can be prepared
  by the engineers?and it intends to
  have new subway lines in operation
  before the expiration of the term of
  the present elected city officials. The
  construction of these new rapid transit
  lines will go on at the same time in all
  boroughs.
  No Partnerships
  "These new rapid transit lines will
  be constructed by the city itself. The
  city will have no partners in this gi?
  gantic enteirprise, and it will enter?
  tain no partnership in %the operation
  of any of these lines when finished.
  It will be exclusively a city under?
  taking. The city will become the sol?
  operator of all thepe new lines and of
  existing 'subway lines which the city
  owns, and which are now .leased, to
  private operators.
  "The city intends to discontinue
  its present partnership arrangements
  with the Interborough and the Brook?
  lyn 'Rapid Transit companies as soon
  as it can legally do sp. It intends to
  take over the city-owned subway lines
  operated by these private companies
  and operate them itself in conjunc?
  tion with the new subways. This will
  be the most extensive venture in city
  operation, as well aa city ownership
  of local transportation lines, anywhere
  on earth.
  City-Owned Mileage
  "At the present time the city owns
  about 111 route miles of rapid transit
  lines, -including certain elevated ex?
  tensions which are operated by the
  j private companies. When the new
  rapid transit lines are finished and in
  operation the city will have a total of
  ?237 route miles, virtually all of" it op?
  erated by the city itself on the basis
  of a five-cent fare for a continuous
  I ride from one end of the greater city</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1911-05-25/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=Subway&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.139,-0.064,1.278,1.278,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The Interboroug'h Offer Completes the City-Owned Subway. The Brooklyn Rapid Transit
      Company Asks the City to Build Subways as Terminals for Its Elevated Railroads.
      The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company Proposes More Elevated
      Roads for Brooklyn. The Interborough Builds Subways There.
      WHAT THE INTERBOROUGH PLAN DOES FOR BROOKL YN
      y TERBOROUGH.
      20
      EXISTING SUBWAYS
      PROPOSED SU8WAYS,IM MEDIATE C Off STRUCT ON,
      INTERBOROUGH AND CITY MONEY.
      ocxxxxxxEUWRE EXTENSIONS TO SUBWAY SYSTEM.
      wmmm SUBWAYS under constnuctoy.
      ALL TO BE OPERATED BY iTERBOROUGH
      FOR A SINGLE S CEiT
      If V--. X A
      m m (CV 4 11 S J x U
      The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company Offers to Reduce Fares to Manhattan at the City's
      Expense, But Refuses to Reduce Fares to Coney Island at that Company's Expense.
      This map shows what the Interborough Company has offered to
      the City as a comprehensive subway plan. The lines shown in heay
      broken lines can be immediately constructed and placed in opera
      tion for a single five-cent subway fare in connection with the present
      subway, the bridge Loop, and the Fourth Avenue Subway. The total
      construction cost will be $198,788,650, of which the City pays
      $110,320,150 for construction and the Interborough $88,478,500. The
      Interborough supplies all of the equipment, which makes a total
      contribution by the Interborough of $140, 824, SCO. The City's expen
      diture under this plan is $58,000,000, leas than called for by the
      Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan.
      The Interborough's plan establishes a universal five-cent subway
      fare from Fort Hamilton, Coney Island. Shetpihead Bay, East New
      York. Ridgewood, Wocdside, Coona, Astoria and all parts of the
      Bronx. The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan establishes a
      ten-cent fare within the Greater City ard for a great many of the
      people in Queens, Manhattan and the Bronx a fii teen-cent fare to
      Coney Island. The Brooklyn Company claims that it will make a
      great saving to Brooklyn people by extending its lines into Manhat
      tan, thus avoiding a double fare.
      The Interborough Company, by going to Brooklyn for the
      people with its numerous lines with a single fare, save more then
      the Brooklyn Company claims to save, because on the Interborough
      there will be a single fare to reach from every point in Brooklyn to
      every point in Greater New York.
      If the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company is so interested in re
      ducing the expenditures of the fare-payer, why do they insist in
      A their proposition that for a short ride from Brooklyn to Coney
      '""'md the lare must be ten cents
      The Interborough has adopted the principle that a single five
      cent fare paid on the subway system shall carry a person from one
      end to the other of the Greater City of New York. On the other
      hand, the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan proposes to
      perpetuate a two-and three-fare system.
      The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's proposal is that it will
      spend less than $21,000,000 for construction in improving its eleva
      ted lines in Brooklyn and placing third tracks thereon if the Greater
      City of New York will pay about $168,000,000 of the taxpayers' money
      for subway construction and connect it with the out-of-date eleva
      ted lines in Brooklyn, provided further that all the receipts on the
      Subways built by the taxpayers' money shall be used by the Brooklyn
      Rapid Transit Company in establishing for all time a dividend on
      many of the unprofitable elevated lines in Boooklyn.
      The Interborough's plan proposes to extend the present City
      Subway so that all the people in Brooklyn, including the outlying
      districts, will be given a five-cent subway fare from one end to the
      other ofthe Greater City of New York. If the Interborough's plan is
      adopted by the City it will save $58,000,000 of the taxpayers' money
      that the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Company's plan calls for, and this
      $58,0C0,000, will construct the lines shown on this map to Rich
      mend, to Jamaica and to Flushing, and if these lines are construc
      ted there would still be $30,000,000 of the taxpayers' money saved by
      accepting the Interborough's plan.
      The Brooklyn Rapid Transit Co. advertises that it will take only
      $73,500,000 of City money to construct the rapid transit lines which
      it has been showing in heavy black lines on its advertising maps.
      The misleading character of this talk about cost can be seen read
      ily by lookinar at its offer of April 25th. in which it was stated that
      the City's requirement of new capital would be $73,500,000 for the
      lines then proposed.
      Since that date and on May 1st the Brooklyn Company added
      to its so-called original lines:
      1. The Jerome Avenue extension to Jerome Park Reservoir.
      2. The Southern Boulevard extension to the Bronx River.
      3. Lines to Astoria and Corona.
      4. The Nostrand Avenue extension.
      5. The Livonia Avenue extension; and
      6. The Fourteenth Street Tunnel to East New York.
      But not a word has been said about the additional cost of these
      lines. Every day since they were added the Brooklyn Company has
      stuck to its original figure of $73,500,000. More than this, and still
      further showing the deceptiveness of their advertisements, the
      Brooklyn Company are placing upon their advertising maps in black
      lines the following lines which they have riot even yet agreed to put
      in their offer:
      a i The Southern Boulevard line extending as far as Pelham
      Bay Park.
      (b) The Utica Avenue extension; and
      (c) The Tunnel to Staten Island.
      And still they seek to lead the public to believe that all the black
      lines will cost the city only $73,500,000.
      Now the facts are that the cost to the city of the lines first
      mentioned by them will be $118,000,000.
      The cost to the city, with their additions of May 1st, will run
      up to $168,000,000.
      The grand total cost to the city of their layout as advertised
      will run up to $188,500,000.
      rMfcall.
      Uuut. It</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-11-13/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=Subway&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.388,0.154,1.681,0.879,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BACILLI INVADE THE SUBWAY.
  DAKKXESS HIGHLY TAVOMABLB TO THEIR GROWTH
  THERE, ALL EXPERTS AGREE.
  Whether Passengers Get Enough Oxygen in Their Air Is a Disputed
  Point Which the City Is Xow Investigating.
  The air in New- York's $55.000.000 subway is already undergoing official investiga
  tion.
  Grarc charges are brought against it; the gravest perhaps being that the only fresh
  elr the subway can gt t is drawn almost entirely from the level of the streets.
  Tests made by the Street Cleaning Department show thai the air at the pavement lerel
  fairly recks with bacilli, and in some districts 9,600 colonies of them were found on a plate
  cf a few inches area at the end of fifteen minutes exposvrrc.
  The reason New-Yorkers can live in such an atmosphere is because sunlight kills
  these swarming bacilli.
  According ba the bacteriologist of the Health Department, bacteria will thrive es
  pecially well in the subway because of the lack of sunlight.
  The roadbed alongside the station platforms of the subway is believed by many ex
  perts to be a breeding place for bacteria, which are expectorated there by passengers
  waiting for trnins, and which, when the sputum dries, are caught up and thrown into the
  faces of crowds by the passing trains.
  The absolute necessity of adequate ventilation and sanitation is shown by an examina
  tion made of the cocoa mats on the floors of the elevated cars. One fibre only 1 inches
  long plucked from such a mat showed 4,000,000 bacilli of different sorts, which would
  breed consumption, pneumonia and grip, besides many more diseases. These mats get
  plenty of sunlight.
  The investigation of the Health Department may also discover that the subway air
  contains too much of the poisonous carbonic acid gas exhaled from the lungs of passen
  gers.
  Tests made by one expert showed that the subway contained more carbonic acid gas
  thin the electric subways of Boston, London or Paris. Another experiment, which, how
  ever, was attacked and called extravagant by a Columbia professor, showed that the sub
  vrr.x air was BO lacking in oxygen as to be positively dangerous.
  Paper pinwheels held in the subway entrances last week showed that, in spite of the
  complaints of stagnant air, passing trains drew in and threw out strong currents of air.
  Employes of the subway said they had not noticed any ill effects from breathing its
  atmosphere day after day.
  Our authority 6'iid be thought the electricity in the subway might purify the air to
  gome extent by the creation of ozone.
  Alexander E. Orr, president of the Rapid Transit Commission, said that the engineer
  ing department of that commission would plin new means of ventilation, and the operat
  ing company would pay for them, in case the subway was found unhealthful.
  I". P. Kryan, vice-president of the operating company, said that it would remedy any
  proved defed in the subway.
  The experts who discuss the subject of subway ventilation for The Tribune, and whose
  views are given below, include Dr. George A. Soper, Charles H. Myers. Samuel Whinery
  ;md H. Waller Brinckerhoff, civil engineers and members of the special commission em
  ployed a year ago by the Merchants' Association to investigate the ventilation and sanita
  tk» of Surface and elevated cars; Professors Charles F. Chandler and Charles Pellqw, of
  I'niversity; Professor Albert Spice, of Cooper Institute; Professor R. Ogden
  Doranns, formerly of the City College; Professor Charles Bnskerville, his successor as
  id of the chemistry department; Dr. August Seibert. a physician; Dr. Herman M.
  the Health Department; William R. Hinsdale, a mining company
  i dunning, a mining engineer.
  GIiTER AIR AT BEST.
  t the Subway, GcU Is Loaded
  xcith Microbes.
  I--.1. 1 main argument of those who believe that
  th? subway is lently ventilated Is the
  amount of air taken in through the entrances
  from the streets. The question arises, Is this
  eir that comes in from the street of sufficient
  purity to be used in ventilating the underground
  system?
  The kiosks are built on the pavement near the
  curb.. They stand wide open to every breeze
  that comes up or down the street. They act as
  a sort of scoop for the dust and germ laden air
  Just, above the pavement. There have been a
  Dumber of experiments in the pa.st which go to
  prove that this air Is full of colonies of bacilli.
  Unless purer air can be supplied these germs
  trill constantly be drawn Into the subway by tho
  millions, to thrive and multiply there in the
  darkness.
  borne time ago a series of testa was made by
  the Btreel Cleaning Department of the air six
  I c at various points in
  m Ltan. Prepared gelatine plates were
  used, and p. :i exposure of half an hour brought
  1 some rather startling results. In places
  •rltere there was a largo amount of travel, where
  pushcarts were In large numbers. In a thickly
  populated tenement house district as many as
  0,000 colonies of bacilli appeared In a fifteen
  minute exposure. Even Fifth-aye., after Laving
  been thoroughly flushed and put in the best pos
  sible condition, showed numerous bacilli.
  With this article The Tribune presents a num
  ber of plate;: selected at random from several
  fcuiidrc-d covering tho part of the city traversed
  by the subway. A tenement street near the
  Bleecker-st. station, for instance, shows 8,070
  colonies. This exposure, as •with the others,
  *as made at the middle of the block and six
  Inches above the pavement. At the corner
  •haw the subway kiosks stand the authorities
  ■ay the number of colonies would probably be
  greater.
  A Harlem street frequented by pushcarts
  showed 2,530 colonies. It Is paved with granite
  and the traffic is heavy. An exposure made at
  TOe-hundred-and-nfty-firstHst and Morrls-ave.
  ■bowed 1.115 colonies, though the street is not a
  crowded tenement section. Over in "Little
  Italy," In East undred-and-twelfth-st., the
  number of colonies was 3.195.
  Already the Street Cleaning Department has
  noticed the danger of contaminating th- sub
  ay fed as it is with :i!r from the streets. Order*
  nave been given to keep the streets In the Imme
  c\ate vicinity of the subway Openings ac clean
  M r.&lt;-&gt;.«!?:h■M all refuse will be carted away immediately
  V hrr&lt; t Hse streets will be flushed by
  the department.
  Acre must ab he considered the ever growing
  Wame of bacilli which are deposited by spittenj
  "the subway. At ary hour of the day men by
  ■J iCOre may be seen waiting for trains and
  setting- freeiy down upon the roadbed of
  &lt;*ack'.d stone Thi« cracked stone cannot be
  e*er»t or flushed, and wfll hold the sputum until
  't .s dry. when the moving trains will sweep it
  "■•to the- lungs of passengers. When the Hi r
  tt^ts rf the elevated trains have been micro
  ■copicaily examined millions of disease terms
  »aye been revealed. And these mats are
  £«ar.ea frequently, and get lots of sunlight
  What Will a similar examination of this un
  cwanabla roadbed of broken stone show after a
  year cf continual darkness?
  -w£ Jor these reasons that the investigation
  •I Dr. Eiggs, the bacteriologist of the Health
  r)ar; may cause a radical change in the
  ventilation of the subway.
  COMPANY TO VENTILATE IF NEEDED.
  The Rapid Transit Commission Is not likely to
  ***c any difficulty in getting the Interborough
  R apid Transit Company to construct a system of
  J lation, if one should be found necessary. E.
  Bryan. vic&lt;2-pre£ider.t of the company, said two
  •r three days &amp;ao: "We are treating this question
  W bad air uh a serious If there i.- a defect
  jn tt*e subway or its ventilation, v in t to remedy
  v«e believed that there mis sufficient outlet to
  Ixu oul^ r air -hrouph the station entrances and
  Pali eh ar£Sl** t'Jbwsy. for Instance, by doors. We will
  "™*^y any defect that (a shown to us. however."
  THE PIN WHEEL TEST.
  It Shows Strong Draughts in and
  Out of the Subway.
  A great many reicnilar travellers in the fuhway
  declare that the air Is improving every day. In
  other words, they say the subway is hard at ■work
  ventilating Itself. A simple expedient for testing
  the air currents in and out of the stations was
  tried by a Tribune reporter at a number of stations
  on two days of last week. A ehec-t of paper, a pin
  and a short stick properly manipulated gave a
  paper pinwbeel such as children run about the
  street with. By holding the paper wheel at the
  entrances, the force and direction of the draught
  could be determined.
  At the Brooklyn Bridge station there are two en
  tranoos and two exits within a few feet of each
  other on the edge of City Hall Park. "When thera
  were no trains moving through the station and no
  wind swiping through the park, there was not
  enough air current to move tho wheel. The rush
  of an express or local train into the station made a
  perceptible current of clr coming out. and th*> wheel
  epun sharply. With the departure of a local train
  for the City Hall loop or of an express train for the
  cv.itching yards there waa a considerable In
  draught, and the wheel spun again. The departure
  of trains on the upbound track did not seem to
  make a perceptible difference to the plnwheel.
  The Fourteenth-st. station is one of the largest on
  the system. The station men are somewhat
  troubled with varying draughts, and the reporter's
  wheel spun merrily in various parts of the station
  according to th© direction of moving trains.
  A wind was blowing briskly from the west when
  the reporter stopped at the Twenty-eight h-st. sta
  tion. The kiosks on the downtown slue «e&lt;=-med to
  act aa scoops, and the wind swept into the station
  with a force that made passengers who left the sta
  tion gather their garments about them. Th.
  wheel was nearly curried off its s-tirk. Crossing to
  the downtown side, a strong out current was felt
  and the wheel fairly whizzed.
  The wheel showed that tho best ventilators for
  the big Grand Central station of the subway are
  the kiosks Rt the corner of Bfadlson-ave. The
  draughts from the cntrancf-s at the eastern end of
  the station were not so perceptible, and depended
  on the movement of trains.
  At Beventy-second-st. and One-hundred-ai;d-thlrd
  et. and Broadway tho stations are entered through
  Wide mouthed brick structures. Tne wheel showed
  that the prevailing air currents are bound in. At
  the One-hundred-und-forty-flfth-Ft. terminal sta
  tion th* wheel acted in the same way.
  The experiments with the paper wheel attracted
  no little attention and some comment.
  "He looks too grown up to Le playing with a pto
  wheel," dpclarf.i one matron as sht entered a sta
  tion where the reporter was experimenting.
  "It's an aggravated case of subwayitla," explained
  the man who accompanied her. "A lot of people
  have it. It began by timing every train between
  st tli as. Ftor tl first wc&lt;-k there would be hall a
  dozen men In every car holding their wat&lt; bes In
  their hands, with their eyes on the dial, aa inter
  ested as though they were timing a racehorse
  Now they are testing air currents and draughts'
  and even the air Itself."
  At a station on Morningslde Heights the reporter
  GELATINE PLATES EXPOSED TO THE AIR AT THE PAVEMENT LEVEL IN VARIOUS PARTS OF THE CITY, AND THE GERM COLONIES
  WHICH THEY COLLECTED.
  A HARLEM STRXET~V>»O
  *J*O FA' JOY fully the luxury of a
  brilliant, soft nnd deliriously flavored
  Ale you must insist upon getting
  g
  there you will find Ale- in its highest
  state without a particle of sediment.
  Any Dealer or l'lace.
  C 11. EVANS SON", N. V.
  Tl
  w.-ia mistaken for a freshman doing some sort of an
  Initiation "stunt."
  "Your wheel will run faster if you hold it in
  front of an express train sonny," suggested an
  Interested sophomore.
  The citizen who is interested in public problem!
  (topped to talk it over.
  "What is there to this bail air business?" he de
  manded. "Yesterday I saw a man in spectacles
  tilling bottles with air. He said be waa going to
  analyse it. Here you are to-day experimenting
  with draughts. I hope you find the air's all right,
  but I don't mind telling you that a ride in the sub
  way always leaves me depressed. I've laid It to the
  flicker of the white posts past tlie windows, but
  perhaps it is the air. It has occurred to me that
  they niiKVit put compressed air tanks in every car
  and l»&gt;t out fresh air as It was needed l suppose it
  would cost too much to compress Adirondack air
  and bring ii down here for the subway. Hut
  wouldn't that bo a tine thin?, though? Think of if
  Consumption cured right here In Manhattan, and
  nil for the price of. a few subway tickets. I you
  think it would be too expensive?"
  The reporter said he thought it might make New-
  York an unrivalled health resort, and the citizen
  went on Into the tube chuckling over his grand
  idea.
  The chemists, official and Individual, have at
  tracted some notice while gathering their air
  samples. Most of them use a bottle with a device
  which draws in the air. When the bottle is filled It
  Is hermetically sealed. Samples are taken from the
  station floors, from a point a few Inches below the
  ceiling-, from cars In motion, from cars standing in
  the terminal and from various places In the tunnel
  Itself. The Board of Health chemist has taken a
  number of samples, a chemist employed by the In
  terborough Company was gathering air last week
  and a number of private individuals who know
  enough about chemistry to take an air sample cor
  rectly and analyze it, have been around with their
  bottles.
  SPITTING IX THE SUBWAY.
  Health Board Will Endeavor to
  Stop the Practice.
  Ah far as the general public lf» concerned the
  Investigation instituted by the Department of Health
  will doubtless be permitted to settle the question
  ns to whether or not the air In the subway Is impure
  and detrimental to the public health, or pure enough
  to breatlio with safety. This investigation was
  ordered early in tho tveftk by Commissioner Thomas
  TESTING SUBWAY AIR.
  Profesor Spice, of the Department of Chemistry of Cooper Union. Is measuring its percentage of
  poisonous carbonic acid gas.
  Darlington, whose inspectors have been at work
  in the tunnel since It was opened.
  The investigations will proceed on two lines. Pro
  fessor Charles F, Chandler, of Columbia University,
  the consulting sanitary officer of the Board of
  Health, will Investigate general air conditions. The
  bacteriologists of the department will look into
  germ conditions prevailing In the cars and stations.
  The Investigations will continue for at least a
  month In order that all of the various conditions
  can be noted. Until the Investigations are complete
  no data will ba given out. The health authorities
  cay that to so would be unfair to both the Bub
  way operating company and to the public, as it
  would be Jumping at conclusions.
  If the result :tli'- subway air Is impure and danscrou to
  lons will be made to lmi
  authorities say th&lt; ha\
  t that 1 mpany will gladly
  follow anj that will make the tube
  more healthy. Every facility is being gb n the
  department chemists engaged in the im
  "From day the subway said Dr.
  Darlington rday to a Tribum i I have
  had inspe tors watching It. l hav&lt;
  two In* 8. I&amp;gt;&lt; hemisi s
  •,\ill take many samples of air it: the subway at
  different points and analyze thwill be taken on different days, at differem times
  of tlio and at difTeren
  attention will be paid to larj;o stations where
  crowds congregate in the rush hours.
  of th&lt; department bacteriologists, prob
  ably Dr. Parke, will carry on a series of experi
  ments for dangerous bacilli. These experiments
  will be made in tho usual way. and will be as ex
  "Until these examinations are folly completed
the department can come to no decision regarding
th&lt; healthfulness of the subway. It. will not do
to jump at conclusions, for the matter is of too
great importance,
"Personally, I ilou'ot very much If. there Is any
thing deleterious about subwa% conditions. My
trip ill 1 Inspection was made before the road was
formally opened. The only objectionable thins I
noti.eJ was a slight odor. Investigation showed
tlun this came directly from th*- oil lamps, which
are a necessary part of the safety signal system.
These lamps are necessary, as electricity could
not be depended on. The odor may be unplr|isant
at times, but there is nothing about it that will
endanger the health of those who ride or work in
the subway."
"The Board of Health is going to rr.:ike ev«ry
effort to stop expectorating in the subway sta
tions and trains. The crusude against spitting on
surface and elevated cars hns been successful to
a murk»-d degree. There war a time when the
Hoard of Health rule against it was Ignored ab
solutely. A number of arrests ware made by th«
police, by department inspector and on complaint
of private citizens. The judges before whom the
fritters were brought promptly imposed lines, and
conditions begna to Improve.
"In tho subway th« danger of disease from ex
pectoration is fully as «r.-;tt. if not greater, than
on surface roads. When the sputum dries the
jrerms it contains ar»- free and become dangerous.
We onnnot have them blowing about the tunnel.
A very close watch will be kept to see that the
habit does not get a foothold on the underground
pi if necessary b campaign similar to that
which brought such Improvement on the surface
and elevated roacis will be waged in the subway."
SPUTUM OX THE TRACK.
When Dried It Is Blown Into One's
Lungs.
rles Myers, ;i civil erudneer, 5.-ild that
most i i!th of the
i which
I. He n ii hould be o!
concreti or s#me other Material.
v. iiii h bed
"At the present time ihe track all r.s**.'U- the plat
forms &lt;&gt;i stations," s;ii'l he, "for it great many pa. c
Bengers serves the purpsse of spittoons. As t-r.;io..s
betwi en the tracks are laid with broken stone and
grave!, thert is DO way of cleaning them, and ac
cordingly tho bacteria implanted there will be
swept Into tho faces of passengers every time a
tra.in comes into the station.
"As for ventilating the eubway. I think the most
FIFTH-AY®.— 63 COLONIXa.
$1.20, 1.80, 3.00, 3.75, 6.00. 12X0 per dozen
practical means would be n partition between the
tracks of traln.-i moving In opposite directions. At
the present time the train* do not act so much in
the capacity of pistons as of the movable parts Of
a churn. There is a certain amount of air. of
coarse, passing In and out of the station entrances.
due to differences in the temperature of th» air
Within and without, and also to the movement of
passengers up and down the states, as well to a
certain extent to the passing trains. With the con
struction of a dividing wall, however, the volume of
air forced in and out of the underground chamber
would be vastly Increased."
Or Boston, As Is Shown by Compar
ative Tests.
As the result of a comparison of experiments by
Professor Alfred Spice, of the department of chem
istry of Cooper Union, and Dr. Georsre H. Sp!c». a
civil engineer, It has been round that the air of tho
New- York subway is more impure than that of the
Boston subway, or the London electric tunnel.
known as the South London Electric Railway.
Professor Spice found that in tha cut between
Thirty-third-st. and Forty-second-st. the air con
tained M ten thousandths of carbonic acid gas.
According to Dr. Soper in the Boston sub
way there Is from 6.53 to 9.13 ten thou
sandths, and in the London tube there is about
3. The London tube is ventilated, however. In
a different way from the New- York subway, for
the reason that there is a sinsrle train to a
single tube, and the air Is thus sucked In behind
and driven out ahead. Nevertheless. Frofessor
Spice thinks there need be no cause for alarm.
In telling or' his experiments Professor Spice
said: "I took a glass gas collector out on the
platform of a local northbound train as it left
the Thirty-third-st. station. The collector was
about eight Inches long, an inch thick, and of
glass. It hail a stopcock at either end. I opened
both stopcocks and let the distilled water with
which it was filled run out. Then I turned the
stopcocks and bagged my air.
"At the laboratory I forced out by means of
mercury enough of the subway air to fill a
burette, or long glass tube, containing just 100
cubic centimetres. This done I again forced oat
the air Into a series of bulbs, called a pipette,
th« bulb of -which held a mixture of potash and
water. This combination absorbs carbonic aci.l
gas as soon as it is brought into contact with
It. After being assured that all of the C O, had
been absorbed, I let the mercury run out of the
burette, thus sucking back the air where I
might measure it. I found that it had lost a
thousandth part. or. in oth.»r words, that it
had formerly contained 10 ten thousandths of
carbonic acid gas."
The air in the centre of a local train Fro
fessor Spice found to contain 10 ten thousandths
of carbonic acid gas, or the same as that 01 the
subway. The car, however, had all the tran
soms open. In a northbound express car. just
before it reached the Xinety-sixrh-Bt. station,
and after it had been closed up tight for three
minutes, he found twenty party of carbonic
acid gas., or twice as much as be found In the
subway.
"Four parts of carbonic acid gas in ten thou
sand parts of air is the amount found in the
open air," said the professor. "Twenty parts, or
as much as I found in the express car, would
do no harm to a healthy person, but might af
fect one of weak hangs. Indeed, an ordinary
person can stand as nigh as fifty before feeling
the effects, in a sort of headachy sensation and
drowsiness, I do not consider, therefore, that
the air In the subway la any more injurious
than thai In some elevated express cars, which
.ire boxed up for a much longer time than any
subway trains, and In which the C has been
found as high as thirty-one parts.
"In warm, damp weather, however, it may
be found that the air of the subway will become
more Impure than is safe for the public health,
and In such case.-; I think fans should be In
stalled. At the present time, however. I think
we should be no more alarmed about the sub
way than about the elevated or surface cars
when overcrowded.
Trains Cannot Purify Subway At
mosphere.
Samuel Whinery, a civil ensrin3e:\ said with much
emphasis that the air of the subway should be
studied most carefully, and if it was found to lack
oxygen and to contain a large number of bacteria
because of being replenished by air taken from the
gutter level of the street, fans should be Installed.
A partition between the uptown and downtown
trains would not be sufficient, he said.
"Some people get the wrong idea of moving air." Btlrresubway stir up
the air, It I don't think that the-y drive much o?
!t out and Especially la summer weather, when
the air of the subway will be heavier than that out
side, this effect on the air will be ntiM less. True*.
moving air exhilarates in or.c way. but only through
the skin. It is just as Injurious to th* lunjs if
containing bacteria or poilOOQua fcaics as if it was
stagnant.
"Great care should be taken to prevent the crowd-
Ing of sub a train*. It ha.* bren fouod that tho
air of cr >wded elevated expres.se* 1.; Uaigsrrous'y
contamltu. teii. anil yet the elevated !3 aired from
Iht I'ftn atmosphere. Subway cars. 0:1 tho other
hand. &lt;"an only be vssti&amp;Ued fro::: eonttaed air.
which under the test conditions caniMt co;apare
with the free atmosphere of heaven."
Dr. Herman it Biggs, the bacterlo!oj?st of tta*
Department of Health, aald. In response to a Cjßsa*</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065167/1915-01-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=new+york+subway&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.213,-0.089,1.425,1.425,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>TWELVE ARE DEAD FROM
  NEW YORK SUBWAY EIRE
  MORE THAN 100 PERSONS OVER
  COME BY 8MOKE AND CUT
  BY GLA88.
  Ilg l lü lll I M B i njure d hundrümH
  caused from an explosion in the
  electrical conduit was the conclu
  sion reached by officials late to
  day after extensive Investigation.
  Public Service Commission Mc
  Call said the subway service may
  be tied up for several days, caus
  ing ;an unparalleled congestion,
  as millions of persons use it every
  day.
  The police declare today's fire
  Is the worst accident In the his
  tory of the New York subway.
  New York, Jan. 6.—More than 100
  persons were Overcome by smoke, cut
  by glass and otherwise hurt in a fire
  In the New York subway between
  .fifteenth and fifty-ninth streets dur
  ing the rush hours this morning,
  In the confusion which followed,
  ■psetting the whole traffic system of
  be metropolis, the police issued a
  IMatement saying twelve are dead,
  iBriÉsnme of the firemen sarrying out
  ip^fcjured estimated the dead at 200.
  ^Ker in the day, however, the flg
  Slj^»roved to be unfounded. So far
  person is positively known to
  !||^nd, though It Is practically cer
  original estimate of the po
  Mflfi be reache'jJÄntite fire fighting force of Man
  called out to fight the
  every pulmotor that could
  was brought to the scene,
  certain that the list of dead
  be6n much greater but
  and efflu'eut work of
  tor.
  that scores of persons were
  I unconscious Is responsible
  H| exaggerated estimates
  j^K>f dead.
  were stalled because
  H|^n-ouble when the fire
  III^^Lsengpi's poured out
  little heed to the
  cl
  fc
  of th^^B
  Sev^H
  of pow^H
  started.*
  of the efl
  deadly tla
  The wo$
  being coi
  cut holes
  the deadly
  bureau of
  pared to b
  .fire department Is
  Ld. The firemen
  ■vements, letting
  Aot the tube.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1918-12-17/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=subway&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.187,-0.069,1.374,1.374,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92051126/1905-09-12/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=new+york+subway&amp;r=-0.169%2C0.363%2C0.987%2C0.516%2C0&amp;st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>CROSS SHOWS WHERE TRAIN PLUNGED INTO STREET.
  rramna'X'rm**
  -c/iwrrsr.og-TCT'f ftHMl
  RESCUERS REMOVING DEAD FROM DEI3R5S OF WRECKED CAR.
  NYork, Sept. 12.—Viewed from
  the standpoint of a railway expert, the
  Immediate cause of the terrible disas
  ter on the elevated1 road was the appli
  cation of the emergency brakes when
  sthe train, was moving at high speed on
  a curve.
  S. S. Neff, who organized the Union
  elevated loop of Chicago in 1897, and
  later built and operated the Boston ele
  vated, and who has been employed as
  an expert for the New York subway
  and the Brooklyn rapid transit, was m
  this city yesterday. When seen in his
  hotel after the accident he said that
  while he did not wish to attack the
  management of the elevated railway
  system, yet in the interest of public
  safety certain things should be known.
  “In the first place,” said Mr. Neff,
  “the junction where the accident hap
  pened is one of tile most dangerous I
  know of. A junction with level ap
  proaches at grade is bad enough, but
  with the descending grade from 59th
  street the ,52 street junction is exceed
  ingly efungerous to operate. It is
  equipped, as I understand, with the old
  ©lyle mechanical interlocking system.
  This junction has for years been oper
  ated in a dangerous manner. Trains
  have been allowed to approach and
  pass over it with clear signals at en
  tirely too high a rate of speed.
  “The actual cause of the accident
  may never be positively determined.
  If. as is stated by the management,
  the mntorman of o. Ninth avenue train
  displayed) signals or markers for
  Bixth avenue train this does not excus-’
  either the motorman or the man in the
  signal tower, as no signal should be
  given to any train approaching a junc
  tion without the tower signal man
  knowing that the motorman had his
  train under control This is especially
  true at junction points where, as on the
  elevated road', no derail device can be
  in1? tailed.
  "If the motorman was approaching
  the junction at a rate of 30 mites an
  hour the signal towerman should never
  have given a clear route or signal to
  the train. This is particularly true at
  53d street junction on account of the
  physical characteristics of the cross
  ing.
  If both signal blades had been at
  danger and an automatic stop fixture
  provided, as on the exprey® trains in
  the subway, the train would have been
  properly stopped and the markers on
  the first car changed for the proper
  route.
  "There is not the slightest diouht that
  the elevated roads of Manhattan and
  Brooklyn are not properly signalled,
  both at junction points ar.d on main
  tr.n ks. It has been unfortunate that
  the financiers and management have
  disregarded this most Important pro
  vision in the safe operation of their
  roads. It has proved to be false econ
  omy, for no motorman is nifnUfble.
  ‘‘Tile Boston 'Lf was equipped with
  a.n electro-pneumatic system of sig
  nals, which has been in operation for
  five years without a single collision or
  derailment. The same system was
  copied by the New York subway, and
  so far as the express or high speed
  tracks are concerned the road is prop
  erly equipped. It is unfortunate, to
  say the least, that the local tracks are
  only equipped with signals on curves,
  leaving straight lines at the mercy of
  the motorman.
  Heavier Cars Needed.
  “As for the accident on the elevated
  yesterday, I would like to bring out as
  forcibly as possible the undesirability
  of operating trains wrth light trailer
  cars between motor cars of greater
  weight. In ail cases of derailment or
  collision the light car gets the worst
  of it.
  “The derailment was no doubt caused
  primarily by too high a rate of speed.
  There is not the slightest doubt that
  the first wheels to leare the track were
  the front wheels of the second car, or
  trailer, and that this was caused by*
  the application of the air brakes in
  emergency, i</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062011/1915-01-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=new+york+subway&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.25,-0.075,1.5,1.5,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>FIRE IN
  NEW YORK
  SUBWAY
  FIRE IN SUBWAY TRAIN CALLS
  OUT WHOLE FIRE DEPARTMENT
  NEW YORK, Jan. t&gt;- During tho rush
  hours when tho New York subway is
  crowded to its fullest capacity a fire
  broke out in one of the trains which
  i aused a congestion of trnftle and tho
  whole of the Manhattan tire depart
  ment was called to the scene. Many
  people were removed in an unconscious
  Mate hut there are as yet no known
  dead.
  The cars and the subway itself are
  practically fire proof which accounts
  for the escape of the people without
  any loss of life.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1919-10-22/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=subway&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.186,-0.069,1.373,1.373,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ping-pong-craze</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-07-13/ed-1/?sp=39&amp;q=ping-pong&amp;r=-0.06,0.725,0.801,0.419,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>THE REPUBLIC: SUNDAY. JULY 13, 1902.
  PING-PONG 15 THE WARM-WEATHER DIVERSION OF YOUNG 5T. LOUIS SOCIETY MATRONS.
  POLISHED TABLES IN CENTER OF REAR
  LAWNS AFFORD CONVENIENT COURTS.
  WITH STARS AND ELECTRIC LIGHTS FOR ILLUMINATION
  THE GAME BECOMES AN EVENING PASTIME.
  VELVETY GRASS PROVES RESTFUL TO
  THE EYES and COOLING TO TIRED FEET
  AiiFS
  S?
  L
  a Srrrm mrvyis
  
  
  imiiniiiiHiiiiiui
  i n a f liiii it- j-
  uiinmiuimm'1'"'"
  ll,,r-- CUM II f UV -Hl frf2.JtTrTr Ufl
  iwS55jw?S
  lumuiim'iiiiiiiin'iinim
  srJ""'ltt''u,ZZz?? 'Th?
  ""ni)iii,i,.Tl '."'WrUCfTfiC?!
  Zr"","H7WJlni .7- UUjm
  i
  i
  I
  fa
  SkV
  1
  
  i
  It
  r
  I
  V
  ;&amp;s1
  K
  .t;
  Mrs. Craufnrr? n..,-
  Donovan and Mr; -Frnpc
  the' table. Mrs. Ralph
  Mrs. Mae W;ggs looking
  i n h wrwrtp'gnF,TTi
  Kr C?.wford Ptttv-iti ef St. Lool has
  ohrtd Q problem o tni-Wng hnsbaad.
  fT7illy cad irlenfti, eomfort&amp;blt at boma,
  rn tn tbe hottest -weather. At her beau
  tiful Mxideaoe. No. C27 West Plus bonle
  Trt3. gmrTrr has so terrors for tho:a who
  Uv thero.
  rtec uuidtwr of 7esra Mrs. Dcncaa has
  rtfoxtd to shut tip her hcrass In tha t-ora-aa;
  cr It her hcsfcond behind to itais
  tfi trlth tha dlscoroforU of a loaeljr ex
  irtzDoa. As Mr. Bcccan's business keeps
  htm la tha eitr tha best part of tha hot
  twin, lira. Duncan declines to co away
  br heraalf. In tha month of August they
  go toxsthtr to some Northern or Eastern
  raajJt and com hack together, irben vaca
  tlsn thsa is ep.
  Tha roolt of tM thourhtfolners and tm
  Mtflshaass oa Mrs. Duncan's part Is trrat
  tlMraJs a yerr channlnr. comfortabla
  hocashold erst on the boulevard, where so
  zsasr bosses have tha blinds drawn and
  tha windows tUhtlr dosed.
  While the front ef the Duncan rxrese has
  that gs!al aspect of epenesa In tha after
  Tmwtt. wbca tha sun Is coins down. It is in
  the back yard that tha Duncans find their
  real enjoyment.
  FingpPong Transplanted to
  tha Cool Back Yard.
  Th4 irrely rame of plac-pcnt, to which
  n" "''"sal
;4?
M
the game. Mrs. Crawford .1
Mrs. Dan Donovan and Mrs. 7,p
Boogher umpiring.
-?'o
N
NS
44
bA
ki
m
V..
,.VW
1U .1
niij
4
fe7-Jf(f

''r2
w
H"
n
Ji
is:
r
m
,uV

X?
BrVT

io
-Vft n
a rause in the Oame.
wigg; and Mrs. Ernest Boogher ap
propriating the candy.
i
eToady aftemoea hrrax to Mrs. Daacsrfs
home her little cotarie of pInsponf friends
for practice or recreation. The youns; ma
trons of this particular summer plng-pons
party are Mrs. Ralph Orthwein. Mrs. Daa
Donovan. Mrs. Mae WIks, Mrs. Ernest
Boogher and their hostes. Duncan. In
the eveninr the husbands Join the rame
r-V
:t
Sgi
ISS

ru .-.j3
ESS
82
'S47
tt
V',??
VY. "rv! .A
wm,jjxw
Mrs- Crawford Duncan's St. Bc.
wi. yVV "ard. Prince, taking his bath.
g


usa
Mrs. Mae r
ef theta are s1ay-t-htJices this seasoa, for
if any cf them so away at an it win sot be
tin the summer la nearly oxer.
The Udlee generally wear their shirt
waist suits for the gama.
linmimiiiL
n n
A-I
-r VJ.5
?3P1
v7B!f9
riaV&amp;'f
nmaott,
'ttnrauiiiit
Mrs. Dan
a.
r
"Atf vj w: fc, gk ---3

l"X1j
,E;
7' V.
sissi

5fV?ZL-jl:35
i zl- Mre- fr,(nA n.. J A I
rr- iiiij. uiawiuiu- LSUlliail dllU iil'.
Jj an Donovan playing Pin--F 0.
fc-i'
scr uuiwiTs, TirTea tns Bisxaaur
sotony f this summer idyl among society
folks, who seem to have banded them
selves together for the purpose of making
the season as socially agreeable as the
long winter months. The Fourth of July
was one of those delightful plcnlo days.
Tennis a Featnre on
the Orthwein Lawn.
Jest now Mrs. Ralph Orthwein is having
laid out at her home en Bartmtr avenue
a tennis court, and that game will also he
played with the stars and electrlo lights
for an illumination,
Mrs. Duncan's ptcg-pocg set win he the
i principals of the tennis games to be played
at sight tn Cabasne, With so much to en
tertain the younger society element, it Is
doubtful if many more will Join the earlier
exodus during the month of August. Mrs,
Mae Wiggs has decided to remain at home
to keep house for her father, the genial Pat
Short, who has rent his wife and grand
son away, hut prefer for himself the
comforts of his charmingly appointed
home. Mrs. Wiggs. who calls her father
"son," looks after the cooking herself, an!
leaves even the fascinating ping-pong, at
which she is a adept, to return home n
Mrs. Duncan's home. Way hack la tha
yard, under a shady tree is a, large atrsara
tank with a canopy oa top to protect tha
bather frost the sun. This Is tha tab la
which Prise. Mrs. Duncan's Mr St. Bs
t.t. takes his dally plunge, The tns Ja
filled with fresh water three times s week.
At the bottom tha tub has a flow-oS. fas
tened with a ecrfc. Any handy hoy eoaW
construct one of these tubs, which has re
tin lining to keep the wood from rottls-g.
Whlle Mrs. Duncan's friends were playing
ping-pong the other afternoon. Prince had
his bath. As he Jumped out and among
tha guests he was not very careful of their
fresh and crisp toilets, but sprayed thira
with the water, which lie shook oat of his
shaggy mane. However, these are incidents
that make things all the more pleasant far
the young matrons, whose healthful recre
ation is the admiration of the few neigh
oars, who, like them, are remaining at
home.
</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-05-18/ed-1/?sp=46&amp;q=PING+PONG+ping+pong+ping-pong&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.408,0.646,0.693,0.724,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>SUMMER DELIGHTS OF
  B1 LJ
  ti
  I
  F. L. VA3IDEVEER &amp;SV HARRY BLO(
  Two well-known young attorneys, who are experts at the
  Written for the Sunday Republic.
  I ping We tear our clothes.
  Thou pongst You raise the deuce, if
  He pongs They fall In a faint.
  Verb, Irreg. Origin, Japan. Inf,
  s to ping-pong.
  St. Xiouls is ping-pong maa. Everybody
  plays It; and so enthusiastic are the de
  votees of the game that It is now assured
  that the game will run through the sum
  mer. But it Is a winter game, declares some
  one. We will make It a summer jjame, fben,
  is the ifsponse.
  PING PONG.
  E.ETT,
  game of Ping-Pong.
  In Its Indigenous clime it is a game for
  all the year. Summer and winter alike, it
  is a game, not only for men, but also for
  women and children.
  Tor more than three centuries how much
  more no one knows ping-pong has been a
  game of great Importance.
  Of course, the name is inane, but there is
  I
  a lot to tho game besides tho name; and
you may call it with perfect propriety, "ta
ble tennis." That will save your feelings.
Tor tho game is nothing moro or less
than a diminutive gamo of tennis It is
counted exactly like tennis; requires as
many players; furnishes as much exercise,
and offers as great an opportunity for tho
practice of subtle heart-charms.
Who plays ping-pong? The answer is
easy: Kverybody. The popularity- of tho
gamo has increased so much in tho last
few months that it has become necessary
to manufacture the racquets and balls in
St. Louis; tho foreign markets are unablo
to furnish even half of what Is required
It is not only a fad, but has undoubtedly
como to stay as much as tennis did years
ago
Tennis is still a popular game. We have
champions; national and local. So It will
bo with ping-pong before another year has
rolled around. Already In St Louis me
have tournaments, championships and
prizes at ping-pong parties. There is great
rivalry between clubs and between mem
bers of clubs. One cannot go to dine now
adays without having to tako part in a
gamo of ping-pong after the dinner. It Is
everywhere and all-absorbing.
Not only men of leisure and ladies of
quality aro indulging In it, hut business
men and college stoudents and women
mho have to busy themselves about a hun
dred and one things during the day. Hv-
erybody has the fever. A ping-pong parlor
on Locust street is crowded every day for
several hours with players and there Is no
sign of any loss of Interest In the game.
Bankers and brokers find that the gamo
gives them moro and better exercise in a
short time that they have been able to get
in any other way. Among the devotees of
the game are Allen West, Dwight Davis,
Harold Kauffman, Hunt Turner and Jim
Drummond. They frequently find tlmo to
meet during the day for a game. Usually
it Is for but a short time, but occaslonaily
they become so Interested that tfcey finish
the afternoon at the table.
But the season for ping-pong Is after
dinner. Then at private residences and at
the clubs there is Invariably a game In
progress. Special rooms have been fitted up
in houses large enough to accommodate
them, and In the clubhouses where the par
ticularly ardent worshippers at tho shrine
of the celluloid ball and the racquet may
commune with their own kind.
Stuart Stlckney, he of golf fame, is a
"fiend" at ping-pong. He says himself that
he has to struggle to keep away from a table
during tho day In order that he may devote
himself to business. But at night and on
Saturdays he gives may to th desire and
Instead of playing golf he stands at a ping
pong table until he is about ready to drop.
The exercise In the game will be ac
knowledged when It Is known that a tennis
and a golf champion have almost forsaken
their favorite game for the enticing ping
pong. Dwight Davis does not play tennis
as much as he used to; and Stuart Stlckney
is rarely seen with his clubs Yet. both ex
celled in their special branches of athletic.
But ping-pong is a winter game, said one
who was only half converted. Needless to
say he could play only fairly. A host rose
to contradict him. Already many lawns are
being prepared for a table during the um
mer. All that is necesasry 1 an even place I
for the table and light enough so that the'
balls may be seen In the evening. In Japan 1
and in England the game Is played the year
'round. Why not In St. Louis?
Evening ping-pong parties during the
summer are already assured. It Is not dis
tinctly a rich man's or woman's game, ai
has often been sapposed. but almost every
one may havo a set Tha sets aro cheap
even as compired with tennis sets. Wher
ever there is room for a dining table therfj
is room for ping-pong, and tho fascination
that the gamo nor. holds, especially amon
tho smart set. cannot bo downed by warn;
m cather.
Among tho particularly pood plng-ponr;
rooms in bt, Louis, asldo from tho clubs,
are those at tho Drummond's. Mis Wtck
him's and at tho McKittrick's. Cvery evo
ning ping-pong holda sway. It is proper
nowadays for young ladies to take soma
form of physical exercise, and ping-ponB
combines all the pleasure that they- may
find in any exercise and affords all tha
sport of play. j
Ralph and Walter McKittrlck, Arthua
Shepley and Dan KIrby- are among the best
and most enthusiastic players In the city.
The Country Club and tho Florissant Club
are utterly crazed over tho game. At pres
ent It holds the trumps over all other
games, and from Indications it will be tha
popular game of the summer at both clubs.
Of course, this does not mean that tenn!
and golf and polo will not havo their de
votees, but ping-pong will bo tho most frequently-
played gamo of tho season.
The women of the city are us enthusias
tic .as the men-possibly more so. and they
havo their claims upon the attention of tho
men and their sports. Ping-pong looks and
sounds llko a game that does not requira
as much cndtiranco and strength as other11
spons anu tint is sid to bo tho reuson
that the women have taken It up. As t,
matter ot fact. It is as violent as nlmnst
any gamo th it Is popular with many peo
ple, but It seems so playful that tho weaker
be. have seized upon It.
It is a fact that one business man of this
c ty a man or more than usual corpulence-
has reduced his weight by forty pounds
playing ping-pong. And If the truth mi.ro
known, it is probably true tint several
women have been enabled to become mora
sylph-like through the medium of the game.
But that Is .v matter concerning which
women will not talk.
Women who are onenlv .anient nl.-ners
of
ny
ping-pong are rot the ones of whom any
one can say they play to reduce thel
weight. They- are modern women In every
may, and have taken up tho game not only
because it Is tho fad, but also because it
Is a g ime that enables them to keep In
good physical condition It is proper no
longer for momtn to be weak and requiring
the attention of maids and menr but they
mut be able to cope with the strongest.
Accordingly, they tako as much exercise,
comparatively, as men And ping-pong of
fers them something in the way of a gam
that has not been offered by any thins
else.
Among the more prominent women play
ers of ping-pong are Mrs. James Drurr
mond, Mrs. William' Gregg, Mri. Laurence
J. Mornn MIs ickham. Mis Mitchell.
Mrs. E O. Stanard, Mrs. W. II. Walker
and Mrs. Goodman King. Each of theso
has an elaborate ping-pong room fitted up
nt her house, and parties are frequent. It
is not at nit unusual for them to meet in
the morning and play arduously befora
luncheon. It serves as an excellent appe
tizer. The game was hroiight 'to St. Louis by
two people at about the same time. Mrs.
E. H. Semple ot Westminster place be
came enamored of the game while abroad
last summer, and when she returned she
set up a table at once. Sirs. Sidney Walker
appeared on the scene at about the sama
time, an enthusiastic player of the game.
That mas its start In thi3 city. It did not
take long to bring the sport to its present
position, but these two St. Louisans havo
been instrumental In making it a fad.
One of the best players among the women
is Mrs. Lewis Haywood She has for sev
eral months been a devotee, and lias ac
quired remarkable 'kill in handling tho
racquet. Mrs. John Fowler Is another ex
cellent player, and Mrc Dan Taylor, Mrs,
Campbell Smith and Mrs. Frank HammeS
are also in the first class. I
V
1
W-u&amp;gg
&amp;gj&amp;4. &amp;JS3figgi3g3
j' m t.
:-x&amp;ft73aBSflffi h. "W g.fe-tgp
ing&amp;&amp;$&amp;ifjser
itt4&amp;ss.-2S</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-05-25/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=daft+ping-pong&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.259,-0.201,1.07,1.07,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>DAFT ON PING-PONG
  Washington Entranced With
  Game, Which Is Played
  in Many Homes
  'fcOOM OF TIGHT CORSET
  f(Xew Diversion Has Phenotncnal
  Hold on All Sort* and Condi-
  tion*. From 9teM Senators
  tv DudtliiiK Debutantes.
  Special to The Globe.
  WASHINGTON, D. C. May 21.—Mover
  j lias the national capital been so com-
  T-letely enslaved by the fascinations of a
  game, indoor or outdoor, as it has fallen
  (under the seductive influence of the won
  jdc-rful new game, which, having set all
  J l^ngland crazy, has come with- a power
  to] stride across the Atlantic to exercise
  its potent influence upon our social life.
  i As a prominent leader of Washington
  I society remarked the other day, "Wash
  ington has fairly gone ping-pong mad."
  Conversation in capital society has now
  i foe-come impregnated with the peculiar
  I terms of the new pastime. Where for
  merly one would hear "social precedence"
  and "rising man," one now hears "clever
  i (half volleyer" and "invincible striker
  I out."
  "Love" and "advantage" as topics of
  social conversation have now a ping-pong
  significance entirely foreign to their for
  xtx-r meaning among the capital gossips.
  The ping-pong party has entirely sup
  planted the whist party arid the bridge
  circle.
  The peculiar ping-pong of the celluloid
  balls as they are beaten to and fro (from
  ■which the game derives its name) is now
  to be heard j in every Washington home
  from the palatial mansion of the fam
  -1 ily of the men who shape the nation's.
  I destiny on Pennsylvania avenue to the
  humble residence of the congressional
  I bootblack in the eastern section of the
  i city. Years are a matter of no consid
  ©ration among the devotees of the sport.
  The mature matron whose nod or frown
  I Oias settled one way or the other the so
  cial aspirations of mar.v- a newcomer
  .at the capital is as frequently to be seen
  i exerting herself in a manner wonderful
  to behold, to keep the little swiftly pass- j
  ing celluloid ball from dropping on her
  I side of the net, as is the beautiful bud
  ding debutante who, with flushed face,
  eyes sparkling with enthusiasm- and ex
  citement. and bared arms wildly but
  Withal skillfully circling the air, is a
  cSaily testimonial to the aethestic features
  of the game.
  Strike* nil Classes.
  Nor are the enthusiasts of the new
  gam" to be found only among the fairer
  sex, Washington masculinity has given
  itself to ping-pong with an abandon
  ,Nor ar^ the enthusiasts .of the now
  which would furnish a profitable study to
  the seeker- of pysehologieal phenomena.
  Staid congressmen, dignified senators.
  Learned members of the bench and bar
  When they meet together nowadays dis
  cuss not, the political significance of the
  lim.s. but the latest-make of ping-pong
  racquet.
  This -may be regarded as gross exagger
  ation. It is a potent fact, however, that
  ping p has attained a surprising vogue
  ■among Washington's public men.
  All the leading hotels and cafes are
  hastening to open up ping-pong parlors
  on their premises, so that their distin
  guished patrons may indulge .to their
  heart's content in the game.
  Senator Maur.a. when asked the other'
  ■day whether he favored the. erection of aj
  ping-pong parlor in the national capital,
  l>uckercd up.his brow* and gave the mat
  tor a few minutes' serious consideration
  before discussing the idea with a smile.
  Congressman Sulzer, when asked to ex
  plain the tremendous hold that ping-pong
  has taken upon members of the-house,
  said that it is a wonderful game for~ex
  erclse. and gives one a good hand to
  sustain the handshaking proclivities of
  the vast army of well meaning citizens
  who swoop down upon unwilling repre
  sentatives of the people with all the re
  lentless energy of the notorious New
  Jersey musquito upon its helpless victim.
  As may be supposed, the stores have
  not been slow to take advantage of the
  commercial possibilities of the craze. In
  -addition to the fact that some of the
  larger dry goods emporiums are opening
  up ping-pong saloons for the accommo
  dation of their patrons, the new game
  has an important bearing upon the latest
  styles. The ping-pong waist is prom
  inently- displayed in the shop windows,
  find is a phenomenal seller; while the
  new forms of neckwear for women and
  men bear handsomely embroidered figure.*
  ■of ping-pong racquets and balls upon
  their silken folds.
  Doom of the Tight Corset.
  One important reform the game prom,
  ises to effect, which may render rational,
  the development which has been lavished'
  upon it by England and America and im
  mortalize the new game as one of the
  most valuable and beneficent reform fac
  tors of the century.
  Ping-pong may abolish the tight laced
  ■corset.
  Ping-pong is essentially an informal
  game to be played at the spur of the
  moment, as the whim seizes. It is a
  game to be introduced by the smiling
  hostess after the last vestige of the din
  "■ner has been cleared away and ti;o
  white table cloth is removed to make
  way for the ping-pong net. Consequently
  as the rapid movement and freedom of
  body S necessary to me ping-pong player
  renders the corset impossible, the charm
  ing diner out has either to leave off her
  corsets when she dresses to attend a
  modern dim party or run the risk of
  having to stand against the wall in ail
  the-prim symmetry of a corseted waist
  and, watch the merry movements of her
  more fortunate sisters who, with grace
  fully swing forms, keep the merry cellu
  loid ball ping-ponging across the table
  at a lively pace to the intense admira
  tion of the man with the racquet on th^
  other side of the table and .every other
  man In the room. v
  This good may ping-pong do; bu other
  wise what peculiar qualities has the same
  to '-rive it phenomenal popularity? Strict
  ly speaking it is nothing more or less
  then a table adaptation of lawn tennis
  and tennis, while possessing to an equal
  and even greater degree the same physi
  cal benefits and sporting fascinations of
  its replica has never attained the vogue
  which has been vouchsafed to ping-pong.
  Played on Dining Table.
  Ping-pong is played on an ordinary din-
  Ing table and its only accessories are
  posts tp hold the net, the net itself
  vellum string or wood-racquets and cellu-
  loid balls: The game is for two people
  one standing on one end of the table,
  the other opposite. The player who first
  delivers the ball is called the server The
  Other the striker out. i The service is
  strictly underhand and is delivered from
  beyond the end of the table.
  The: ball served must drop on the table
  beyond the net and is then in piav. if
  it dops into the net or off the table it
  counts to the striker out
  The server wins a stroke if the striker
  out fails to return the service or ball in
  play of the table.
  The striker out wins a stroke If the
  server fails to return the ball in play or
  makes a foul in service.
  On either player winning his first stroke
  the score la 15. The second stroke brings
  the score to 30; the third stroke is called
  •40 and the fourth stroke wins a game
  The player who wins the first six games
  -wins a set.-
  This is all there really is to the game
  of ping-pong. Certainly it Is a skill de
  manding and skill acquiring game. It
  lias simplicity and cheapness to recom
  mend it. It is far better from a hygenie
  standpoint than a majority of parlor
  prames and is an extremely socialble and
  interesting pastime. It is. for these rea
  sons and its similarity to tennis, a game
  calculated to prove attractive to the"
  younger members of both sexes.
  But why It has set the people of two
  countries almost crazy: why old as well
  as young-have taken up ping-pong when
  they would not as much as look at an
  other form of sport; why the game
acquired such a vogue on the other side
that one serious British magazine writer
has accused; English society of being
more interested in the records of ping- j
pong champion than in the fortune of
the British troops in South Africa and
has prophetically croaked of Nero fid
dling, while Rome is burning— are
phenomena that: it would puzzle the
average human being to account for; and
the answer is certainly not forthcoming
from the devotees of the game.
9 -—Bertram Lebhar.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-06-01/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=PING-PONG&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.096,0.478,0.828,0.866,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>ECHOES FROM PING -PONG
  IT was a glorious meet."
  "How much did you lose?"
  "It is to be hoped that King Ed-
  ward will patronize the game ex-
  warn -wm c*
  tensively."
  "It was so thoughtful In the" genial
  hostess to pass around chewing gum and
  chicken salad."
  "Mr Leon Lilac opened a costly snuff-
  ln the shape of a racque, and Mr.
  Harry Heart wore a pair of ping-pong
  trousers."
  "It is much to be commended that,
  thoueh there were numerous bad plays,
  all strenuous language was eliminated,
  The strongest expression was 'Oh,
  fudge!' by Mr. Charley Callow, after
  he had driven the ball through a thin
  mirror."
  "It is not known as yet. if the different
  *y.a Hoiie-h'tful
  churches will sanction the dengntiui
  game. Many of the fellows hope not.
  There is always so much spice in any-
  thing a little wicked." j
  "Ping-Pong has eclipsed bridge whist
  for parlor gambling Severa^
  young ladies present -lost their matinee
  allowances for a year. It is also whis-
  pered that certain mesfiames will not be
  able to contribute toward charity func-
  tions for some time."
  "Of course, the inevitable wit waa
  present. Mr. Freddy Wages remarked
  that while table tenn.s was a quiet pame,
  it could not be played without a racquet,
  For this outburst of brilliancy he was
  rewarded with loud and continuous ap-
  DJ ause
  ..The' re has been much discussion as
  t0 wnether a physical culture course is
  essential to those intending to take the
  game up. We think it is. Mr. Harold
  m&amp; limlted hlmself t0 ten clgar.
  eUeg per day and only chewed g.um after
  meals. He also says that he takes vig
  orous exercise by dressing himself, in
  stead of allowing his valet to do so, as
  previously.There can be no doubt," said an ex
  pert the other day, "that the constant
  watching- of the ball which is required in
  the game tends to aggravate a^eakneaw
  of the eyes. The moving of the muscUf
  which control the eye3 wearies them after
  an ordinary game. The control of. the
  eyes is really the most essential part, for
  the game calis into requisition compara
  tively few muscles.
  "I have heard much of the ping-pong
  ankle, but as the ankle is used compara
  tively little in playing I do not think that
  the maiaUy is one.v/hich the player need
  count. Some players find that the dorsal
  muscles arc easily tired, and the man
  who stoops a great deal in his effort to
  find the balls which have been knocked to
  the carpet is lijtcly to suffer from sore
  ness and inflammation of the muscles
  alrout the pftins. There is in my opinion
  j. ping-pong eye, although I deny that
  there is si ping-pong face.
  "It has been said that the muscles of
  the legs and arms are often wearied By
  the game. This .is true in a. sense, but I
  think that the eye and the brain -will be
  exhausted :n ping-pong long before the
  muscles used in sending and returning
  balls can be affected to any appreciable
  extent."
  ISEASES with strange names have
  Dloliowtd in the wake of ping-pong,
  J.ut the real pang is not a fanciful
  une. for the watching of the cellu
  loid* sphere really strains the eyes.
  Let London surgeons talk as they will
  about tei.dosyr.ovitis "and p^ig-ponS an
  kles: all these are as nothing compared
  to tho'strair.ed muscles of the eye of the
  Ail ping-pong devotees, even experts,
  suffer from the ping-pong eye more or
  Jess. Other muscles employed to playing
  th* game are ""speedily co-ordinated. To
  develop a proper technique is^ing-pong
  is no easy matter, and in the endeavor
  the eye suffers the most.
  There is a ping-pong wrist, of course,
  and a ping-pong back, but the player who
  can return a ball a hundred times or so
  suffers comparatively little from these.
  The tyro who bends often to pick up the
  balls -which bound upon the carpet is the
  one who is most likely to complain of
  In time he learns, however, to make the
  optical nerves save the exertions of the
  muscles. Then he requires a ping-pony
  i ji^jlimii
  Not much strength is required in tho
  game. A little more vigorous than bil
  liards and not quite bo arduous as tennis.
  of which it is a cousin german, pins-
  THE S U^J)AY CALL.
  pcng appeals to those who have the quick
  eye.
  The skillful player can keep his body
  almost rigid, and standing In front of the
  table send the ball backward and forward
  with scarcely a movement of a muscle
  except those of the wrists. Many or the
  players are able- to sit In one of the
  chairs such as are used by spectators in
  billiard games, and still keep the ball go
  ing rapidly.
  Physicians say that many ping-pong
  players suffer from an inflammation of
  the eye. and champion players add their
  Testimony. The constant watching of the
  ball is liable to cause heaoaclies, or, 'in
  other words, to cause irritation to spread
  from the overworked optical mu.-des.
  The pir.g-ro"g eye is often bloodshot.
  The only way to cure it is to stop play
  ing and to give the overworked eye a
  chance to rest. Th!s the ping-pong devo
  te*- objects to doing. When ho becomes
  absorbed in the game he persists in play
  ing it in season and out of season.
  There are many ping-pong table's which
  served originally in dining-rooms. The
  man who plays upon them is prone fo
  contract the ping-pong eye. The ideal
  table should be dark green^This color is
  easy on the eye. A retired billiard or
  poo! table is well adapted to the game,
  as far*"as the effect upon the eye is con
  cerned. The ball is dazzling white. It
  THE PING PONG
  STRAIN ON THE EYE
  MUSCLES</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-09-21/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=ping-pong&amp;r=-0.92,-0.035,2.841,1.485,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-12-23/ed-1/?sp=29&amp;q=TABLE+TENNIS</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>TABLE TENNIS.
HI'LKS OF TLAY FOR THE NKW INIM&gt;OR
GAME. AI^SO CALLED POMPOM."
Table tennis is the name of a new game which
was introduced in England a short time ago.
and has already become one of the most popu
lar of indoor amusements. It is the came
of lawn tennis in miniature, played on an or
dinary dining table. The net is a tiny one, made
of gauxe stretched between two uprights, which
rest on a bar laid across the table. The balls
are made of the thinnest kind of pyroxyline ma
terial, and are consequently very light. The
racquet has a slender handle and a blade with
a frame about one-half inch thick, which Is cov
ered on both sides with thin drumhead Material.
The play and counting are practically the satnas in lawn tennis, but, according to the rules,
'•the player serving must not put his racquet
over the table nor have it above his wrist." That
is, he must serve underhand and never over
hand, but after service he may hit the ball as he
likes, but he most not volley.
The contact of the light ball with the drum
head racquet produces a pleasant sound, and
because of this sound th(» game received the
name "pompom."
Among the rules for playing the game are the
following:
No faults are allowed: if a fault is served.
that is, the ball does not go over the net or goes
off the table without touching the opposite side
to the server, a |M&gt;int is counted to the non
server.
If the net is touched by the l»all. and the ball
goes over, and otherwise the service is correct,
it is a let. and counU nothing to either side.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1902-01-05/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=PING-PONG</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>AN ABSORBING HEW INDOOR GAITS
WHICH HAS ATTAINED GREAT
POPULARITY IN LONDON;
The three men who occupied the studio flat
were having their quiet end-afternoon srnoks
together. There was the artist, w hose hair haj
turned gray after long years of painting an*
black and white doings; the youth who, fcesi
from art school, was just making a start, and
the man of business, who was the saving clause
of the combination. He put up the money wh»3
black and whites would not sell and the youths
checks from home were delayed In the mails.
"I wish people would find something new wia
which to entertain us, said the man of buij.
ness, in a bored tone.
"New Year is coming," chirped the youth, aa
obvious statement, setir.g that Christmas «xj
just one day past. "Perhaps Santa Claus tLpgti
off' the dear girls to a new game."
There*! nothing new under the sun. Billy*
said the •Id artist. "If taert was I'd draw it jj
hurry."
Then there came a knock on the door, and a
messenger appeared with a dainty note. Billy
grasped it hastily. Billy was in love.
"It's addressed to all of us," he said, with di*.
appointment.
"All the more reason you should hurry up aaj
lead it,"' commanded the man of business.
"It's from Harriet," he murmured, as he read
it to himself.
"Head out loud, uli&gt;.t"" commanded one of the
older men.
"Won't you ccme up to-morrow night and
play ping-pong." read Billy. "Now, what is
ping-pong?"
"Search me?" remarked the one who was nut
artistic, except when it came to making money.
"Sounds Chinese," said the artist.
"I've heard of 'pom-pom,' remarked BiUy.
"That's a sort of big gun which makes a funny
noise." Billy had ence had the idea of beeoininj
a military man. "But ping-pon^r— that's a new
one on me."
"Some new style of bridge. I suppose." mut
tered the artist. "It's not for me. I've sacri
ficed enough on that altar."
"Well. I'm going up to play ping-pong," an
nounced the youth. "I don't care what it is, tit
name's new. Better come along. Jack. You
were growling a minute ago about there being
nothing new, and here you are."
Dilly went to Harriet's and played ping-pong,
and when he had not retumeO by midnight th«
other fellows knew that he was enjoying it. H«
would not tell them what the new game was
when he finally put in an appearance, but ad
vised them to find out for themselves.
An indoor edition of tennis is ping-pong, til*
name coming from the curious sound which tie
parchment rackets give forth when they striis
the little balls. It is played on the dining room
taMe, across the centre of which a low net is
stretched. Th&gt; rules are almost the same as
in tennis, and the points are counted tennis
fashion. There is even mure chance for skilful
handling of the ball than In outduor game*
and there are tricks innumerable which add
interest and variety. Skilful players can ii??
up the volleying process until interest reaches
fever pitch. It is almost as exciting for tie
spectators as for the players, which U core
than can be said of tennis.
It is an absorbing game, as the EngHsh S«l
tell you. It his been played i:i London ilisisj
romis for the last two or three years; but ha
never been strictly in vogue until this winter
The ollieers of the British army carried pir.g
peng sets to South Africa with t'.u-m. and have
set up their tab) on tho wldt when the Ecea
let them remain Ln camp long enough.
Why the game has not taken hold in tiia
country is something which Americans who live
In London cannot understand. They have writ
ten home about the beauties and delisht3 o! v
ping-pong. They laud it to the skies for tie
exercise it affords to busy c.tn who have o
work in offices all day. and to women who
occupied with a round of teas a^d recepucsi
PING-PONG.
Continued on Seventh I'agc*</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071197/1902-03-02/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=fad+table+tennis</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>w
HE ALL ABSORBING FAD
fg very body as Is Anybody Plays Ping
Pong Directions for Playing
Jlf you would be the proper thing
With progress keep along
Do you ping pong
Shakespeare
4amtnai G4 S
b then I rede ye learn to pips
And also learn to poug
VVell well well go and pine pongl
Xhe only reason that ping pong Is not
ntentloned In Shakespeare Is probably
wjug to tho fact that the game was jot
Invented In Shakiispeares time Toor
lng pong li lawn tenuis little brother
f
Bi Is the latest little International baby
Sthjt has found Its way Into the lap of so
fclety If you belonged to the hoi pollol
faiijl wero quartered n Londons White
Sfchjpel or New Yorks tendetloln and
fnappeiicd to be a champon ping pouger
utho doors of tho most eNCluslve society of
Jboth cities would swing open to aduit yon
Fqr ping pong Is strictly the thing and
Jytha Hkllleil player U at present It
Being little It Is played Indoors and
ujbecausjc of the moving about which It
Permits It Is rapidly superseding euchro
hlgh Uvb and bridge whist as a means of
jrepreatlon and entcitalnmcnt In the games
rjut mentioned one must sit In one position
throughout the tedious cveuing llng pong
isKillfferent In ping pong one must t tlr
constantly
tiding pong Is usually played on a dining
jtable with a specially piepured celluloid
ball Instead of the India rubber one iw
Jnglawn teunls It requires some little
praetIco before the proper strength Is at
jitalped with which to strike tho ball but
tea minutes or so Is suflielont as a rule
rtoinabIc the plajcrs to keep the ball within
fch space of the table top The ping pong
foil does not fly easllv
mA dining tablo about seven feet to nine
feet long by half the width without a
idoth is thp best place to play the giie
toj and when the room Is lighted from
febtvo tho table by a chandelier tho tnbf
M uld be moved a little to the sldo of tha
lrm
PWThe height of the net can be varied from
Jcp inches to Ave Inches the lower It Is
stftpa more difficult the strokes can be made
ito return
iKThe racquets are Tellum covered bats of
I
Thc Home of the Patrician
Patrician
Shoes for Women
350
kn Eloquent Tribute
Is on the lips of every woman yho
has worn the Patrician They
are a 20thcentury product in every
particular of style workmanship
and service and their fitting quali
ties are little short of marvelous
atrician
SHOES
re made from the choicest and
nost fashionable Icatiers hey aie
modeled by artists and aie put to
feci her by expert craftsmen Ex
cept onal facilities and an imme se
Jotiput enable us to sell the
Patrician at
ISole Acency
the kind that used to be known as battle
dores
Warming tho battledores slightly before
tho tiro will lmptovo their elasticity but
caic must be taken not to overheat them
When wlogs are used wlb the net these
should bo died up on the posts so that
they project out beyond the edge Of the
table aaid thus prevent n ball being re
turned tound the sides of the posts Instead
of over the net
1 The game Is for two players They
shall stand one at each end of the tabic
The plajer who lirst delivers tho ball shal
i e called tho server and the other the
sttikorout
2 At the end of tie first game tho
strlkorout shall become tho server and the
sirvei shall become the strikerout una
so on alternately
a The service shall bo strictly under
hand und delivered from beyond tha end
of the table
4 The ball served must drop anywhere
ou the table top beyond the net and Is then
In play If It drops Into the net or off the
tabie It counts to the striker out There is
no second son lie as In lawn tennis
0 In fretting It Is a let If the ball touch
the net lu parsing over
0 If the ball in play htrllscg any obiect
above or around the table beloro it bounces
on tho table top Itself net or post except
ed It counts against the player
7 The berver wins a stioku If the strlker
out fulls to return the service or return
the service or ball In play off the table
b The strikerout wins n stroke If the
server bcrve a fault or falls to return the
ball In play or return the ball In play so
that It falls off the table
0 No volleyllng Is allowed hut as long
as the ball touches the table top It Is In
play aud can be taken at half volley
10 On either player winning his rtrst
stroke the score is called 15 for that
plajer on either player winning his sec
ond stroke the score Is called SO for that
player on either plajer winning his third
stroke the score is called 40 for that play
er and tha toiuth stroke won by either
player Is scoied game for that player ex
es pt as below
11 If both players have w n three
stiokes 40 all the score Is called deuce
snd the next stroke won by either player is
scored advantage to thit player If tho
same player wl the nest stroke he win
the game If hi loses the next stroke the
store is again called deuce and so on
until either player wins the two strokes lm
mediately following the score of deuce
when the game is scored for that player
12 The player who flist wins six games
wins a set
13 The game may nlso be scored by
points twentytwo up The players lu this
cn e change the service aucr every tive
points scoied like overs at cricket
The apparatus of the game costs about
260 i
A pingpong dance In which the women
wear pingpong patches and powdeted hair
Is the latest development of the present
mania Tho women carrying white balls
with a red number on each and each gen
tleman a scarlet ball with a corresponding
fluro in white walk down the ball room
and meet at a silken net Batting begins
Af soon as each dancer secures the ball the
numbers are called out pairing oft begins
and the couples glide down the room hand
in hand in minuet style The latest rival
of pingpong bv the wnv Is table bowls
which has Just been exhibited at the Alex
andra palace</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-04-06/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=ping-pong+table+tennis</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>From present indications society will
no longer be divided upon the lines of
birth, l)i ceding or wealth, but the quail-
Jiciition for membership in the innermost
circle will )m- ability to play "ping pong,"
that fascinating parlor game that has
recently come over the seas to us from
aristocratic London.
Age. sex. color or previous condition
inaki no difference with the devotees of
the game and in England duchesses have
been known to struggle for the honor of
having a champion ping pong player from
some suburb at their receptions. Success
ful authors, artists and actors are no
longer being: lionized and made to roar
for the benefit of society. Their place ,s
but secondary now to the man who can
make the highest score with the bellum
covered racquet* and the celluloid balls.
The craze has but just struck the West,
although in New York, and. in fact, in
all of the Eastern cities, it is raging al
most as widely as it does in England.
The dealers say they are unable to keep
up with the demand for the game and
that thousands of sets have been sold,
v.ith the demand still increasing. "Pins
pong" parties are taking the place of
bridge whist and cinch contests and even
of bowline tournaments. No longer does
the Western swain sit contentedly in the
parlor with the girl of his heart, discuss
ing the weather undisturbed by the other
members of the family. Now the parlor
is in use. Father and mother and the
neighbors are "serving" and "returning"'
and calling love 15, love 30, deuce ad
vantage, etc.
i'iiiK pong is Bimply modified tennis
played upon a ta-ble in the houft« instead
of a court in the open air and is, in fact,
table tennis. Bui when the little celluloid
ball strikes the hard surface of a table
the contact prodapes a sound best
d&lt; scribed by the word "ping" and as it
bounds against the viium racquet the
Bound "pong," a full note lower, issues.
Some person with a quick ear and a
quicker imagination translated these
sounds and the gamfe was christened with
the catchy name "ping pong," a name
tnat has helped to call attention to it.
The balls are very light, much like blown
birds' iggs to the touch, and there is no
possibility of their breaking or of injur
ing anything they may strike except, of i
course, fragile bric-a-brac. The racquets
are light rattan affairs, covered with
vellum. In this respect they differ from j
those used in ordinary tennis, although
ih>- dealers are showing some specially
constructed ones strung with catgut, as j
are tennis racquets. They were ordered
by ]&gt;ing pong players' who are also tenn:s
experts and who believe they can play
In tter with the strung racquets than with
the vellunf-covered ones. Any table
about the height of a billiard table and
jn the neighborhood o. nine feet long by
five feet wide will do for the game. Many
use dining tables. To be correct one
should have a table, the surface of which
has been painted dark green, or covered
With biliard cloth, it makes no difference
in the game whether it is played with or
Without a cloth upon the table. Without
a cloth the balls will, of course, bounce
higher. The game is played by two or
Jour persons, usually by two. For the
at in which thfe are two players,
and this is the game in high favor, each
player stands art one end of th&lt;- table.
The one first delivering the ball is called
the "serve;;" t):.- other person is th-e
".■strikeout." At the end of the iirst game
the "strikeout"-becomes the "server' and'
00 on alternately to the end of the sets.
As soon as theball is served and drops
nnywlK re on the table top beyond the t.et
it is 'play." if it drops Into the net-or
off the table it counts to the "strike out."
I i&lt; re is no second service as in lawn ten
jus. On either player winning the first
strike, the score is called fifteen for that
fourth stroke won by either player is sac
ond "game," unless both players have
yon three strikes, "forty all," whsn the
scon- is called deuce, and the next stroke
v.on by either player is scored "advan
tage" to that player.
[f the same player wins the next stroke
the game Is his: If he loses the next
eiroke the score is again deuce, and so i
on until either player wins the two
Strokes imediately following the score
player; on either player winning his or
her second stroke, the score for that play
er is thiity. On either player winning- the
third stroke, the score is forty, and the
of deuce, and the "game" is scored for
that player. The player who lirst wins
six games wins the set. In tourna
ments usually three sets are played by
each &lt;.im;)etitor against each other one.
The rules for playing are similar to
those in lawn teunis, except that no over
hnnd service is allowed. There are no
urts marked as in lawn tennis, the
~"\i of the table forming the court, so
that the ball striking any part of the ta
ble is in play. The strokes, apart from
the service, are divided into two main
lasses—the half volley and all other
Etrokee. The half volley is when the bull
,i.v.T.T..ViV.riT.*»i"iT.r.r. .-■"..-,—.:.v....
Rheumatic
1
Sciatic. Sharp and Shooting Pains. 3!
Strains, Weaknessand ail bodily aches it&gt;
and pains relieved almost instantly. Ql
Backache.- Headache. FaceaChe. 3&gt;
Chest Pains, and all Nervous Pains 91
and Muscular Weakness cured by
St Jacobs Oil f

After all other rerr.edics fail.
i -.-Acts like magic 1 .jjr
Conquers Pain I
I
Price, 25c and 50c.
?f
SOLD D-AALL DEALERS IS MEDICINE.
is taken' immediately after striking the
table. The player hits where he thinks
the ball will be, not at the ball itself,
and it is, therefore, almost impossible
to actually hit is half voiieyin^. Ji is the
ball which hits the racket, and not the
racket that hits the ball. This ia en
tirely defensive play. To attack, the
ball must be struck after it has reached
the top of the bound, or even later, for on
ly then has the player complete control of
the ball. When the ball bounds high it
may be smashed straight on the table,
but if your opponent gets back so as to
make the return, twist your wrist BO that
the ball is hit at right angles to the
flight or even somewhat underneath; it
will drop close to the net and come
straight up or even bounce back over the
net. An effective stroke in reply to a
hard (irive is that called the "crouch
smash." As the ball cornea toward you,
crouch down and hit It at the edge of the
table. This is a good return for a hard
service, but it is most difficult to ac
complish. All these strokes can be done
■backhanded— -in fact, some are such
easier, as, owing to the wrist having
more play in the proper direction, a (,-rtat
er twist can be imparted to the ball.
In addition a ball falling on the right
hand side»f the table can be driven with
the back of the hand in any d-esircu di
rection. This stroke should only Le used
when pressed by a hird ball.
It will be gathered from th&lt;^ strokes
described that play can be made both
back and forehand. This gives many
more opportunities for deceiving an op
ponent. Variety is the secret of success.
Nev&lt; r let your opponent anticipate your
intention. When driven to swing, after
hitting the ball, do not stop and turn
back, but continue the swing the same
way, bo as to make a complete circle.
The player i an get square with the table
much quicker by doing this. Ping pong
sets may be had to suit any fancy or any
THE HEAVENS
IN APRIL
April, the fourth month in the year.
presents many attractions for those who
follow with unwavering interest the ever
changing movements of the heavenly
bodies. The scene of beauty has, how
ever, shifted to the early morning hours,
if one would see the planets in their glory.
So that it takes an early riser to glean
from the heavens the really choice bits,
unless a telescope is at hand. The stars
are, however, always to be relied upon,
and just now in the northern section of
the heavens we see the Little Bear pass
ing above the horizontal position which he
had not quite reached last month, while
the Great Bear is overhead and inverted.
King Cepheus is now immediately below
the pole, and, like some earthly monarchs,
is standing on his head in a most un
kingly attitude. Cassiopeia is where it
always can be found, on the opposite side
of the pole from that occupied by the
Great Bear, so that the Lady in the
I'hair need never fear being hugge.i by
this fierce dcniz&lt; n of the Arctic regions.
In the southern sky the great sea serpent,
Hydra, occupies the leading position, ihis
is the longest and nearly the largest of
the constellations. The ruling elliptic
constellation for the month is the Lion,
easily distinguished by the Sickle, in the
handle of which is the bright star R» gu
lus. In the cast there is Bootes, Under
neath which are the stars of the Serpent,
but the fangs of the latter are innocuous,
for presumably they cannot pierce the
boots of the former, who tramples fear
lessly upon him. In the west Taurus is
passing from fcight. The Twins, followed
by Procyon, the Lesser Dog, are ap
proaching the mid-west, or prime ver
tical, and hanjj like glorious crowns over
Orion, as he pas-:cs to his setting place,
says the New York Sun.
While contemplating these worlds, shin
ing so brightly in the morning and in the
evening, we may. without too great an
effort of the imagination, think that iTley
contain beings moving with all the activ
ity of life; nations, civilizations, cities
like Babylon, Thebes. o r even something
approaching our own cosmopolitan Gotfi
am—human beings, in a word, who are
everything that we are, under different
physical forms, but no doubt reasoning
by the aid of the same principles of logic
which govern our thought, though their
manner of perception may be totally dif
lt rent from our own. Perhaps they have
escaped more quickly from the limbo of
barbarism and form intelligent, enlight
ened, pacific and fraternal societies, wor
shipping the beautiful, the true, and the
good.
The month opens with the sun 4 de
grees north of the equator, and the days
twelve hoLrs forty-one minutes in length.
The declination increases more than 10
degrees to the northward, with the addi
tion of one hour and nineteen minutes to
the day"s length. This should cause all
nature to bloom and p:jt on its lovely
spring coloring. On the Sth there is a par
tial eclfpsa of the sun, one of three allot
td to this year. We are not among the
favored this time, however, as the vari
ous phenomena attending the en
trance into the shadow and the depart
ure therefrom are not visible in our lati
tude.
The moon Is quite generous with us this
month, as it presents five phases, the last
quartering taking place on the first and
last days of the month. thcoming on the Bth, the day of Ihe partial
eclipse of the sun. first quartering coming
on the 15th, and the full moon coming on
the 226. People are wont to judge of trie
chances of there being a dry or we?
month throughout April by the Pos'tion~t>f
the horns of the crescent moon. It is an
excellent illustration of the persistence
with which the belief in lunar influence
upon mankind still lingers, thougCi re
peatedly proved to be false. The early
Chaldeans believed in the influence of the
position of the heavenly bodies upon hu
man life, and their system was later
elaborated by the Greeks. If we once as
sume that there is a relation between the
configuration of stars and planets in the
sky and affairs on the earth, it Is not
difficult to find coincidences which ap
parently prove that relation. It is a curi
ous fact that the Greek astrology ascrib
ed an influence to the appearance of the
moon's horffs. which the later belief in
its effect on rainfall seems to have sup
planted. Saturn is twice in conjunction
with the moon, once on the 2d and again
en the- 29th. On the 18th the planet is in
quadrature, or half-way between conjunc-
THE ST. PAUL, GLOBE, vSUNDAY, APRIL 6, 1902.
pocketbook. Some of the tables are col
lapsible, with folding supports, and may
be stowed in small space. The bats or
racquets are already acquiring as great
variety as golf clubs. There are already
tournament bats, club bats and other
kinds. The best have vellum drums, al
though drums are also made in parch
ment and wood. Good players prefer the
short-handled bats to those of regulation
length. Ping pong- balls are largely im
ported, although American manufactur
ers are experimenting with various mate
rials in hope of improving the celluloid
spheres now in use, giving the regula
tion s|ze and weight. The net is usually
hand-made, of from five to seven inches
In height, linen bound, with a fair de
gree of elasticity. The poles on which it
is stretched are shapely wooden pegs,
with leather bottoms, which protect the
table, to which they are fastened with
clamps. In each outfit there are usually
a half dozen bats or battledores and one
dozen balls. Whether the game Is to
have permanent place among the amuse
ments is a question that i&lt; being discuss
ed by those who have watched and ana.
lyzed the rise and fall of fads in the way
of indoor and outdoor amusements. Its
champions_ contend that it has every pos
sible requisite for the proper exercise of
body and mind that young women who
are noj equal to the roughing and phys
ical strain entailf-d by golf, tennis and
kindred strenuous sports will be heartily
and healthfully benefited by ping pong.
Others contend that the craze now
sweeping over Europe and America Is
but a passing fancy that will be rh&lt;&gt;-te&gt;
lived than the bicycle vogue, and that
the new amusement will die out with the
coming of the outdoor reason, and tb^f
ore another w'nter arrives its hold win
have been broken and the devotees of
other pleasures will return to their old
gods and idols.—Milwaukee Senfinel.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016357/1902-05-03/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=PING-PONG+ping+pong+craze</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>P1NGPONO IS A CRAZE GRAZEHAS CRAZEHAS CRAZEHAS
HAS INVADED ALL SORTS OF PLACES PLACESFROM PLACESI PLACESFROM
FROM CLUBS TO HOTELS HOTELSOne HOTELSOne HOTELSOne
I
One Factory U I Timilnjr TlIrnln Out n Tl TIu Tlrogand TlrogandSets unand unandScti jflnll jflnllSet
Sets Set n l DnyTho Lay nj Tho 1ainlon l 1assinn lon For fie Sport StiortHas SOItIInOrown SportIIas
Has IInOrown Grown Up Siicldtnlj 6llItltenlllo Ilc urcsrj ureerue ureerueLnnJunlo uroalueLanguage ue ueLanguage
Language For Carne Term TermIn TennIn TermsIn
In the past few days persons walk walking walkIng walkIng
ing through the quiet uptown streets streetshave streetshave streetshave
have remarked about the number of ofhouses ofhouses ofhouses
houses through whose open windows windowscame windowscame windowscame
came the staccato pins pln 1 pong pongl ot the thexylonite thexylonlte thexylonlte
xylonlte table tennis ball Accordlug Accord AccordIng According
Ing to the stories which aro told by bydealers bytJealers bydealers
dealers In sporting goods thousandsotsets thousands thousandsof
of otsets sets of this game hare ha e been sold to tofamilies totam tofamilies
families tam Illes in the city and the demand demandappears tJemantJappears demandappears
appears to be increasing One taco factory tacotory fuetory
tory at Ohlcopee Falls alone is turn turnlug turn turning turnIng
ing out 1000 sets dolly and Is far t l be behind bebind behind
hind Its orders Pingpong Ptng poug outfits arc arcgoing arcgoing aregoing
going iu numbers now to suburban suburbangolf sulmrbangolf suburbangolf
golf clubs It shows what a bold the thesport thesport thesport
sport has taken on Its devotees that thateven tlUltoen thateven
even the golfing enthusiast must take takehis takehis takehlsping
his hlsping pingpong pIngp pnng ng to flu iinks links with him himOur hImOur himOur
Our greatest demand for complete completesets completesets completesets
sets including the regulation tables tableshas tableshas tableshas
has of course come from the clubs clubssaid clubssnld clubssaid
said a dealer yesterday But the thewomen thcwomcn thewomen
women women and children hare got the thefever thetever thefever
fever as bad ba as their brothers and andfathers andtathers andfathers
fathers If youre writing about the thepingpong theplngl1011g theping
pingpong ping pong craze you cant make it t too toostrong oo oostrong oostrong
strong So far as I know we havent haventsold haventsold haventsold
sold a set to any old ladles la les home yet yetbut yetbut yetbut
but I dare are say the game will reach reachthem reachthem reachthem
them in time This craze beats any anything anything anything
thing I ever heard of Our belief is isthat Isthat Isthat
that its only beginning Hot weather weathermay weathermay weathermay
may affect our sales somewhat but butwo butwe
wo look for an increased demand next nextfall nextfall nextfall
fall fallOur
Our indoor putting green In the theback theback theback
back of the th store has been occupied by bya bya
a pingpong ping poug table for several weeks weeksLfits weeksL weeksLets
Lets L ts of people who never saw the thegame thegame thegame
game come In here and watch a few fewsets fewsets fewsets
sets get fascinated by the play and nndcud riudend andend
end by buying racquets and balls anda and anda anda
a net to take home and set up on their theirdiningroom theIrdlnlngroom theirdining
diningroom dining room or billiard table Theres Theresa
a game going on here almost every everyhour ceryhOUl everyhour
hour of the day People cant seem to toget toget toget
get enough of IL ILThe It ItTho ItTho
Tho clubs have been and are still stilltlys stillt10 stilltl
tlys t10 tl o stronghold of the craze although althoughthe nlthouhtho althoughthe
the newspapers have had more to say sayabout sayabout sayabout
about the play In brokers ofllces of lces and andon andon andon
on ocean steamers So sudden has been beenthe beenthe beenthe
the passion for the sport and so much muchroom muchroom muchrOonl
room does a regulation table take up upthat upthat upthat
that most of the clubs have had to togive togive togive
give up some other sport in whole or orIn 01In orin
In part for a time or else sacrifice sacrificepart sacrltleepart sacrificepart
part of their diningroom space No Nobody Nobody Nobody
body seems to object however Even Eventho Erentho Eventhe
tho most sedate of club loungers al although nltbough although
though he may begin by scoffing at atthe atthe atthe
the childs play ends in becoming becomingcither becomIngeither becomingeither
either an enthusiast entllUslastor or a disappointed disappointedbut lsappolnledbut
but persistent duffer dufferCollege dufferCollega dufferCollege
College clubs or other clubs fre frequented tree treequented frequented
quented by younger men are the worst worstsufferers worstsufferers worstsufferers
sufferers from the pingpong ping pong malady maladyTho maladylo maladyI1he
I1he Tho lo Harvard 1 alvald Club early In Inthcwlutol Inthcwlutolput the winter winterput winterput
put up the little nets on its billiard billiardtables bllliardtables billiardtables
tables and billiards have scarcely
been played there since Members Memberspay Memberspay Iemberlpay
pay the same amount per hour for forplaying forplayIng forplaying
playing pingpong ping pong that they formerly formerlywere 1ormerl 1ormerlwero formerlywere
were cbnrgdtl for fortbe the use of the bit billiard bllliard bitHard
liard tables The club has since set up upIn upIn upin
In addition a veal ping pingpong pong board boardThe boardThe boardThe
The Yale Club has four tables in one oneof oneot oneof
of the class diningrooms on the ninth ninthfloor ninthfioor ninthfloor
floor The Cornell University Club Clubgives Clubgives Clubgives
gives up half Its diningroom to the thopastime thepastime thepastime
pastime and the House UouseOommlttee UouseOommltteenow Committee Committeenow Committeenow
now talks of letting the whole apart apartment apattment apartment
ment bo used for It so many of the themembers themembers themembers
members want to play and pingpong pingpongtables plngpongtables ping pong pongtables
tables can be used ns dining lnlnl tables if ifit ItIt ifit
it takes too long to make the change changeIn changeIn changeIn
In n Brooklyn Droold n athletic club the ping plugpongcrs pingpongers pingpongers
pongers have Invaded the the handball handballcourt handballcourt handballcourt
court Most of these resorts Ies rts have had hador hador hador
or are having pingpong ping pong tdurnamentsand tdurnaments tournamentsnnd
nnd clever players bare Jave been dowel developed deeloped doweloped
oped in the course of a few weeks weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses
Boardinghouses In all parts of town townhave townhave townhave
have been hard hit by the craze The Thelong ihelong Thelong
long table ta ble in the back parlor l llor makes a agood agood agood
good pingpong pl ping gllong pong board and a till the young youngman youngman youngman
man In the hall bedroom two flights flightsup filghtsup flightsup
up takes delight In making the star starboarder starboatder starboarder
boarder look like thirty cents The Thelandladies Thelandladies rholandladIes
landladies are arc rc not enthusiastic overthe over overthe 001the
the game because when played In the theevening theevening theevening
evening it has a n tendency to develop developa developrobust
a robust appetite for late suppersThe suppers suppersThe suppersThe
The vernacular of tbo sport has not notyet notyet notyet
yet reached a l high degree of development develop development oelop11ent
ment For the present as Is the case casewith casewltbany casewith
wltbany with any new game players make free freewith treewltb freewith
with words nnd phrases plll ses proper to toother toother toother
other branches of sport Expressions Expressionslike Expressionslike
like You dealt cm the last time timeThis timeThis timeThis
This cue Is rotten Off side are areheard areIleard areheard
heard around the board Picturesque Picturesquelanguage Plctulesquelanguage Picturesquelanguage
language of n different character is isalso Isnlso isalso
also common The elusive celluloid celluloidsphere celluloidsphere celluloidsphere
sphere is as conducive to profanity as nsthe asthe asthe
the guttn guttnpercha percha A well known lawn lawntennis lawntennis lawntennis
tennis player has n novelty in the way wayof wayof wayof
of pingpong ping pong profanity When he hemakes hemakes hemakes
makes a fault he shouts Fudge I or orGoodness 01Goollness oreGoodness
Goodness gracious He explains that thatho thatbo thatlie
ho learned the game by playing with wltl1his withbis withhis
his sisters and it Isnt worth cussln cusslnabout cusslnabout cussinabout
about anyway anywaNew New York SunSmall Sun</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1902-07-12/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=ping+pong&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.386,0.457,0.553,0.579,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>PING-PONG IN PORT.
  (Continued from Page 1
  few minutes now and tden In mutinl
  reminiscence, si)s that he himself has
  dabbled n little In the game He baa
  not ct advanced far enough to tell a
  ping from a pong houewi but Is will
  ing to learn, If onlv from 1I.4 phig
  pongy conversation of others
  A half dozen oases of ping-pong sets
  arrived from Sin Francisco In the
  American batk. Knlulani )esterd.i)
  morning The rfame is evltlentl) gain
  ing In favor In Honolulu when tho
  paraphernalia begins to come Into the
  Paradise ofths Pacific in such bulk
  Knthuslasti slorj In the fact that
  Hawaii Is ar. American tcnltui), 11
  for no other reason than that they
  would be compellel to pj) tint) oil Me
  tools of ping-pong If the count!) stood
  to Ameilia Ir tre relation of n foieign
  land
  Numbers of tl.r members of the cus
  tom house foi i- have Invested In ping
  pong outfits and off hours at home aie
  imbued very pleasantl) except when It
  tomes to g'ovelllng on the floor and
  under furniture for the balls. It Is even
  hinted tint a fondness for the game
  has devolujied in quatteta hlghei than
  the foiee of Inspectors In the custom
  house. ThU rumor, howevci. has not
  )ct been verified
  The new Sprei kels boats are up to
  date ns far as ping-pong Is contented
  The Sierra, Sonoma ami Ventuti 111 e
  all mined with plug-pong outfits and
  when the Sonouu and Ventuia weie in
  port a few dajs ago many people fiom
  nshoro noticed the tables and othei gear
  rigged out on the piomenade decks of
  these elegant steamets
  It Is said that uffle-boaid aboaul tho
  boats of the 'jtiJiIlun-Austrullan lino
  will soon give phce to ping-pong la
  fact tho game ha.i ahead) been inlro
  ducetl aboard one of the boats, tin Mo
  ana,
  Sailing vessels Ibeused to cam pas
  sengers, sin h as the Kalulanl and th
  Coronatlo, will not maintain their
  popularity unless the) Invest In ping
  pong outfits
  There is tome talk of Inttocliiclng
  ping-pong aboard the Kinnii Admiral
  Jleckley Is heaitll) In favoi of tho
  scheme. It Is suggested however, that
  n rule should be made that the captain
  refrain from playlngthe game, as It nas
  n faculty of so absorbing tho attention
  that other Ideas aie llkel) to suffer In
  consequence
  What If It should tome to the pass
  when two pln?s of the bell meant
  "go ahead" to tie ei.g.neer, while a
  "pong" signified stophei'" There la
  a possibility that the lolling of the
  Klnau would Interfere with the gamo
  aboaid that vessel in this ease many
  balls would decorate the walo of tlm
  speedy craft all the wa) from Hono
  lulu to Hllti
  Puibei Slmeison of the steamer Man
  lia Loa belli ves In ping-pong, nccoid
  lug to his fi lends, and Inasmuch as his
  fatbei Is master of that splendid
  paektt bo might he nble to Induct) his
  parent to entourage the game an ong
  the passengem aboard the steamer-
  In the event o- the game continuing
  In Its populnilty on the wateifiont tho
  tiny Is likely to soou come when tho
  WANTS
  For Want Column See Page Six
  FOR SALE.
  RESTAURANT FOR SALE Com
  pletely equipped; best location In
  Honolulu: for sale at a Largaln. Hn
  qulru at once at California Lunch
  Room, cor. Hotel and Union Sts.
  219C-1W
  sailors will make a demand for ping
  pong outfits In the forecastle. All kinds
  of possibilities loom up on the horl
  zon of the now almost universal game.
  It would be a dreadful thing If a vessel
  should arrive here from Newcastle, for
  example', and tne crew snoulil lodge a
  complaint with the Federal authorities
  to the effect that the master of that
  vessel had cut down the sailors' sup-
  pi) of ping pong balls during the voy
  ugo.
  Frank J. Turk, tho handsomo nnd
  popular sailor shipping agent of Queen
  street, when caked as to his views on
  ping pong, said that he was too busy to
  pluy tho game, besides Oscar Lewis,
  his former partner. Is now In business
  on the Coast, nnd lfu Is about tho only
  man who would have an) chance in
  the game with Turk
  Severn! old captains who havo not
  pln)ed a game of nny kind sinco they
  sported with whales In tho Arctic
  have tnken up plug pong with their
  grandchildren and no longer complain
  of rheumatism, gout, lame backs, or
  that tired feeling
  Ping pong has the waterfront In Its
  grip. How long will It last?</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2023271006/1941-03-28/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=ping+pong&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.424,0.805,0.489,0.511,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>PING PONG EXHIBITION
  Mr. Sernai and Mr. Lippman, Northwest
  Doubles Ping Pong champions, displayed
  their artistry in exhibition gomes at tho
  Post Servic Club Wednesday night. It is
  reported that many of the soldier specta
  tors are suffering from stiff necks after
  following the play of the champions.
  A community sing was hold after the
  Ping Pong exhibition.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1919-03-01/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=ball+sports&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.287,-0.079,1.574,1.574,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016353/1902-05-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=table+tennis&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.043,0.096,1.1,1.15,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>i t r Making a PingJong PingJongget On g nay t tI
    I get et at HOllie HOllieOt Ho HoOf a e
    1 1Of
    Of all the Indoor games that the wrl wrlr wrlcr wrier
    cr r bas tried trIedand and bo has tackled about aboutill aboutn aboutill
    ill n of them themnont none has proved such Jolly follyIQod Jollyood jollyfCod
    fCod ood fun as table tennis or as the Engish Eng EngIsh
    Ish call It pingpong pingpongA plngpongfirstclass ping pong pongA
    I A firstclass pingpong plug pong outfit with wilhtwo withtwo withtwo
    two rackets racl ets that are perfect little ten tenits ten11s tenis
    its is rackets on a small scale will cost costibout costbout costibout
    ibout 4 1 at the shop When it comes comeso corpes
    o a n very cheap set you can probably probablypake probablypate probablypnke
    pate at home just as good an outfit outfitFirst outfitIDd outfittntl
    IDd tntl maybe btlter btlterF1rst bejteri
    F1rst i First irstas as Si to the tb r rackets clictS In England Englandlie England1te
    lie kind most favored have centres of oflarchment ofnrchment oflarchment
    larchment like a drumhead from fromVhlch fromvhlch fromwhich
    Vhlch the ball rebounds with that bum bumfling humnlng humg
    fling pingpong ping pong sound which gives the thefame therame thelame
    fame Its name nameThe nampThe nameThe
    The writer prefers the string racket racketPieces Jacketrleces racket4leeos
    Pieces of rattan soaked sOI1I Ctl a while In Inrteamlng inrteamlng inrteaming
    rteamlng hot water WI1 tar to make them very verytupplo verytupple verytupelo
    tupelo make good racket frames A Arooden Aooden Awoden
    rooden handle hollowed out at the end endvlth endrith endvltb
    vlth grooves for the rattan frame to toIt toIt toIt
    It In Is simply constructed us shown shownn
    n the thedlagram diagram above In stringing the thertrlng thertrlng theitring
    rtrlng used on a banjo would be about about1ght aboutofght aboutfight
    fight Two strings for each racket racketJiould racketJlOuld rackethould
    Jiould b bt enough enoughThese enougllhese enoughThese
    These hese strings should shoul bo thoroughly thoroughlylooked thoroughlyoOaked thoroughlycaked
    looked and then used while still wet wetDo weto
    Do 0 not string too tight for If you do dovhen dorhen dovllen
    vhen the strings dry and shrink they theyvlll theym theyvlll
    vlll m pull the frame all allout out of shape shapeString shflpeHdng shapetring
    String first across and andAlen toen en up and andlown andlawn andtown
    lawn exactly as In a regulfClon regul on racket racketn
    n making n support for your net a aouple aDuple aduple
    Duple of yards of heavy hen telegraph wire wirevlll wirem wirevlll
    vlll m answer Take each length and andlouble alldIiouble andlouble
    louble and bend into shape shown In Inhe Inbe inbe
    be diagram This of Itself may not be belulte beluite beluite
    luite stanch enough to hold the net netaut netlut netnut
    nut but by running a cord from the thex theop theop
    x op p of one wire support down and un unler unler unler
    ler the tab table I to the top of the other otherlupport otherIUpport othersupport
    support you OU should be able to obtain obtainlie obtainhe obtainhe
    he necessary amount of rigidity The Thelet Thelet Thelet
    let itself should be about sis Inches InchesUgh Inches11gh inchessigh
    Ugh from the table and should clear clearhe clealhe clearhe
    he table by enough to allow the ball ballo ballto
    o pass easily asllr under it Any material materialvlll materialIVJIl materialgrill
    vlll do for the net though a gauze or orlotting orlotting ortotting
    lotting of some kind bound at the top topvlth toppith
    pith Ith an Inch or two of white tape isLest Is Isest iscst
    Lest est As to the table Itself It should
    be e simply a smooth and flat surface surfaceibout surfacelbout surfaceibout
    ibout five by ten feet or say four by bysight byIght byIght
    Ight fret fretThe ftetThe feetThe
    The game Is played exactly as tenass ten tensis tenIlls
    sis is played except e cept that there is but butne butme butlne
    me ne court on either efth el side of the net If Ifthe Ifhe Ifthe
    the he ball strikes the very edge e ge of the thetable thel1ble theable
    table and 10 o bounces off at In such suel1l1 a way waythat wayat waythat
    that at a return la Impossoble call it an anedger anedger anedger
    edger and serve over again againThe a Ialn IalnTIle aln alnThe
    The method oC scoring is the same lameHil sameis
    18 in tennis One rule of the old game gamevhlch gamejhlch gamewhich
    which IB barred because of the narrow narrowbounds narrowoundl narrowbounds
    bounds ic volleying A ball can never neverie neerJe neverbe
    ie returned except on the bounce bouncePickups bouncePlckuPI bouncePickups
    Pickups however loWerer are allowable An Another Anther An9ther
    other ther strict ruling of pingpong ping pong is that thatQO thatno
    QO overhand strokes are allowed the thehand thehand theband
    hand must never be raised above the theheight theheIght theheight
    height of th tlll elbow Also the serve servemutt 5118I servemust
    mutt be delivered from a a point beyond beyondthe beyondthe beyondthe
    I the end of the table tableThe tableThe tableThe
    The tennis experts and allround nll ronnd ath athletes dhbave athletes
    letes have devised It new sort of racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
    that makes of tills parlor game nme a rath rathir ratbar rathar
    ar strenuous and exciting affair affairThe affairThe affairThe
    The racket is simply a l wooden pad paddle pRal11e padale
    ale of about the same outside dimen dimensions dim dimenslona en en3lonl
    sions as a the pingpong plag pong strung racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
    that is about six inches In diameter diameterroughly dlameterroughly diameterroughly
    roughly speaking IIpealtingthe the handle being of ofany oflny ofany
    any desired length lengthThe lengUIThe lengthThe
    The paddle part IB not of one piece piecewith piecewith piecewith
    with the handle hl1n le as it would break or orsplit 01split orsplit
    split too easily The handle Is spliced splicedon
    on The paddle padaJeon on one side or both bothaccording botIllccordlng bothaccording
    according to bow you play is covered coveredwith coveredwith coveredwith
    with emery cloth or paper guled on oncarefully oncarefullJ oncarefully
    carefully With this thl rough surface surfaceyou lurfacerou surfaceyou
    you can cut the ball</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1919-10-17/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=ball+sports&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.284,-0.078,1.569,1.569,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
</topics>